[{"question":"...... refers to the structure of a work of art.","options":["form","Plot","Setting","Style",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Conflict in a literary work begins to unfold with","options":["climax","episode","exposition","resolution",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The character assumed by the author in his writing is","options":["protagonist","chorus","persona","pseudonym",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Oral literature is part of","options":["drama","folklore","poetry","music",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Poetry is written in","options":["chapters","paragraphs","scenes","lines",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Poetry is written in","options":["descriptive","dramatic","narrative","poetic",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The ....... produces comic relief in drama","options":["chorus","protagonist","antagonist","clown",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A short play is also called a","options":["farce","novelette","playlet","slapstick",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the stanza and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFor days I wept and felt depressed<br>\r\nThe one and all I loved had left<br>\r\nBut then on me our Bill impressed<br>\r\n'Your love is where she looks bereft'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme is","options":["abab","aaba","abcc","abbc",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the stanza and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFor days I wept and felt depressed<br>\r\nThe one and all I loved had left<br>\r\nBut then on me our Bill impressed<br>\r\n'Your love is where she looks bereft'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe lines are iambic","options":["pentameter","trimeter","tetrameter","hexameter",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the stanza and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFor days I wept and felt depressed<br>\r\nThe one and all I loved had left<br>\r\nBut then on me our Bill impressed<br>\r\n'Your love is where she looks bereft'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe lines constitute","options":["an epic","a quatrain","an ode","a sestet",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"''The sun smiled gently on the scene'' illustrates","options":["paradox","euphemism","hyperbole","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The major part of the Petrarch sonnet is the","options":["quintet","sestet","tercet","octave",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"A Poem that celebrates an object, person or event is","options":["a sonnet","a dirge","an ode","a balled",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"''That it will rain is not unlike'' illustrates the use of","options":["irony","lilotes","metaphor","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An...... is an indirect and usually unfavourable remark","options":["allusion","irony","aside","innuendo",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"'Many hands make light work' illustrates the use of","options":["zeugma","hyperbole","metonymy","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Through ........ the ills of society are criticised with the objective of having them corrected","options":["dramatic irony","comic relief","satire","farce",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the following lines to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe livid waters roared and snarled and flapped <br>\r\nAt the poor battered and weeping yacht.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used in the lines is","options":["simile","alliteration","assonance","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the following lines to answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe livid waters roared and snarled and flapped <br>\r\nAt the poor battered and weeping yacht.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe picture presented is one of","options":["quiet sea","dark sky","stormy weather","calm season",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHe was under the siege of three union executive members.<br>\r\nThere was the Secretary standing over him ; there was the Treasurer puffing away at a cigarette; there was the Organiser lounging near the door, a deadpan look <u>plastered on each of their faces like a death-mask<\/u>.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncredulous, he sat in a pensive mood. How cloud the others do such a thing? His discontent turned to silent anger that simmered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I think it is not right, '' he said, just managing not to explode from his growing anger. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n''You sign that sheet, Mr President,'' ordered the Secretary in a barely audible but stern voice.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Why are you doing this?'' he asked, his voice not giving any hint of the boiling cauldron of <u>screaming anger<\/u> in his chest.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Will you sign, Mr President?''<br>\r\n''All right,'' he said, now seething amiably.<br>\r\nHe took his pen, picked up the sheet of paper and looked over the signatures. Then he proceeded to tear up the paper into shreds.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe attitude of the writer towards the President is one of","options":["contempt","disdain","disinterest","approval",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHe was under the siege of three union executive members.<br>\r\nThere was the Secretary standing over him ; there was the Treasurer puffing away at a cigarette; there was the Organiser lounging near the door, a deadpan look <u>plastered on each of their faces like a death-mask<\/u>.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncredulous, he sat in a pensive mood. How cloud the others do such a thing? His discontent turned to silent anger that simmered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I think it is not right, '' he said, just managing not to explode from his growing anger. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n''You sign that sheet, Mr President,'' ordered the Secretary in a barely audible but stern voice.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Why are you doing this?'' he asked, his voice not giving any hint of the boiling cauldron of <u>screaming anger<\/u> in his chest.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Will you sign, Mr President?''<br>\r\n''All right,'' he said, now seething amiably.<br>\r\nHe took his pen, picked up the sheet of paper and looked over the signatures. Then he proceeded to tear up the paper into shreds.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe prevailing atmosphere is","options":["tense","sad","cordial","warm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHe was under the siege of three union executive members.<br>\r\nThere was the Secretary standing over him ; there was the Treasurer puffing away at a cigarette; there was the Organiser lounging near the door, a deadpan look <u>plastered on each of their faces like a death-mask<\/u>.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncredulous, he sat in a pensive mood. How cloud the others do such a thing? His discontent turned to silent anger that simmered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I think it is not right, '' he said, just managing not to explode from his growing anger. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n''You sign that sheet, Mr President,'' ordered the Secretary in a barely audible but stern voice.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Why are you doing this?'' he asked, his voice not giving any hint of the boiling cauldron of <u>screaming anger<\/u> in his chest.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Will you sign, Mr President?''<br>\r\n''All right,'' he said, now seething amiably.<br>\r\nHe took his pen, picked up the sheet of paper and looked over the signatures. Then he proceeded to tear up the paper into shreds.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression ''plastered on each of their face like a death mask'' illustrates.","options":["alliteration and metaphor","simile and personification","personification and alliteration","metaphor and simile",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHe was under the siege of three union executive members.<br>\r\nThere was the Secretary standing over him ; there was the Treasurer puffing away at a cigarette; there was the Organiser lounging near the door, a deadpan look <u>plastered on each of their faces like a death-mask<\/u>.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncredulous, he sat in a pensive mood. How cloud the others do such a thing? His discontent turned to silent anger that simmered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I think it is not right, '' he said, just managing not to explode from his growing anger. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n''You sign that sheet, Mr President,'' ordered the Secretary in a barely audible but stern voice.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Why are you doing this?'' he asked, his voice not giving any hint of the boiling cauldron of <u>screaming anger<\/u> in his chest.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Will you sign, Mr President?''<br>\r\n''All right,'' he said, now seething amiably.<br>\r\nHe took his pen, picked up the sheet of paper and looked over the signatures. Then he proceeded to tear up the paper into shreds.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''......... screaming anger'' is an example of","options":["allusion","personjfication","simile","euphei,,,,,ism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHe was under the siege of three union executive members.<br>\r\nThere was the Secretary standing over him ; there was the Treasurer puffing away at a cigarette; there was the Organiser lounging near the door, a deadpan look <u>plastered on each of their faces like a death-mask<\/u>.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIncredulous, he sat in a pensive mood. How cloud the others do such a thing? His discontent turned to silent anger that simmered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I think it is not right, '' he said, just managing not to explode from his growing anger. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n''You sign that sheet, Mr President,'' ordered the Secretary in a barely audible but stern voice.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Why are you doing this?'' he asked, his voice not giving any hint of the boiling cauldron of <u>screaming anger<\/u> in his chest.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Will you sign, Mr President?''<br>\r\n''All right,'' he said, now seething amiably.<br>\r\nHe took his pen, picked up the sheet of paper and looked over the signatures. Then he proceeded to tear up the paper into shreds.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe last paragraph illustrates","options":["foreshadow","pathos","bathos","climax",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWe have come to the crossroads <br>\r\nAnd I must either leave or come with you <br>\r\nI lingered over the choice<br>\r\nBut in the darkness of my doubts<br>\r\nYou lifted the lamp of love<br>\r\nAnd I saw in your face <br>\r\nThe road that I should take.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is","options":["indecision","separation","rejected love","requited love",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWe have come to the crossroads <br>\r\nAnd I must either leave or come with you <br>\r\nI lingered over the choice<br>\r\nBut in the darkness of my doubts<br>\r\nYou lifted the lamp of love<br>\r\nAnd I saw in your face <br>\r\nThe road that I should take.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["decisive","frustrated","disappointed","angry",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWe have come to the crossroads <br>\r\nAnd I must either leave or come with you <br>\r\nI lingered over the choice<br>\r\nBut in the darkness of my doubts<br>\r\nYou lifted the lamp of love<br>\r\nAnd I saw in your face <br>\r\nThe road that I should take.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the poem is","options":["paradox","parody","metaphor","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"The mood of the poem is","options":["jubilant","sad","gloomy","romantic",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWe have come to the crossroads <br>\r\nAnd I must either leave or come with you <br>\r\nI lingered over the choice<br>\r\nBut in the darkness of my doubts<br>\r\nYou lifted the lamp of love<br>\r\nAnd I saw in your face <br>\r\nThe road that I should take.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem can be described as","options":["an epitaph","a lyric","a lullaby","an elegy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Othello","Duke","Brabantio","lago",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Cassio","Brabantio","Roderigo","Othello",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Sooty bosom'' is a metaphor for","options":["a black coat","Othello","a breastplate","lago",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Run from her guardege'' refers to","options":["Emilia","Desdemona","Bianca","Cassio's mistress",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["another street outside the Sagittary","a council chamber","a seaport in Cyprus","the citadel",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Brabantio","Cassio","Gratiano","lago",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe addressee is","options":["Othello","Duke","Roderigo","Montano",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat has happened to the speaker?","options":["He has been fined","He has fallen out of favour","He has been denied promotion","He has lost his job",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression shows that the speaker is","options":["jovial","insincere","polite","unfriendly",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Answer all the question in this section<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Othell0<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo opposite to marriage that she shunned <br>\r\nThe wealthy, curled darlings of our nation,<br>\r\n<u>Run from her guardage<\/u> to the <u>sooty bosom<\/u><br>\r\nOf such a thing as thou to fear, not to delight? <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 66 - 70)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["a street in Venice","a street in Cyprus","outside the citadel","a court before the citadel",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\nWork on,<br>\r\nMy medicine work! Thus credulous fools are caught,<br>\r\nAnd many worthy and chaste dames even thus,<br>\r\nAll guiltless, meet reproach. What ho! My lord!<br>\r\nMy lord, I say!<br>\r\n(Act IV, Scene One, Lines 45 - 49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Cassio","Duke","herself","himself",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\nWork on,<br>\r\nMy medicine work! Thus credulous fools are caught,<br>\r\nAnd many worthy and chaste dames even thus,<br>\r\nAll guiltless, meet reproach. What ho! My lord!<br>\r\nMy lord, I say!<br>\r\n(Act IV, Scene One, Lines 45 - 49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Othello","lago","Lodovico","Bianca",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\nWork on,<br>\r\nMy medicine work! Thus credulous fools are caught,<br>\r\nAnd many worthy and chaste dames even thus,<br>\r\nAll guiltless, meet reproach. What ho! My lord!<br>\r\nMy lord, I say!<br>\r\n(Act IV, Scene One, Lines 45 - 49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJust before this speech,","options":["Othello falls into a trance","Bianca flings a handkerchief at Cassio","Montano fights with Cassio","Roderigo is killed",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\nWork on,<br>\r\nMy medicine work! Thus credulous fools are caught,<br>\r\nAnd many worthy and chaste dames even thus,<br>\r\nAll guiltless, meet reproach. What ho! My lord!<br>\r\nMy lord, I say!<br>\r\n(Act IV, Scene One, Lines 45 - 49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''medicine'' in the extract refers to the speaker's","options":["hatred","passion","lies","loyalty",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\nWork on,<br>\r\nMy medicine work! Thus credulous fools are caught,<br>\r\nAnd many worthy and chaste dames even thus,<br>\r\nAll guiltless, meet reproach. What ho! My lord!<br>\r\nMy lord, I say!<br>\r\n(Act IV, Scene One, Lines 45 - 49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character that enters immediately after is","options":["lago","Emilia","Othello","Cassio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am glad I have found this napkin;<br>\r\nThis was her first remembrance from the Moor.<br>\r\n<u>My wayward husband<\/u> hath a hundred times <br>\r\nWooed me to steal it; but she so loves <u>the token<\/u><br>\r\n(For he conjured her she should ever keep it)<br>\r\nThat she reserves it evermore about her <br>\r\nTo kiss and talk to.<br>\r\n(Act III, Scene Three, Lines 289 - 95)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Bianca","Emilia","Clown","Desdemona",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am glad I have found this napkin;<br>\r\nThis was her first remembrance from the Moor.<br>\r\n<u>My wayward husband<\/u> hath a hundred times <br>\r\nWooed me to steal it; but she so loves <u>the token<\/u><br>\r\n(For he conjured her she should ever keep it)<br>\r\nThat she reserves it evermore about her <br>\r\nTo kiss and talk to.<br>\r\n(Act III, Scene Three, Lines 289 - 95)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe characters that just left the scene are","options":["Othello and lago","Montano and Cassio","Othello and Desdemona","Grantiano and Desdemona",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am glad I have found this napkin;<br>\r\nThis was her first remembrance from the Moor.<br>\r\n<u>My wayward husband<\/u> hath a hundred times <br>\r\nWooed me to steal it; but she so loves <u>the token<\/u><br>\r\n(For he conjured her she should ever keep it)<br>\r\nThat she reserves it evermore about her <br>\r\nTo kiss and talk to.<br>\r\n(Act III, Scene Three, Lines 289 - 95)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'She' in the extract refers to","options":["Bianca","Desdemona","Emilia","Musician",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am glad I have found this napkin;<br>\r\nThis was her first remembrance from the Moor.<br>\r\n<u>My wayward husband<\/u> hath a hundred times <br>\r\nWooed me to steal it; but she so loves <u>the token<\/u><br>\r\n(For he conjured her she should ever keep it)<br>\r\nThat she reserves it evermore about her <br>\r\nTo kiss and talk to.<br>\r\n(Act III, Scene Three, Lines 289 - 95)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'My wayward husband' refers to","options":["Othello","lago","Cassio","Roderigo",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am glad I have found this napkin;<br>\r\nThis was her first remembrance from the Moor.<br>\r\n<u>My wayward husband<\/u> hath a hundred times <br>\r\nWooed me to steal it; but she so loves <u>the token<\/u><br>\r\n(For he conjured her she should ever keep it)<br>\r\nThat she reserves it evermore about her <br>\r\nTo kiss and talk to.<br>\r\n(Act III, Scene Three, Lines 289 - 95)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn the extract ''this napkin'' is ''the token'' of love between","options":["lago and Emilia","Cassio and Desdemona","Bianca and Cassio","Desdemona and Othello",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Gymnosperms bear naked seeds because they lack","options":["ovary","colourful flowers","pollen grains","stigma",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Gymnosperms bear naked seeds because they lack","options":["ovary","colourful flowers","pollen grains","stigma",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An example of an organism that exist as a colony is","options":["Spirogyra","Paramecium","Euglena","Volvox",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"An example of an organism that exist as a colony is","options":["Spirogyra","Paramecium","Euglena","Volvox",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"DNA formation is associated with","options":["Golgi bodies","Iysosomes","mitochondria","nucleus",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Muscles act in opposite direction in order to","options":["cause a bone to move","prevent dislocation at joints","prevent muscle fatigue","regulate bodily activities",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"Muscles act in opposite direction in order to","options":["cause a bone to move","prevent dislocation at joints","prevent muscle fatigue","regulate bodily activities",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2016"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA modest two-room hut built of mud and roofed with straw graciously sheltered the Mensahs. One of the rooms advertised itself as a living room. The kind earthenware pot willingly kept company with four ever-smilling stools. The pot eternally contained cool water for guests. The second room was a warm-hearted bedroom without a bed. The poor pair had to sleep on bare straw mats on the polished dirt floor Some overwashed rags deputised for blankets and sheets and pillows. Two strong dry logs, facing each other like bitter rivals burned themselve out at night, not merly to keep the couple warm but mainly to ward off hungry mosquitoes and other hostile pests.<br>\r\nThere was no door to ward off the cold night air. Some rude devices, however, were contrived to keep the room quite safe from prying eyes and curious domestic animals. Would any thief be ever tempted to peep into <u>such a rude room of such a poor pair?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression 'such a rude room of such a poor pair' illustrates","options":["onomatopoeia","pun","rhyme","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA modest two-room hut built of mud and roofed with straw graciously sheltered the Mensahs. One of the rooms advertised itself as a living room. The kind earthenware pot willingly kept company with four ever-smilling stools. The pot eternally contained cool water for guests. The second room was a warm-hearted bedroom without a bed. The poor pair had to sleep on bare straw mats on the polished dirt floor Some overwashed rags deputised for blankets and sheets and pillows. Two strong dry logs, facing each other like bitter rivals burned themselve out at night, not merly to keep the couple warm but mainly to ward off hungry mosquitoes and other hostile pests.<br>\r\nThere was no door to ward off the cold night air. Some rude devices, however, were contrived to keep the room quite safe from prying eyes and curious domestic animals. Would any thief be ever tempted to peep into <u>such a rude room of such a poor pair?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["dawn","sunset","midday","night",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProud mothers of the coming age,<br>\r\n'Tis good to find you now engage<br>\r\nYour minds and time your lives to raise <br>\r\nAbove the level of bygone days.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis good to see you play your part <br>\r\nWith spirit and undaunted heart,<br>\r\nIt gives young Afric's throbbing soul<br>\r\nA glimpse of a bright and glorious goals.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nGod bless you, mothers of our race,<br>\r\nGod cause to shine on you His face;<br>\r\nAnd give you strength and all you crave<br>\r\nTo bring forth sons and daughters brave<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme is","options":["aabb ccdd eeff","abab abab aabb","abca abbc abab","abba abca abab",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProud mothers of the coming age,<br>\r\n'Tis good to find you now engage<br>\r\nYour minds and time your lives to raise <br>\r\nAbove the level of bygone days.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis good to see you play your part <br>\r\nWith spirit and undaunted heart,<br>\r\nIt gives young Afric's throbbing soul<br>\r\nA glimpse of a bright and glorious goals.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nGod bless you, mothers of our race,<br>\r\nGod cause to shine on you His face;<br>\r\nAnd give you strength and all you crave<br>\r\nTo bring forth sons and daughters brave<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is","options":["the love of mother","invoking the spirit of womanhood","admiration for women's hard work","the suffering of women",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProud mothers of the coming age,<br>\r\n'Tis good to find you now engage<br>\r\nYour minds and time your lives to raise <br>\r\nAbove the level of bygone days.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis good to see you play your part <br>\r\nWith spirit and undaunted heart,<br>\r\nIt gives young Afric's throbbing soul<br>\r\nA glimpse of a bright and glorious goals.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nGod bless you, mothers of our race,<br>\r\nGod cause to shine on you His face;<br>\r\nAnd give you strength and all you crave<br>\r\nTo bring forth sons and daughters brave<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in line 7 is","options":["conceit","personification","hyperbole","pathos",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A speech in a play in which a character speaks his or her thoughts alone is","options":["a monologue","an aside","an epilogue","a soliloquy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"In literature, repetition is used essentially for","options":["rhyme","suspense","allusion","emphasis",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The pattern of a poem without reference to its content is referred to as the","options":["limerick","metre","free verse","form",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The performers in a play constitute the","options":["chorus","characters","audience","east",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the stanza and the question <br>\r\nPan, O great Pan, to thee<br>\r\nThus do we sing!<br>\r\nThou who keep'st chaste and free<br>\r\nAs the young spring:<br>\r\nEver be thy honour spake<br>\r\nFrom that place the more is broke<br>\r\nTo the place day doth unyoke<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe stanza is an example of","options":["appellation","apostrophe","euphemism","elegy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the stanza and the question <br>\r\nPan, O great Pan, to thee<br>\r\nThus do we sing!<br>\r\nThou who keep'st chaste and free<br>\r\nAs the young spring:<br>\r\nEver be thy honour spake<br>\r\nFrom that place the more is broke<br>\r\nTo the place day doth unyoke<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPan is used here as","options":["an allusion","symbol","irony","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the stanza and the question <br>\r\nPan, O great Pan, to thee<br>\r\nThus do we sing!<br>\r\nThou who keep'st chaste and free<br>\r\nAs the young spring:<br>\r\nEver be thy honour spake<br>\r\nFrom that place the more is broke<br>\r\nTo the place day doth unyoke<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme of the stanza is","options":["abcabcc","ababcdd","babacc","bcbccaa",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A metrical foot in which a stressed syllable is followed by an unstressed syllable is","options":["iambic","spondaic","trochaic","dactylic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"........... Is the location of the action of the plot","options":["Setting","Narrative technique","Point of view","Characterization",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A ballad is essentially a ........... poem","options":["descriptive","dramatic","pastoral","narrative",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The first four lines of the Shakespearan sonnet rhyme","options":["abcd","abba","abab","cdcd",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A story in which characters or actions represent abstract ideas or moral qualities is","options":["an epic","a legend","an allegory","a satire",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"The use of imagery in prose or verse","options":["appeals to the senses","develops the plot","creates confusion","obscures meaning",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the line to answer the questions.<br>\r\n'Our leaders will not compromise freedom<br>\r\nNor will our heads give up liberty.'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe lines illustrate","options":["soliloquy","parallelism","dialogue","contrast",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"'heads' in the second line is an example of","options":["synecdoche","inversion","epithet","conceit",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Use the line to answer the questions.<br>\r\n'Our leaders will not compromise freedom<br>\r\nNor will our heads give up liberty.'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA character that develops in the course of a novel or play is described as","options":["flat","antagonist","round","protagonist",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"A dirge is a poem sung","options":["to send a child to sleep","to make workers happy","at a birthday party","at a funeral",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"In drama, the ............. creates humour","options":["hero","clown","villain","chorus",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"'Let me not love thee if I love thee not' illustrates","options":["metaphor","proverb","paradox","meiosis",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"...........is a literary device used to express unpleasant in a more acceptable manner","options":["Epilogue","Epigram","Euphemism","Eulogy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA modest two-room hut built of mud and roofed with straw graciously sheltered the Mensahs. One of the rooms advertised itself as a living room. The kind earthenware pot willingly kept company with four ever-smilling stools. The pot eternally contained cool water for guests. The second room was a warm-hearted bedroom without a bed. The poor pair had to sleep on bare straw mats on the polished dirt floor Some overwashed rags deputised for blankets and sheets and pillows. Two strong dry logs, facing each other like bitter rivals burned themselve out at night, not merly to keep the couple warm but mainly to ward off hungry mosquitoes and other hostile pests.<br>\r\nThere was no door to ward off the cold night air. Some rude devices, however, were contrived to keep the room quite safe from prying eyes and curious domestic animals. Would any thief be ever tempted to peep into <u>such a rude room of such a poor pair?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe write's attitude to the couple is one of","options":["resignation","indifference","patronage","praise",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA modest two-room hut built of mud and roofed with straw graciously sheltered the Mensahs. One of the rooms advertised itself as a living room. The kind earthenware pot willingly kept company with four ever-smilling stools. The pot eternally contained cool water for guests. The second room was a warm-hearted bedroom without a bed. The poor pair had to sleep on bare straw mats on the polished dirt floor Some overwashed rags deputised for blankets and sheets and pillows. Two strong dry logs, facing each other like bitter rivals burned themselve out at night, not merly to keep the couple warm but mainly to ward off hungry mosquitoes and other hostile pests.<br>\r\nThere was no door to ward off the cold night air. Some rude devices, however, were contrived to keep the room quite safe from prying eyes and curious domestic animals. Would any thief be ever tempted to peep into <u>such a rude room of such a poor pair?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the passage is","options":["litotes","personification","simle","paradox",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY <br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nA modest two-room hut built of mud and roofed with straw graciously sheltered the Mensahs. One of the rooms advertised itself as a living room. The kind earthenware pot willingly kept company with four ever-smilling stools. The pot eternally contained cool water for guests. The second room was a warm-hearted bedroom without a bed. The poor pair had to sleep on bare straw mats on the polished dirt floor Some overwashed rags deputised for blankets and sheets and pillows. Two strong dry logs, facing each other like bitter rivals burned themselve out at night, not merly to keep the couple warm but mainly to ward off hungry mosquitoes and other hostile pests.<br>\r\nThere was no door to ward off the cold night air. Some rude devices, however, were contrived to keep the room quite safe from prying eyes and curious domestic animals. Would any thief be ever tempted to peep into <u>such a rude room of such a poor pair?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhetorical question that ends the passage stresses the","options":["wickedness of thieves","poverty of the couple","security of the hut","filthiness of the surrounding",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProud mothers of the coming age,<br>\r\n'Tis good to find you now engage<br>\r\nYour minds and time your lives to raise <br>\r\nAbove the level of bygone days.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis good to see you play your part <br>\r\nWith spirit and undaunted heart,<br>\r\nIt gives young Afric's throbbing soul<br>\r\nA glimpse of a bright and glorious goals.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nGod bless you, mothers of our race,<br>\r\nGod cause to shine on you His face;<br>\r\nAnd give you strength and all you crave<br>\r\nTo bring forth sons and daughters brave<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poet's tone is one of","options":["sadness","joy","condemnation","sarcasm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nProud mothers of the coming age,<br>\r\n'Tis good to find you now engage<br>\r\nYour minds and time your lives to raise <br>\r\nAbove the level of bygone days.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis good to see you play your part <br>\r\nWith spirit and undaunted heart,<br>\r\nIt gives young Afric's throbbing soul<br>\r\nA glimpse of a bright and glorious goals.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nGod bless you, mothers of our race,<br>\r\nGod cause to shine on you His face;<br>\r\nAnd give you strength and all you crave<br>\r\nTo bring forth sons and daughters brave<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'To bring forth sons and daughters brave'' illustrates","options":["paradox","zeugma","inversion","epigram",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Speaker is","options":["Gonzalo","Antonio","Prospero","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Speaker is","options":["Gonzalo","Antonio","Prospero","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe addressee is","options":["Ariel","Ferdinand","Caliban","Miranda",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''impostor'' is","options":["Sebastian","Antonio","Ferdinand","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''advocate'' and the ''impostor'' are","options":["conspirators","suspicious of each other","enemies","attracted to each other",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Answer all the questions in this section <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and anser the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSilence ! One word more <br>\r\nShall make me chide thee, if not hate thee. What!<br>\r\nAn advocate for an impostor! Hush!<br>\r\n(Act 1,Scene Two, lines 478 - 480)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker's utterance betrays his","options":["anger","pretence","hatred","sorrow",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou cram <u>these words<\/u> into mine ears against <br>\r\nThe stomach of my sense. Would I had never <br>\r\nMarried my daughter there! For, coming thence,<br>\r\nMy son is lost, and, <u>in my rate<\/u>, she too,<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 99 - 102)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Gonzalo","Antonio","Sebastian","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou cram <u>these words<\/u> into mine ears against <br>\r\nThe stomach of my sense. Would I had never <br>\r\nMarried my daughter there! For, coming thence,<br>\r\nMy son is lost, and, <u>in my rate<\/u>, she too,<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 99 - 102)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''These words'' refer to","options":["the shipwreck","the son's disappearance","the daughter's wedding","Prospero's magic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou cram <u>these words<\/u> into mine ears against <br>\r\nThe stomach of my sense. Would I had never <br>\r\nMarried my daughter there! For, coming thence,<br>\r\nMy son is lost, and, <u>in my rate<\/u>, she too,<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 99 - 102)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhere did the wee\\dding take place?","options":["Algiers","Milan","Tunis","Naples",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou cram <u>these words<\/u> into mine ears against <br>\r\nThe stomach of my sense. Would I had never <br>\r\nMarried my daughter there! For, coming thence,<br>\r\nMy son is lost, and, <u>in my rate<\/u>, she too,<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 99 - 102)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["outside Prospero's cell","on a ship","in front of Prospero's cell","another part of the island",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou cram <u>these words<\/u> into mine ears against <br>\r\nThe stomach of my sense. Would I had never <br>\r\nMarried my daughter there! For, coming thence,<br>\r\nMy son is lost, and, <u>in my rate<\/u>, she too,<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 99 - 102)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.......in my rate'' means","options":["I'm very certain","so far as I can see","there's no doubt","as it appears",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the uestion<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel:  All hail, great master! Grave sir, hali ! I come<br>\r\nTo answer the best pleasure; be't to fly,<br>\r\nTo swim, to dive into the fire, to ride<br>\r\nOn the curled clouds, to thy strong bidding task <br>\r\nAriel and all his quality.<br>\r\n(Act I Scene Two, lines 189 - 193)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel has 'come' because","options":["he has been invited by Prospero","he wants to make a request","he desires a meeting","flying is no problem to him",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the uestion<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel:  All hail, great master! Grave sir, hali ! I come<br>\r\nTo answer the best pleasure; be't to fly,<br>\r\nTo swim, to dive into the fire, to ride<br>\r\nOn the curled clouds, to thy strong bidding task <br>\r\nAriel and all his quality.<br>\r\n(Act I Scene Two, lines 189 - 193)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero has actually","options":["raised a storm at sea","punished Miranda","dismissed Ferdinand","commanded Ariel to disappear",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the uestion<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel:  All hail, great master! Grave sir, hali ! I come<br>\r\nTo answer the best pleasure; be't to fly,<br>\r\nTo swim, to dive into the fire, to ride<br>\r\nOn the curled clouds, to thy strong bidding task <br>\r\nAriel and all his quality.<br>\r\n(Act I Scene Two, lines 189 - 193)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBefore Ariel's entry","options":["Ferdinand has brought in some wood","Prospero had put Miranda to sleep","Caliban had been sweaing at prospero","Trinculo had discovered Caliban's cloak",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the uestion<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel:  All hail, great master! Grave sir, hali ! I come<br>\r\nTo answer the best pleasure; be't to fly,<br>\r\nTo swim, to dive into the fire, to ride<br>\r\nOn the curled clouds, to thy strong bidding task <br>\r\nAriel and all his quality.<br>\r\n(Act I Scene Two, lines 189 - 193)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Ariel  and all his quality' means Ariel and","options":["all at his command","the quality of a spirit","his band of spirit","an ability to cause mischief",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the uestion<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAriel:  All hail, great master! Grave sir, hali ! I come<br>\r\nTo answer the best pleasure; be't to fly,<br>\r\nTo swim, to dive into the fire, to ride<br>\r\nOn the curled clouds, to thy strong bidding task <br>\r\nAriel and all his quality.<br>\r\n(Act I Scene Two, lines 189 - 193)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSoon after, Ariel","options":["flies off to do his duty","recounts the confusion on board the ship","kneels down to worship Prospero","calls Ceres and another spirit",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX: We two, my lord.<br>\r\nWill guard your person while you take take your rest,<br>\r\nAnd watch your safety.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY: Thank you - Wondrous heavy .<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 184 - 187)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''we two'' are","options":["Antonio and Adrian","Sebastian and Adrian","Sebastian and Franciso","Antonio and Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX: We two, my lord.<br>\r\nWill guard your person while you take take your rest,<br>\r\nAnd watch your safety.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY: Thank you - Wondrous heavy .<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 184 - 187)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX and Y are","options":["Antonio and Alonso","Sebastian and Alonso","Antonio and Gonzalo","Sebastian and Gonzalo",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX: We two, my lord.<br>\r\nWill guard your person while you take take your rest,<br>\r\nAnd watch your safety.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY: Thank you - Wondrous heavy .<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 184 - 187)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX and Y are","options":["Antonio and Alonso","Sebastian and Alonso","Antonio and Gonzalo","Sebastian and Gonzalo",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX: We two, my lord.<br>\r\nWill guard your person while you take take your rest,<br>\r\nAnd watch your safety.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY: Thank you - Wondrous heavy .<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 184 - 187)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe situation in the extract is highly","options":["satirical","prophetic","ironical","comical",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX: We two, my lord.<br>\r\nWill guard your person while you take take your rest,<br>\r\nAnd watch your safety.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY: Thank you - Wondrous heavy .<br>\r\n(Act II, Scene One, lines 184 - 187)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat has happened to all the other characters in the scene?","options":["They have been made deaf and dumb","Ariel has put them all to sleep","They have been sent away","Prospero has put them to sleep",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"In drama, comic relief often occurs in","options":["comedies","tragedies","historical plays","romantic plays",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A struggle between opposing forces in a story or play is","options":["denouement","conflict","comedy","tragedy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"An expression from which one derives a mental picture is","options":["paradox","exaggeration","imagery","photography",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The repetition of the same vowel sounds in a line is","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","parallelism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A character in the story who narrates what happens to him or her is","options":["a second person narrator","a first person narrator","an  omniscient narrator","a third person narrator",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"An understatement  is otherwise called","options":["litotes","conceit","pun","contrast",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The loneliest people live in the most crowded places illustrates","options":["paradox","anecdote","allegory","parody",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A person's life story written by another person is","options":["a commentary","a biography","an autobiography","an epistolary",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"The term used to depict the freedom of a poet with language is","options":["poetic diction","bathos","graphology","poetic licence",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A poem in which a lone speaker seems to be addressing someone else is a","options":["pathetic fallacy","verbal irony","dramatic irony","dramatic monologue",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A story which explains a natural phenomenon is","options":["legend","parable","myth","fiction",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A short which expresses an idea in a clever way is","options":["an epigram","a limerick","an ode","a lyric",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A literary work that vividly portrays life can be described as","options":["realistic","romantic","idealistic","sarcastic",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A character whose actions or qualities serve to heighten those of the hero through contrast is","options":["an adversary","a protagonist","an antagonist","a foil",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"One of the following is used to develop character","options":["Climax","Atmosphere","Setting","Dialogue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A curtain raiser is an introductory performance that is","options":["not part of the main play","the first part of the main play","not separate from the play","the first party of the final scene",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"A stanza of four lines is a","options":["couplet","quintet","septet","quatrain",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"_ in drama operates against a character who is unawares of a situation which the audience know about","options":["Verbal irony","Dramatic irony","Satire","Parody",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSaid the Lion: ''On music I dote<br>\r\nBut something is wrong with my throat<br>\r\nWhen I practice a scale<br>\r\nThe listeners quail<br>\r\nAnd flee at the first note''.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat type of poem is this?","options":["Epic","Limerick","Ode","Sonnet",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSaid the Lion: ''On music I dote<br>\r\nBut something is wrong with my throat<br>\r\nWhen I practice a scale<br>\r\nThe listeners quail<br>\r\nAnd flee at the first note''.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme of the poem is","options":["aabba","ababa","ababb","abbaa",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goldsmith at work is a priest at the altar . As though he was were performing the Eucharist, he is engaged in deliberate motions of reverence. The small vials of various liquids such as mercury are little vessels of communion wine. The minuscule rings of intricately crafted gold are like miniature wafers.<br>\r\nHe dips one tiny ring into a liquid, lifts it up to the sky and presses it onto a space in the growing length of necklace. It fits- it is like dipping bread into wine and slipping it between the parted lips of a communicant.<br>\r\nOur lent vigils are not as solemn as the goldsmith's silent solemnity that directs his work. We look on as the wizardry of the master matter craftsman displays itself. We are held in thrall....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject matter of the passage is","options":["a goldsmith at work","celebrating the Eucharist","a priest at the altar","communion wine and wafers",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goldsmith at work is a priest at the altar . As though he was were performing the Eucharist, he is engaged in deliberate motions of reverence. The small vials of various liquids such as mercury are little vessels of communion wine. The minuscule rings of intricately crafted gold are like miniature wafers.<br>\r\nHe dips one tiny ring into a liquid, lifts it up to the sky and presses it onto a space in the growing length of necklace. It fits- it is like dipping bread into wine and slipping it between the parted lips of a communicant.<br>\r\nOur lent vigils are not as solemn as the goldsmith's silent solemnity that directs his work. We look on as the wizardry of the master matter craftsman displays itself. We are held in thrall....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant devices used are","options":["personification and irony","parallelism and repetition","metaphor and simile","metonymy and synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goldsmith at work is a priest at the altar . As though he was were performing the Eucharist, he is engaged in deliberate motions of reverence. The small vials of various liquids such as mercury are little vessels of communion wine. The minuscule rings of intricately crafted gold are like miniature wafers.<br>\r\nHe dips one tiny ring into a liquid, lifts it up to the sky and presses it onto a space in the growing length of necklace. It fits- it is like dipping bread into wine and slipping it between the parted lips of a communicant.<br>\r\nOur lent vigils are not as solemn as the goldsmith's silent solemnity that directs his work. We look on as the wizardry of the master matter craftsman displays itself. We are held in thrall....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe use of the above devices creates an atmosphere of","options":["fear","doom","hope","awe",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goldsmith at work is a priest at the altar . As though he was were performing the Eucharist, he is engaged in deliberate motions of reverence. The small vials of various liquids such as mercury are little vessels of communion wine. The minuscule rings of intricately crafted gold are like miniature wafers.<br>\r\nHe dips one tiny ring into a liquid, lifts it up to the sky and presses it onto a space in the growing length of necklace. It fits- it is like dipping bread into wine and slipping it between the parted lips of a communicant.<br>\r\nOur lent vigils are not as solemn as the goldsmith's silent solemnity that directs his work. We look on as the wizardry of the master matter craftsman displays itself. We are held in thrall....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe writer's attitude is one of","options":["bewilderment","reverence","indifference","arrogance",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe goldsmith at work is a priest at the altar . As though he was were performing the Eucharist, he is engaged in deliberate motions of reverence. The small vials of various liquids such as mercury are little vessels of communion wine. The minuscule rings of intricately crafted gold are like miniature wafers.<br>\r\nHe dips one tiny ring into a liquid, lifts it up to the sky and presses it onto a space in the growing length of necklace. It fits- it is like dipping bread into wine and slipping it between the parted lips of a communicant.<br>\r\nOur lent vigils are not as solemn as the goldsmith's silent solemnity that directs his work. We look on as the wizardry of the master matter craftsman displays itself. We are held in thrall....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe narrative technique captures the _ of the scene.","options":["seriousness","vividness","ordinariness","loneliness",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt dawn must I rise to till the rock<br>\r\nThat our land has turned into<br>\r\nThe land where on we'd gleefully harvested paddy<br>\r\nPlanted and nurtured and tended on plots marshy<br>\r\nOur woes are bloody woes of accursed revenges<br>\r\nOf the land spirits aggrieved and by his fellow<br>\r\nKindred blood has counted for less than no value<br>\r\nBrother's wife has been wife to other brother's brother <br>\r\nCommunal loot has emptied our country silos<br>\r\n<u>The earth has stooped breathing and sighed<\/u><br>\r\nSoldered tears has the moon shed<br>\r\nThe earth was scorched at noon-day night<br>\r\nAnd our land has turned to hoeing rock.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is","options":["famine and disease","drought and heat","abomination and retribution","sickness and death",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt dawn must I rise to till the rock<br>\r\nThat our land has turned into<br>\r\nThe land where on we'd gleefully harvested paddy<br>\r\nPlanted and nurtured and tended on plots marshy<br>\r\nOur woes are bloody woes of accursed revenges<br>\r\nOf the land spirits aggrieved and by his fellow<br>\r\nKindred blood has counted for less than no value<br>\r\nBrother's wife has been wife to other brother's brother <br>\r\nCommunal loot has emptied our country silos<br>\r\n<u>The earth has stooped breathing and sighed<\/u><br>\r\nSoldered tears has the moon shed<br>\r\nThe earth was scorched at noon-day night<br>\r\nAnd our land has turned to hoeing rock.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the poet is one of","options":["recklessness","hopelessness","happiness","loneliness",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt dawn must I rise to till the rock<br>\r\nThat our land has turned into<br>\r\nThe land where on we'd gleefully harvested paddy<br>\r\nPlanted and nurtured and tended on plots marshy<br>\r\nOur woes are bloody woes of accursed revenges<br>\r\nOf the land spirits aggrieved and by his fellow<br>\r\nKindred blood has counted for less than no value<br>\r\nBrother's wife has been wife to other brother's brother <br>\r\nCommunal loot has emptied our country silos<br>\r\n<u>The earth has stooped breathing and sighed<\/u><br>\r\nSoldered tears has the moon shed<br>\r\nThe earth was scorched at noon-day night<br>\r\nAnd our land has turned to hoeing rock.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The earth has stopped breathing and sighed'' illustrates","options":["bathos","climax","personification","paradox",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt dawn must I rise to till the rock<br>\r\nThat our land has turned into<br>\r\nThe land where on we'd gleefully harvested paddy<br>\r\nPlanted and nurtured and tended on plots marshy<br>\r\nOur woes are bloody woes of accursed revenges<br>\r\nOf the land spirits aggrieved and by his fellow<br>\r\nKindred blood has counted for less than no value<br>\r\nBrother's wife has been wife to other brother's brother <br>\r\nCommunal loot has emptied our country silos<br>\r\n<u>The earth has stooped breathing and sighed<\/u><br>\r\nSoldered tears has the moon shed<br>\r\nThe earth was scorched at noon-day night<br>\r\nAnd our land has turned to hoeing rock.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe run-on lines convey the speaker's","options":["indignation","lamentation","disappointment","defiance",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt dawn must I rise to till the rock<br>\r\nThat our land has turned into<br>\r\nThe land where on we'd gleefully harvested paddy<br>\r\nPlanted and nurtured and tended on plots marshy<br>\r\nOur woes are bloody woes of accursed revenges<br>\r\nOf the land spirits aggrieved and by his fellow<br>\r\nKindred blood has counted for less than no value<br>\r\nBrother's wife has been wife to other brother's brother <br>\r\nCommunal loot has emptied our country silos<br>\r\n<u>The earth has stooped breathing and sighed<\/u><br>\r\nSoldered tears has the moon shed<br>\r\nThe earth was scorched at noon-day night<br>\r\nAnd our land has turned to hoeing rock.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThere is a predominance of words associated with","options":["celebration","nature","governance","nurture",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCaliban:  Ay, that I will; and I'II be wise hereafter, <br>\r\nAnd seek for grace. What a thrice-double ass<br>\r\nWas I, to take <u>this drunkard<\/u> for a god,<br>\r\nAnd worship this dull foot!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero : Go to; away!<br>\r\nAlonso : Hence, and bestow <u>your luggage<\/u> where you found it.<br>\r\nSebastian : <u>Or stole, rather.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act V, scene one lines 293 - 299)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat is Caliban promising to do?","options":["Carry more wood","Behave appropriately for forgiveness","Denounce Stephano and Trinculo","Confess his part in the conspiracy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCaliban:  Ay, that I will; and I'II be wise hereafter, <br>\r\nAnd seek for grace. What a thrice-double ass<br>\r\nWas I, to take <u>this drunkard<\/u> for a god,<br>\r\nAnd worship this dull foot!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero : Go to; away!<br>\r\nAlonso : Hence, and bestow <u>your luggage<\/u> where you found it.<br>\r\nSebastian : <u>Or stole, rather.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act V, scene one lines 293 - 299)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPROSPERO HAS ASKED CALIBAN TO","options":["go and bring Miranda","go to Prospero's cell","fetch more wood","learn his language lessons",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCaliban:  Ay, that I will; and I'II be wise hereafter, <br>\r\nAnd seek for grace. What a thrice-double ass<br>\r\nWas I, to take <u>this drunkard<\/u> for a god,<br>\r\nAnd worship this dull foot!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero : Go to; away!<br>\r\nAlonso : Hence, and bestow <u>your luggage<\/u> where you found it.<br>\r\nSebastian : <u>Or stole, rather.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act V, scene one lines 293 - 299)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe contents of ''your luggage'' are","options":["Alonso's satchel and swords","food and water from the ship","paddles fur and a harpoon","the clothing put up by Ariel",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCaliban:  Ay, that I will; and I'II be wise hereafter, <br>\r\nAnd seek for grace. What a thrice-double ass<br>\r\nWas I, to take <u>this drunkard<\/u> for a god,<br>\r\nAnd worship this dull foot!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero : Go to; away!<br>\r\nAlonso : Hence, and bestow <u>your luggage<\/u> where you found it.<br>\r\nSebastian : <u>Or stole, rather.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act V, scene one lines 293 - 299)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''this drunkard'' is","options":["Trinculo","Stephano","Gonzalo","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nCaliban:  Ay, that I will; and I'II be wise hereafter, <br>\r\nAnd seek for grace. What a thrice-double ass<br>\r\nWas I, to take <u>this drunkard<\/u> for a god,<br>\r\nAnd worship this dull foot!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero : Go to; away!<br>\r\nAlonso : Hence, and bestow <u>your luggage<\/u> where you found it.<br>\r\nSebastian : <u>Or stole, rather.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act V, scene one lines 293 - 299)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSebastian says ''Or stole it, rather'' because the luggage","options":["does not belong to Caliban","belongs to Caliban","is not from the ship","is from the ship",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extrat and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero:  <u>Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated<\/u><br>\r\n<u>In what thou hadst to say<\/u>. So, with good life<br>\r\nAnd observation strange, my meaner ministers<br>\r\nTheir several kinds have done. My high charms work,<br>\r\nAnd these, <u>mine enemies<\/u> are all knit up<br>\r\nIn their distractions. They now are in my power;<br>\r\nAnd in these fits I leave them,....<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 85-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero is speaking to","options":["Caliban","Miranda","Ferdinand","Ariel",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extrat and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero:  <u>Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated<\/u><br>\r\n<u>In what thou hadst to say<\/u>. So, with good life<br>\r\nAnd observation strange, my meaner ministers<br>\r\nTheir several kinds have done. My high charms work,<br>\r\nAnd these, <u>mine enemies<\/u> are all knit up<br>\r\nIn their distractions. They now are in my power;<br>\r\nAnd in these fits I leave them,....<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 85-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe first line means that the addressee","options":["obeyed Prospero's instructions exactly","did not carry out Prospero's intructions","modified the instruction of Prospero","failed to understand the instructions of Prospero",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extrat and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero:  <u>Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated<\/u><br>\r\n<u>In what thou hadst to say<\/u>. So, with good life<br>\r\nAnd observation strange, my meaner ministers<br>\r\nTheir several kinds have done. My high charms work,<br>\r\nAnd these, <u>mine enemies<\/u> are all knit up<br>\r\nIn their distractions. They now are in my power;<br>\r\nAnd in these fits I leave them,....<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 85-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero's enemies include the voyagers but not","options":["Alonso","Antonio","Ferdinand","Stephano",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extrat and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero:  <u>Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated<\/u><br>\r\n<u>In what thou hadst to say<\/u>. So, with good life<br>\r\nAnd observation strange, my meaner ministers<br>\r\nTheir several kinds have done. My high charms work,<br>\r\nAnd these, <u>mine enemies<\/u> are all knit up<br>\r\nIn their distractions. They now are in my power;<br>\r\nAnd in these fits I leave them,....<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 85-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat has just taken place is that","options":["the enemies have been tantalized with a banquet","Caliban brought home some wood","Ferdinand is splitting wood","Miranda has offered to help Ferinard",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extrat and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProspero:  <u>Of my instruction hast thou nothing bated<\/u><br>\r\n<u>In what thou hadst to say<\/u>. So, with good life<br>\r\nAnd observation strange, my meaner ministers<br>\r\nTheir several kinds have done. My high charms work,<br>\r\nAnd these, <u>mine enemies<\/u> are all knit up<br>\r\nIn their distractions. They now are in my power;<br>\r\nAnd in these fits I leave them,....<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 85-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nProsero decides to","options":["sit back and watch","kick Caliban in the mouth","go to Ferdinard","Discharge Ariel",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : <u>So they are.<\/u><br>\r\nMy spirits, as in a dream, are all bound up.<br>\r\nMy father's loss, the weakness which I feel,<br>\r\nThe wrack of all my friends, nor <u>this man's<\/u> threats<br>\r\nTo whom I am subdued, are but light to me,<br>\r\nMight I but through my prison once a day<br>\r\nBehold <u>this maid.<\/u> All corners else o'th' earth<br>\r\nLet liberty make use of,...<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 487-496)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Alonso","Ferdinand","Gonzalo","Boatswain",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : <u>So they are.<\/u><br>\r\nMy spirits, as in a dream, are all bound up.<br>\r\nMy father's loss, the weakness which I feel,<br>\r\nThe wrack of all my friends, nor <u>this man's<\/u> threats<br>\r\nTo whom I am subdued, are but light to me,<br>\r\nMight I but through my prison once a day<br>\r\nBehold <u>this maid.<\/u> All corners else o'th' earth<br>\r\nLet liberty make use of,...<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 487-496)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''this man'' is","options":["Alonso","Trinculo","Stephano","Prospero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : <u>So they are.<\/u><br>\r\nMy spirits, as in a dream, are all bound up.<br>\r\nMy father's loss, the weakness which I feel,<br>\r\nThe wrack of all my friends, nor <u>this man's<\/u> threats<br>\r\nTo whom I am subdued, are but light to me,<br>\r\nMight I but through my prison once a day<br>\r\nBehold <u>this maid.<\/u> All corners else o'th' earth<br>\r\nLet liberty make use of,...<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 487-496)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''this maid'' is","options":["Caribel","Miranda","Sycorax","Dido",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : <u>So they are.<\/u><br>\r\nMy spirits, as in a dream, are all bound up.<br>\r\nMy father's loss, the weakness which I feel,<br>\r\nThe wrack of all my friends, nor <u>this man's<\/u> threats<br>\r\nTo whom I am subdued, are but light to me,<br>\r\nMight I but through my prison once a day<br>\r\nBehold <u>this maid.<\/u> All corners else o'th' earth<br>\r\nLet liberty make use of,...<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 487-496)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThose present in this scene are","options":["Stephano and Trinculo","Prospero and Miranda","Prospero and Gonzalo","Miranda and Alonso",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : <u>So they are.<\/u><br>\r\nMy spirits, as in a dream, are all bound up.<br>\r\nMy father's loss, the weakness which I feel,<br>\r\nThe wrack of all my friends, nor <u>this man's<\/u> threats<br>\r\nTo whom I am subdued, are but light to me,<br>\r\nMight I but through my prison once a day<br>\r\nBehold <u>this maid.<\/u> All corners else o'th' earth<br>\r\nLet liberty make use of,...<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 487-496)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''So they are'' refers to the","options":["speaker's friends","speaker's nerves","monster's threats","listener's spirits",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I speak true! if hollowly, invert<br>\r\nWhat best is boded me to mischief! I,<br>\r\nBeyond all limit of what else i' the world,<br>\r\nDo love, prize, honour you.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line 70-73)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Prospero","Ferdinand","Miranda","Gonzalo",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I speak true! if hollowly, invert<br>\r\nWhat best is boded me to mischief! I,<br>\r\nBeyond all limit of what else i' the world,<br>\r\nDo love, prize, honour you.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line 70-73)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWho is with the speaker?","options":["Miranda","Gonzalo","Prospero","Ferdinand",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I speak true! if hollowly, invert<br>\r\nWhat best is boded me to mischief! I,<br>\r\nBeyond all limit of what else i' the world,<br>\r\nDo love, prize, honour you.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line 70-73)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker wants to","options":["prove his love","deny his love","prove his innocence","affirm his loyalty",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I speak true! if hollowly, invert<br>\r\nWhat best is boded me to mischief! I,<br>\r\nBeyond all limit of what else i' the world,<br>\r\nDo love, prize, honour you.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line 70-73)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is lured to that place by","options":["Ariel","Caliban","Miranda","Gonzalo",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I speak true! if hollowly, invert<br>\r\nWhat best is boded me to mischief! I,<br>\r\nBeyond all limit of what else i' the world,<br>\r\nDo love, prize, honour you.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line 70-73)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["another part of the island","in the palace","on a ship","before Prospero's cell",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2014"},{"question":"_ is fundamental to a play or novel.","options":["Mime","Conflict","Flashback","Epilogue",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A long and serious narrative about heroic characters is a\/an","options":["burlesque","ballad","epic","elegy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The device used in 'Light as wind on water laid' is","options":["rhyme","simile","onomatopeia","pun",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"''The fire gnawed ceaselessly at the bark of the tree'' illustrates","options":["personification","eithet","allusion","paradox",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"This book should fill the memory, rule the heart and guide the feet.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe above expression illustrates the use of","options":["repetition","refrain","synecdoche","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"The author's attitude towards the subject being treated is","options":["mood","tone","feeling","atmosphere",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"One of the following makes use of gesture only:","options":["comedy","lampoon","mime","satire",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An omniscient narrator in a novel","options":["dataches himself from the story","knows nothing about the characters and events","knows everything about the caharecters and events","is a character in the story",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In poetry _ is made up of stressed and unstressed syllables","options":["an anapaest","trochee","dacty 11","an iambus",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Bank verse has no","options":["metre","rhyme","rhythm","imagery",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A very brief story is an","options":["allusion","autobiography","allegory","anecdote",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"An epilogue","options":["introduces a play","develops characters","sums up a play","introduces characters",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"'The king has joined his ancestors' is an example of","options":["euphemism","eulogy","malapropism","trilogy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In the line 'season of mist and mellow fruitfulness', the main appeal is to the sense of","options":["touch","sight","hearing","smell",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A question used for effect which does not require an answer is","options":["oratorial","antithetical","anticlimactic","rhetorical",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"''The pen is mightier than the sword'' is an example of","options":["symbol","metaphor","metonymy","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"In a play, unfolding events reach their peak in the","options":["climax","denouement","catharsis","conflict",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"''But at my back I always hear<br>\r\nTime's winged chariot hurrying near'' illustrates","options":["metaphor","apostrophe","oxymoron","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A short witty saying is a\/an","options":["epitaph","sonnet","limerick","epigram",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs they trooped off down the field with their sullen dogs, the farmer started the tractor up and <u>the cutter blade blurred into life<\/u><br>\r\nLeft alone, Grooby sank into a shocked stupor. His mind whirled around <u>like a fly that dared not alight<\/u>. A blank vacancy held him. He seemed unable to move, even to wipe away the sweat that collected in his eyebrows and leaked down into his eyes. He sensed that the sun had settled over the earth, so that <u>the air was actually burning gas.<\/u> He watched  <u>the tractor dwindle in the bottom of the field,<\/u> as if it were melting into a glittering muddle in the haze.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''...the cutter blade blurred into life''.<br>\r\nThe above expression appeals to the sense of","options":["hearing","touch","sight","taste",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs they trooped off down the field with their sullen dogs, the farmer started the tractor up and <u>the cutter blade blurred into life<\/u><br>\r\nLeft alone, Grooby sank into a shocked stupor. His mind whirled around <u>like a fly that dared not alight<\/u>. A blank vacancy held him. He seemed unable to move, even to wipe away the sweat that collected in his eyebrows and leaked down into his eyes. He sensed that the sun had settled over the earth, so that <u>the air was actually burning gas.<\/u> He watched  <u>the tractor dwindle in the bottom of the field,<\/u> as if it were melting into a glittering muddle in the haze.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The air was actually burning gas'' is a","options":["personification","euphemism","metaphor","paradox",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs they trooped off down the field with their sullen dogs, the farmer started the tractor up and <u>the cutter blade blurred into life<\/u><br>\r\nLeft alone, Grooby sank into a shocked stupor. His mind whirled around <u>like a fly that dared not alight<\/u>. A blank vacancy held him. He seemed unable to move, even to wipe away the sweat that collected in his eyebrows and leaked down into his eyes. He sensed that the sun had settled over the earth, so that <u>the air was actually burning gas.<\/u> He watched  <u>the tractor dwindle in the bottom of the field,<\/u> as if it were melting into a glittering muddle in the haze.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe diction conveys a feeling of","options":["hope","helplessness","anger","indifference",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs they trooped off down the field with their sullen dogs, the farmer started the tractor up and <u>the cutter blade blurred into life<\/u><br>\r\nLeft alone, Grooby sank into a shocked stupor. His mind whirled around <u>like a fly that dared not alight<\/u>. A blank vacancy held him. He seemed unable to move, even to wipe away the sweat that collected in his eyebrows and leaked down into his eyes. He sensed that the sun had settled over the earth, so that <u>the air was actually burning gas.<\/u> He watched  <u>the tractor dwindle in the bottom of the field,<\/u> as if it were melting into a glittering muddle in the haze.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression ''like fly that dared not alight'' is a\/an","options":["simile","hyberbole","irony","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs they trooped off down the field with their sullen dogs, the farmer started the tractor up and <u>the cutter blade blurred into life<\/u><br>\r\nLeft alone, Grooby sank into a shocked stupor. His mind whirled around <u>like a fly that dared not alight<\/u>. A blank vacancy held him. He seemed unable to move, even to wipe away the sweat that collected in his eyebrows and leaked down into his eyes. He sensed that the sun had settled over the earth, so that <u>the air was actually burning gas.<\/u> He watched  <u>the tractor dwindle in the bottom of the field,<\/u> as if it were melting into a glittering muddle in the haze.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting of the extract is","options":["dawn","midday","evening","night",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI'm going soldering:<br>\r\n<u>Mad the rhythm runs<\/u><br>\r\nWith drumming and with trumpeting<br>\r\nAnd glory of the guns.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI've come home again:<br>\r\nI know that blood is red;<br>\r\nI know how sodden falls the rain<br>\r\nWhere flesh lies dead.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is best described as the","options":["love of war","glory of war","excitement of war","reality of war",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI'm going soldering:<br>\r\n<u>Mad the rhythm runs<\/u><br>\r\nWith drumming and with trumpeting<br>\r\nAnd glory of the guns.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI've come home again:<br>\r\nI know that blood is red;<br>\r\nI know how sodden falls the rain<br>\r\nWhere flesh lies dead.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Mad the rhythm runs'' is an example of","options":["pathos","oxymoron","bathos","inversion",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI'm going soldering:<br>\r\n<u>Mad the rhythm runs<\/u><br>\r\nWith drumming and with trumpeting<br>\r\nAnd glory of the guns.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI've come home again:<br>\r\nI know that blood is red;<br>\r\nI know how sodden falls the rain<br>\r\nWhere flesh lies dead.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme in the first stanza is","options":["aabb","abab","abbaa","aabc",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI'm going soldering:<br>\r\n<u>Mad the rhythm runs<\/u><br>\r\nWith drumming and with trumpeting<br>\r\nAnd glory of the guns.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI've come home again:<br>\r\nI know that blood is red;<br>\r\nI know how sodden falls the rain<br>\r\nWhere flesh lies dead.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant sound device in the second stanza is","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopeia","repetition",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI'm going soldering:<br>\r\n<u>Mad the rhythm runs<\/u><br>\r\nWith drumming and with trumpeting<br>\r\nAnd glory of the guns.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI've come home again:<br>\r\nI know that blood is red;<br>\r\nI know how sodden falls the rain<br>\r\nWhere flesh lies dead.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe two contrasting moods in the poem is are","options":["sadness and hope","bravery and cowardice","excitement and disappointment","calmness and anxiety",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou <u>liest<\/u>, most ignorant monster! I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou deboshed fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I today. Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half a fish and half a monster? <br>\r\n(act 111, scene two lines 23-27)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Stephano","Caliban","Trinculo","Adrian",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou <u>liest<\/u>, most ignorant monster! I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou deboshed fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I today. Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half a fish and half a monster? <br>\r\n(act 111, scene two lines 23-27)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Trinculo","Stephano","Sebastian","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou <u>liest<\/u>, most ignorant monster! I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou deboshed fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I today. Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half a fish and half a monster? <br>\r\n(act 111, scene two lines 23-27)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''lie'' is that the speaker is a\/an","options":["drunkard","coward","ass","idiot",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou <u>liest<\/u>, most ignorant monster! I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou deboshed fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I today. Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half a fish and half a monster? <br>\r\n(act 111, scene two lines 23-27)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe addressee asks that the speaker be","options":["punished severely","hanged on a tree","beaten to death","bitten to death",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou <u>liest<\/u>, most ignorant monster! I am in case to justle a constable. Why, thou deboshed fish, thou, was there ever man a coward that hath drunk so much sack as I today. Wilt thou tell a monstrous lie, being but half a fish and half a monster? <br>\r\n(act 111, scene two lines 23-27)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLater in the scene the addressee proposes a plot to","options":["make Trinculo king of the island","kill prospero","steal miranda","rob prospero of his clothes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are <u>three men of sin,<\/u> whom Destiny -<br>\r\nThat hath to instrument this lower world<br>\r\nAnd what is in't - the never-surfeited sea<br>\r\nHath caused to belch up you; and on this island,<br>\r\nWhere man doth not inhabit - you 'mongst men<br>\r\nBeing most unfit to live.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 53-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Prospero","Miranda","Ariel","Gonzalo",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are <u>three men of sin,<\/u> whom Destiny -<br>\r\nThat hath to instrument this lower world<br>\r\nAnd what is in't - the never-surfeited sea<br>\r\nHath caused to belch up you; and on this island,<br>\r\nWhere man doth not inhabit - you 'mongst men<br>\r\nBeing most unfit to live.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 53-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''three men of sin'' are","options":["Alonso,Gonzalo and Antonio","Alonso, Antonio and Sebastian","Antonio,Sebastian and Gonzalo","Sebastian,Gonzalo and Antonio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are <u>three men of sin,<\/u> whom Destiny -<br>\r\nThat hath to instrument this lower world<br>\r\nAnd what is in't - the never-surfeited sea<br>\r\nHath caused to belch up you; and on this island,<br>\r\nWhere man doth not inhabit - you 'mongst men<br>\r\nBeing most unfit to live.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 53-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn the first line, 'Destiny' is","options":["metaphor","personification","allusion","euphemism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are <u>three men of sin,<\/u> whom Destiny -<br>\r\nThat hath to instrument this lower world<br>\r\nAnd what is in't - the never-surfeited sea<br>\r\nHath caused to belch up you; and on this island,<br>\r\nWhere man doth not inhabit - you 'mongst men<br>\r\nBeing most unfit to live.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 53-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker immediately","options":["reports them to Prospero","makes them repent","drives them away","makes them go mad temporarily",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou are <u>three men of sin,<\/u> whom Destiny -<br>\r\nThat hath to instrument this lower world<br>\r\nAnd what is in't - the never-surfeited sea<br>\r\nHath caused to belch up you; and on this island,<br>\r\nWhere man doth not inhabit - you 'mongst men<br>\r\nBeing most unfit to live.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene three lines 53-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA character in the scene whom Prospero admires is","options":["Ferdinand","Gonzalo","Adrian","Francisco",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLook thou be true. Do not give dalliance<br>\r\nTook much the rein. The strongest oaths are straw<br>\r\nTo the fire i' the blood. Be more abstemious.<br>\r\nOr else, good night your vow!<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 51-54)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Alonso","Prospero","Gonzalo","Ferdinand",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLook thou be true. Do not give dalliance<br>\r\nTook much the rein. The strongest oaths are straw<br>\r\nTo the fire i' the blood. Be more abstemious.<br>\r\nOr else, good night your vow!<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 51-54)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Miranda","Antonio","Ferdinard","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLook thou be true. Do not give dalliance<br>\r\nTook much the rein. The strongest oaths are straw<br>\r\nTo the fire i' the blood. Be more abstemious.<br>\r\nOr else, good night your vow!<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 51-54)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device in lines 52 and 53 is","options":["personification","simile","metaphor","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLook thou be true. Do not give dalliance<br>\r\nTook much the rein. The strongest oaths are straw<br>\r\nTo the fire i' the blood. Be more abstemious.<br>\r\nOr else, good night your vow!<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 51-54)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnother character present in the scene is","options":["Caliban","Trinculo","Stephano","Miranda",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLook thou be true. Do not give dalliance<br>\r\nTook much the rein. The strongest oaths are straw<br>\r\nTo the fire i' the blood. Be more abstemious.<br>\r\nOr else, good night your vow!<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 51-54)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''oath'' referred to in the scene is","options":["Miranda shall not give in to Ferdinand","Ferdinand shall not have intimate contact with Miranda","Miranda shall vow to be faithful to Ferdinand","Ferdinand shall not tell his father about Miranda",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOh, a Cherubin<br>\r\nThou wast that did preserve me. Thou didst smile,<br>\r\nInfused with a fortitude from heaven,<br>\r\n<u>When I have decked the sea with drops full salt.<\/u><br>\r\nUnder my burthen groaned; which raised in me<br>\r\nAn undergoing stomach, to bear up<br>\r\nAgainst what should ensue<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene two lines 154-161)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Alonso","Gonzalo","Prospero","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOh, a Cherubin<br>\r\nThou wast that did preserve me. Thou didst smile,<br>\r\nInfused with a fortitude from heaven,<br>\r\n<u>When I have decked the sea with drops full salt.<\/u><br>\r\nUnder my burthen groaned; which raised in me<br>\r\nAn undergoing stomach, to bear up<br>\r\nAgainst what should ensue<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene two lines 154-161)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Ferdinand","Ariel","Caliban","Miranda",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOh, a Cherubin<br>\r\nThou wast that did preserve me. Thou didst smile,<br>\r\nInfused with a fortitude from heaven,<br>\r\n<u>When I have decked the sea with drops full salt.<\/u><br>\r\nUnder my burthen groaned; which raised in me<br>\r\nAn undergoing stomach, to bear up<br>\r\nAgainst what should ensue<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene two lines 154-161)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker sees the addressee as a\/an","options":["lover","saviour","burden","antagonist",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOh, a Cherubin<br>\r\nThou wast that did preserve me. Thou didst smile,<br>\r\nInfused with a fortitude from heaven,<br>\r\n<u>When I have decked the sea with drops full salt.<\/u><br>\r\nUnder my burthen groaned; which raised in me<br>\r\nAn undergoing stomach, to bear up<br>\r\nAgainst what should ensue<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene two lines 154-161)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''When I have decked the sea with drops full salt'' suggests","options":["dreaming","swimming","weeping","sleeping",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOh, a Cherubin<br>\r\nThou wast that did preserve me. Thou didst smile,<br>\r\nInfused with a fortitude from heaven,<br>\r\n<u>When I have decked the sea with drops full salt.<\/u><br>\r\nUnder my burthen groaned; which raised in me<br>\r\nAn undergoing stomach, to bear up<br>\r\nAgainst what should ensue<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene two lines 154-161)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSoon after this dialogue appears","options":["Ariel","Ferdinand","Gonzalo","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"A story which explains a natural phenomenon is","options":["legned","parable","myth","fiction",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A narrative in which characters and events are invented is","options":["fiction","epistolary","autobiography","biography",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Lines and stanzas are to poetry as action and dialogue are to","options":["music","prose","fiction","drama",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The performers in a play constitute the","options":["chorus","characters","audience","cast",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Use the following lines to answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTruth may bend but will never break:<br>\r\nIt will ever rise above falsehood as oil above water.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe alliteration in the first line","options":["draws attention to the key ideas","drwas attention to the rhythm of the line","makes the idea sound more true","makes the line sound more pleasant",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Use the following lines to answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTruth may bend but will never break:<br>\r\nIt will ever rise above falsehood as oil above water.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe simile in the second line","options":["expresses the idea more vividly","tells one that oil is heavier than water","makes a comparison between oil and water","expresses the idea in a complex manner",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The types of literary work are","options":["eras","episodes","genres","cantos",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The choice of words to create special effects is called","options":["fallacy","atmosphere","diction","mood",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A long narrative chronicling a family's heroic deeds is a\/an","options":["opera","epistle","fable","saga",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"_ in drama operates against a character who is unaware of a situation which is known to the audience","options":["Verbal irony","Dramatic irony","Satire","Parody",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The use of dialogue, creates a\/an _ effect","options":["hunorus","poetic","ironic","dramatic",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"One of the following is not a form of poetry","options":["Sonnet","Ode","Suspense","Lyric",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the following lines and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBut since, alas! frail beauty must decay,<br>\r\ncurled or uncurled, since looks will turn to gray;<br>\r\nsince painted or unpainted, all shall fade.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA literary device used in the first line is","options":["paradox","litotes","hyperbole","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the following lines and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBut since, alas! frail beauty must decay,<br>\r\ncurled or uncurled, since looks will turn to gray;<br>\r\nsince painted or unpainted, all shall fade.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe device used in the second and third lines is","options":["antithesis","pun","onomatopoeia","euphemism",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the following lines and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBut since, alas! frail beauty must decay,<br>\r\ncurled or uncurled, since looks will turn to gray;<br>\r\nsince painted or unpainted, all shall fade.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe use of the word 'since' illustrates","options":["alliteration","repetition","assonance","consonance",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Identify the odd item","options":["poetry","prose","melodrama","drama",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The clash of interest that originates from opposing forces in literature is","options":["climax","denouement","conflict","aside",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"A major character whose flaws combine with external forces that lead to his downfall is a","options":["flat character","round character","romantic hero","tragic hero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a drama?","options":["Burlesque","Resolution","Pantomime","Opera",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite<br>\r\nShall share me  this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\non; for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep;<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I cant you capture,<br>\r\nJust as the time I snore deep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Tis so strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one you is in my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is about a","options":["nightmare","dream","raid of bugs","raid of mosquitoes",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite<br>\r\nShall share me  this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\non; for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep;<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I cant you capture,<br>\r\nJust as the time I snore deep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Tis so strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one you is in my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is generally made up of","options":["rhyming couplets","heroic couplets","end-stopped lines","run-on lines",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite<br>\r\nShall share me  this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\non; for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep;<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I cant you capture,<br>\r\nJust as the time I snore deep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Tis so strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one you is in my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is a\/an","options":["monologue","dialogue","epilogue","prologue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite<br>\r\nShall share me  this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\non; for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep;<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I cant you capture,<br>\r\nJust as the time I snore deep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Tis so strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one you is in my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poet's mood is one of","options":["sarcasm","indifference","joy","despair",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite<br>\r\nShall share me  this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\non; for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep;<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I cant you capture,<br>\r\nJust as the time I snore deep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Tis so strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one you is in my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant attitude of the poet is one of","options":["amazement","pity","regret","nonchalance",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bright sun continued to smile. Andrew's face beamed with pleasure with every passing moment.<br>\r\nVery few of his contemporaries have so succeeded in reaching the top of the ladder. Andrew in particular<br>\r\nhad been an <u>orphan of storm<\/u>. His father's death during his third year in the secondary school coupled with the physical misfortune which he suffered when a stockfish machine severed his left middle finger, constituted a serious setback but Andrew did not despair.<br>\r\nThe courage to fail is very cheap; every fool can afford of fail. But it raises one above the herd of cowards and never-do-wells to be up and struggling. The reward of forbearance in the end is resounding success.<br>\r\nAnd so it was for was for Andrew ever since he finished his university education; it had been success galore. He had got a good job in one of the country's insurance companies. His pay was good, his prospects seemed bright. The <u>habitual Thomases<\/u> in his family found it very hard to believe. At forty he had a good car and had already built a house of his own.<u>The world was at his feet.<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Orphan of storm'' implies that Andrew","options":["had a good life","was orphaned at birth","had a difficult early life","was not afriad of storms",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bright sun continued to smile. Andrew's face beamed with pleasure with every passing moment.<br>\r\nVery few of his contemporaries have so succeeded in reaching the top of the ladder. Andrew in particular<br>\r\nhad been an <u>orphan of storm<\/u>. His father's death during his third year in the secondary school coupled with the physical misfortune which he suffered when a stockfish machine severed his left middle finger, constituted a serious setback but Andrew did not despair.<br>\r\nThe courage to fail is very cheap; every fool can afford of fail. But it raises one above the herd of cowards and never-do-wells to be up and struggling. The reward of forbearance in the end is resounding success.<br>\r\nAnd so it was for was for Andrew ever since he finished his university education; it had been success galore. He had got a good job in one of the country's insurance companies. His pay was good, his prospects seemed bright. The <u>habitual Thomases<\/u> in his family found it very hard to believe. At forty he had a good car and had already built a house of his own.<u>The world was at his feet.<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage is an example of a\/an","options":["autobiography","expository passage","descriptive passage","biography",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bright sun continued to smile. Andrew's face beamed with pleasure with every passing moment.<br>\r\nVery few of his contemporaries have so succeeded in reaching the top of the ladder. Andrew in particular<br>\r\nhad been an <u>orphan of storm<\/u>. His father's death during his third year in the secondary school coupled with the physical misfortune which he suffered when a stockfish machine severed his left middle finger, constituted a serious setback but Andrew did not despair.<br>\r\nThe courage to fail is very cheap; every fool can afford of fail. But it raises one above the herd of cowards and never-do-wells to be up and struggling. The reward of forbearance in the end is resounding success.<br>\r\nAnd so it was for was for Andrew ever since he finished his university education; it had been success galore. He had got a good job in one of the country's insurance companies. His pay was good, his prospects seemed bright. The <u>habitual Thomases<\/u> in his family found it very hard to believe. At forty he had a good car and had already built a house of his own.<u>The world was at his feet.<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the extract is one of","options":["love","admiration","hatred","resignation",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bright sun continued to smile. Andrew's face beamed with pleasure with every passing moment.<br>\r\nVery few of his contemporaries have so succeeded in reaching the top of the ladder. Andrew in particular<br>\r\nhad been an <u>orphan of storm<\/u>. His father's death during his third year in the secondary school coupled with the physical misfortune which he suffered when a stockfish machine severed his left middle finger, constituted a serious setback but Andrew did not despair.<br>\r\nThe courage to fail is very cheap; every fool can afford of fail. But it raises one above the herd of cowards and never-do-wells to be up and struggling. The reward of forbearance in the end is resounding success.<br>\r\nAnd so it was for was for Andrew ever since he finished his university education; it had been success galore. He had got a good job in one of the country's insurance companies. His pay was good, his prospects seemed bright. The <u>habitual Thomases<\/u> in his family found it very hard to believe. At forty he had a good car and had already built a house of his own.<u>The world was at his feet.<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The world was at his feet'' implies that Andrew","options":["was loving","was standing on the world","was arrogant","achieved result easily",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bright sun continued to smile. Andrew's face beamed with pleasure with every passing moment.<br>\r\nVery few of his contemporaries have so succeeded in reaching the top of the ladder. Andrew in particular<br>\r\nhad been an <u>orphan of storm<\/u>. His father's death during his third year in the secondary school coupled with the physical misfortune which he suffered when a stockfish machine severed his left middle finger, constituted a serious setback but Andrew did not despair.<br>\r\nThe courage to fail is very cheap; every fool can afford of fail. But it raises one above the herd of cowards and never-do-wells to be up and struggling. The reward of forbearance in the end is resounding success.<br>\r\nAnd so it was for was for Andrew ever since he finished his university education; it had been success galore. He had got a good job in one of the country's insurance companies. His pay was good, his prospects seemed bright. The <u>habitual Thomases<\/u> in his family found it very hard to believe. At forty he had a good car and had already built a house of his own.<u>The world was at his feet.<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\n''habitual Thomases'' is an example of an","options":["allegory","aphorism","allusion","apostrophe",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nP : Mark his condition, and the answer questions <br>\r\nIf this might be a brother.<br>\r\nQ: I should sun<br>\r\nTo think but nobly of my grandmother:<br>\r\nGood wombs have borne bad sons.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 116-120)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker P is","options":["Alonso","Antonio","Ferdinand","Proospero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nP : Mark his condition, and the answer questions <br>\r\nIf this might be a brother.<br>\r\nQ: I should sun<br>\r\nTo think but nobly of my grandmother:<br>\r\nGood wombs have borne bad sons.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 116-120)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Q is","options":["Miranda","Prospero","Sebastian","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nP : Mark his condition, and the answer questions <br>\r\nIf this might be a brother.<br>\r\nQ: I should sun<br>\r\nTo think but nobly of my grandmother:<br>\r\nGood wombs have borne bad sons.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 116-120)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dialogue recalls","options":["their exile to the island","the killing of the king","their love affairs","the grandmother's death",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nP : Mark his condition, and the answer questions <br>\r\nIf this might be a brother.<br>\r\nQ: I should sun<br>\r\nTo think but nobly of my grandmother:<br>\r\nGood wombs have borne bad sons.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 116-120)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker P wants his partner to","options":["pity his condition","fight his brother","justify his action","love him",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nP : Mark his condition, and the answer questions <br>\r\nIf this might be a brother.<br>\r\nQ: I should sun<br>\r\nTo think but nobly of my grandmother:<br>\r\nGood wombs have borne bad sons.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 116-120)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speakers are","options":["grandfather and son","lovers","father and daughter","friends",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt mine  unworthiness, that dare not offer<br>\r\nWhat I desire to give; and much less take<br>\r\nWhat I shall die to want. But this is trifling;<br>\r\nAnd all the more it seeks to hide itself,<br>\r\nThe bigger bulk it shows. Hence, bashful cunning!<br>\r\nAnd prompt me, plain and holy innocence!<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one lines 78 - 83)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Ferdinand","Stephano","Miranda","Prospero",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt mine  unworthiness, that dare not offer<br>\r\nWhat I desire to give; and much less take<br>\r\nWhat I shall die to want. But this is trifling;<br>\r\nAnd all the more it seeks to hide itself,<br>\r\nThe bigger bulk it shows. Hence, bashful cunning!<br>\r\nAnd prompt me, plain and holy innocence!<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one lines 78 - 83)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n After this speech, the character addressed","options":["sings","dances","kneels","weeps",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt mine  unworthiness, that dare not offer<br>\r\nWhat I desire to give; and much less take<br>\r\nWhat I shall die to want. But this is trifling;<br>\r\nAnd all the more it seeks to hide itself,<br>\r\nThe bigger bulk it shows. Hence, bashful cunning!<br>\r\nAnd prompt me, plain and holy innocence!<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one lines 78 - 83)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n The character addressed is","options":["prospoero","Ferdinand","Alonso","Juno",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt mine  unworthiness, that dare not offer<br>\r\nWhat I desire to give; and much less take<br>\r\nWhat I shall die to want. But this is trifling;<br>\r\nAnd all the more it seeks to hide itself,<br>\r\nThe bigger bulk it shows. Hence, bashful cunning!<br>\r\nAnd prompt me, plain and holy innocence!<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one lines 78 - 83)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n The speaker is expressing","options":["love","hatred","sorrow","regret",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt mine  unworthiness, that dare not offer<br>\r\nWhat I desire to give; and much less take<br>\r\nWhat I shall die to want. But this is trifling;<br>\r\nAnd all the more it seeks to hide itself,<br>\r\nThe bigger bulk it shows. Hence, bashful cunning!<br>\r\nAnd prompt me, plain and holy innocence!<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one lines 78 - 83)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character who secretly watches and listens is","options":["Trinculo","Stephano","Caliban","Prospero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speakers are","options":["arguing","in prison","dancing","in love",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker N","options":["is attracted to the temple","admires speaker M","dislikes the spirit in the house","dwells in the temple",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker M means to","options":["defend himself","kill himself","escape from prison","dine with N",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe other character present is","options":["Alonso","Caliban","Prospero","Antonio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker M is a","options":["prince","traitor","king","sailor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe other character present is","options":["Alonso","Caliban","Prospero","Antonio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract ans answer your question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nM : No, as I am a man.<br>\r\nN : There's nothing ill can dwell in such a temple\\If the ill spirit have so fair a house,<br>\r\nGood things will strive to dwell with it.<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two lines 459 - 462)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker M is a","options":["prince","traitor","king","sailor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Come on then; down, and swear.<br>\r\nY : I shall laugh myself to death at this puppy-headed monster<br>\r\nA most scurvy monster! I could find in my heart to beat him<br>\r\nX: Come, kiss.<br>\r\n(Act 11 scene two lines 139-143)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker X is","options":["Stephano","Ferdinand","Miranda","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Come on then; down, and swear.<br>\r\nY : I shall laugh myself to death at this puppy-headed monster<br>\r\nA most scurvy monster! I could find in my heart to beat him<br>\r\nX: Come, kiss.<br>\r\n(Act 11 scene two lines 139-143)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Y is","options":["prospero","Gonzalo","Trinculo","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Come on then; down, and swear.<br>\r\nY : I shall laugh myself to death at this puppy-headed monster<br>\r\nA most scurvy monster! I could find in my heart to beat him<br>\r\nX: Come, kiss.<br>\r\n(Act 11 scene two lines 139-143)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnother character present is","options":["Franciso","Sebastian","Adrian","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Come on then; down, and swear.<br>\r\nY : I shall laugh myself to death at this puppy-headed monster<br>\r\nA most scurvy monster! I could find in my heart to beat him<br>\r\nX: Come, kiss.<br>\r\n(Act 11 scene two lines 139-143)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Y is a","options":["monster","Musician","sea captain","jester",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Come on then; down, and swear.<br>\r\nY : I shall laugh myself to death at this puppy-headed monster<br>\r\nA most scurvy monster! I could find in my heart to beat him<br>\r\nX: Come, kiss.<br>\r\n(Act 11 scene two lines 139-143)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["in front of Prospero's cell","on a ship","on the seashore","another part of the island",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2012"},{"question":"The protagonist is the","options":["author","villain","hero","speaker",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"As chapter is to prose, so ...is to poetry","options":["couplet","stanza","line","chorus",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Verbal irony occurs when a speaker on stage","options":["says the opposite of what the speaker means","is misunderstood","tries to deceive the audience","is alone",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A humorous scene in a play intended to ease tension is","options":["climax","tragi-comedy","comedy","comic relief",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A dead metaphor is one that is","options":["overused and ineffective","exteneded in meaining","implied","mixed",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"''My bounty is as boundless as the sea, My love as deep'' is an example of","options":["hyperbole","litotes","euphemism","paradox",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Through the trees l'll hear a <u>single<\/u> ringing sound, a cowbell <u>jingle.<\/u> The underlined illustrate _ rhyme.","options":["end","decasyllabic","intenal","dimeter",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A literary work is a satire when it","options":["finds fault","humorously criticises to improve a situation","provokes laughter","teaches a lesson for social improvement",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Foreshadowing is a device used to","options":["prepare the reader for the direction a plot will take","introduce the plot","shed light on events through background information","recall the past",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A mountain of fufu was placed before the hungry visitors. The device used above is","options":["hyperbole","euphemism","alliteration","assonance",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A patter of beats to denote movement in poetry is","options":["refrain","rhyme","scansion","metre",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is an example of a\/an","options":["dirge","epigram","oxymoron","parody",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe tone of the extract is one of","options":["anger","pity","sarcasm","indifference",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA poem whose shape resembles the object described is a\/an","options":["emblematic poem","romantice poem","elegy","sonnet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ominscient narrator is","options":["all knowing","limited","realistic","always humorous",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhich of the following does not defin a character?","options":["the way the character appears","what the character says","what others say about the character","what the character does",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA bard is a","options":["novelist","playwright","poet","narrator",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA literary work that vividly portrays life can be described as","options":["realistic","romantic","idealistic","sarcastic",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhich of the following is not a type of play?","options":["Tragedy","Tragic flaw","Comedy","tragi-comedy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere lies our sovereign Lord the King<br>\r\nWhose word no man relies on <br>\r\nWho never said a foolish thing<br>\r\nAnd never did a wise one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe attitude of an author towards the subject matter is","options":["theme","tone","style","setting",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEach profession, intellectual or manual, deserves consideration, whether it requires painful physical effort or manual dexterity, wide knowledge or the patience of an ant. Ours, like that of the doctor, does not allow for any mistake. You don't joke with life, and life is both body and mind. To warp a soul is as much a sacrilege as murder. Teachers _ at kindergarten level, as at university level _ form a noble army accomplishing daily feats, never praised, never decorated. <u>An army forever on the move, forever vigilant: an army without drums, without gleaming uniforms.<\/u> This army, thwarting traps and snares, everywhere plants the flag of knowledge and morality.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe writer's mood is that of _","options":["excitement","optimism","indifference","frustration",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEach profession, intellectual or manual, deserves consideration, whether it requires painful physical effort or manual dexterity, wide knowledge or the patience of an ant. Ours, like that of the doctor, does not allow for any mistake. You don't joke with life, and life is both body and mind. To warp a soul is as much a sacrilege as murder. Teachers _ at kindergarten level, as at university level _ form a noble army accomplishing daily feats, never praised, never decorated. <u>An army forever on the move, forever vigilant: an army without drums, without gleaming uniforms.<\/u> This army, thwarting traps and snares, everywhere plants the flag of knowledge and morality.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe writer of the passage is a _","options":["doctor","soldier","teacher","student",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEach profession, intellectual or manual, deserves consideration, whether it requires painful physical effort or manual dexterity, wide knowledge or the patience of an ant. Ours, like that of the doctor, does not allow for any mistake. You don't joke with life, and life is both body and mind. To warp a soul is as much a sacrilege as murder. Teachers _ at kindergarten level, as at university level _ form a noble army accomplishing daily feats, never praised, never decorated. <u>An army forever on the move, forever vigilant: an army without drums, without gleaming uniforms.<\/u> This army, thwarting traps and snares, everywhere plants the flag of knowledge and morality.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant image in the passage is that of","options":["soldiery","medicine","religion","education",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEach profession, intellectual or manual, deserves consideration, whether it requires painful physical effort or manual dexterity, wide knowledge or the patience of an ant. Ours, like that of the doctor, does not allow for any mistake. You don't joke with life, and life is both body and mind. To warp a soul is as much a sacrilege as murder. Teachers _ at kindergarten level, as at university level _ form a noble army accomplishing daily feats, never praised, never decorated. <u>An army forever on the move, forever vigilant: an army without drums, without gleaming uniforms.<\/u> This army, thwarting traps and snares, everywhere plants the flag of knowledge and morality.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined illustrates","options":["antithesis","allusion","parallelism","parody",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nEach profession, intellectual or manual, deserves consideration, whether it requires painful physical effort or manual dexterity, wide knowledge or the patience of an ant. Ours, like that of the doctor, does not allow for any mistake. You don't joke with life, and life is both body and mind. To warp a soul is as much a sacrilege as murder. Teachers _ at kindergarten level, as at university level _ form a noble army accomplishing daily feats, never praised, never decorated. <u>An army forever on the move, forever vigilant: an army without drums, without gleaming uniforms.<\/u> This army, thwarting traps and snares, everywhere plants the flag of knowledge and morality.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The flag of knowledge and morality'' illustrates","options":["euphemism","litotes","metaphor","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere stood our ancestral home<br>\r\n<u>The crumbling wall marks the spot<\/u><br>\r\nHere a sheep was led to the slaughter<br>\r\nTo appease the goods and atone<br>\r\nFor fauilts which our destiny<br>\r\nHas blossomed into crimes<br>\r\nThere my cursed father once stood<br>\r\nAnd shouted to us, his children<br>\r\nTo come back from our play<br>\r\nTo our evening meal and sleep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the poem is","options":["hopeful","joyful","nostalgic","exciting",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere stood our ancestral home<br>\r\n<u>The crumbling wall marks the spot<\/u><br>\r\nHere a sheep was led to the slaughter<br>\r\nTo appease the goods and atone<br>\r\nFor fauilts which our destiny<br>\r\nHas blossomed into crimes<br>\r\nThere my cursed father once stood<br>\r\nAnd shouted to us, his children<br>\r\nTo come back from our play<br>\r\nTo our evening meal and sleep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe sheep was led to the slaughter","options":["to prepare their evening meal","because it was a troublesome sheep","because their father was a butcher","as a sacrifice to their gods",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere stood our ancestral home<br>\r\n<u>The crumbling wall marks the spot<\/u><br>\r\nHere a sheep was led to the slaughter<br>\r\nTo appease the goods and atone<br>\r\nFor fauilts which our destiny<br>\r\nHas blossomed into crimes<br>\r\nThere my cursed father once stood<br>\r\nAnd shouted to us, his children<br>\r\nTo come back from our play<br>\r\nTo our evening meal and sleep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''To appease the gods''...''implies","options":["seeking the favour of the gods","offering meals to the gods","accusing the gods for their misfortune","reciting incantations to the gods",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere stood our ancestral home<br>\r\n<u>The crumbling wall marks the spot<\/u><br>\r\nHere a sheep was led to the slaughter<br>\r\nTo appease the goods and atone<br>\r\nFor fauilts which our destiny<br>\r\nHas blossomed into crimes<br>\r\nThere my cursed father once stood<br>\r\nAnd shouted to us, his children<br>\r\nTo come back from our play<br>\r\nTo our evening meal and sleep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined means that","options":["they were living in a house with a high wall","their building is no longer where it used to be","the children had caused the wall to crumble","their father made them pull down the wall",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere stood our ancestral home<br>\r\n<u>The crumbling wall marks the spot<\/u><br>\r\nHere a sheep was led to the slaughter<br>\r\nTo appease the goods and atone<br>\r\nFor fauilts which our destiny<br>\r\nHas blossomed into crimes<br>\r\nThere my cursed father once stood<br>\r\nAnd shouted to us, his children<br>\r\nTo come back from our play<br>\r\nTo our evening meal and sleep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe image used in line six is taken from","options":["war","the moon","flowers","prison",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBe not afeard; the isle is full of noises,<br>\r\nSounds and sweet airs, that give delight, and hurt not.<br>\r\nSometimes a thousand twangling instruments<br>\r\nWill hum about mine ears; and sometime voices,<br>\r\nThat, if I then had waked after long sleep,<br>\r\nWill make me sleep again.And then, in dreaming,<br>\r\nThe clouds methought would open, and show riches<br>\r\nReady to drop upon me; that, when I waked,<br>\r\nI cried to dream again.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene two, lines 132-140)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Ferdinand","Gonzalo","Alonso","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBe not afeard; the isle is full of noises,<br>\r\nSounds and sweet airs, that give delight, and hurt not.<br>\r\nSometimes a thousand twangling instruments<br>\r\nWill hum about mine ears; and sometime voices,<br>\r\nThat, if I then had waked after long sleep,<br>\r\nWill make me sleep again.And then, in dreaming,<br>\r\nThe clouds methought would open, and show riches<br>\r\nReady to drop upon me; that, when I waked,<br>\r\nI cried to dream again.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene two, lines 132-140)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Horatio","Caliban","Stephano","Ferdinand",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBe not afeard; the isle is full of noises,<br>\r\nSounds and sweet airs, that give delight, and hurt not.<br>\r\nSometimes a thousand twangling instruments<br>\r\nWill hum about mine ears; and sometime voices,<br>\r\nThat, if I then had waked after long sleep,<br>\r\nWill make me sleep again.And then, in dreaming,<br>\r\nThe clouds methought would open, and show riches<br>\r\nReady to drop upon me; that, when I waked,<br>\r\nI cried to dream again.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene two, lines 132-140)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is a","options":["carnivore","savage","sailor","devourer",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBe not afeard; the isle is full of noises,<br>\r\nSounds and sweet airs, that give delight, and hurt not.<br>\r\nSometimes a thousand twangling instruments<br>\r\nWill hum about mine ears; and sometime voices,<br>\r\nThat, if I then had waked after long sleep,<br>\r\nWill make me sleep again.And then, in dreaming,<br>\r\nThe clouds methought would open, and show riches<br>\r\nReady to drop upon me; that, when I waked,<br>\r\nI cried to dream again.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene two, lines 132-140)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat are 'noises' in the extract?","options":["shouting","clapping","thunder","music",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Tempest<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBe not afeard; the isle is full of noises,<br>\r\nSounds and sweet airs, that give delight, and hurt not.<br>\r\nSometimes a thousand twangling instruments<br>\r\nWill hum about mine ears; and sometime voices,<br>\r\nThat, if I then had waked after long sleep,<br>\r\nWill make me sleep again.And then, in dreaming,<br>\r\nThe clouds methought would open, and show riches<br>\r\nReady to drop upon me; that, when I waked,<br>\r\nI cried to dream again.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene two, lines 132-140)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnother character presents is","options":["Trinculo","Ferdinand","Miranda","Prospero",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFaith, sir you need not fear. When we were boys,<br>\r\nWho would believe that there were mountaineers<br>\r\nDew-lapped like bulls, whose throats had hanging at'em<br>\r\nWallets of flesh? or that there were such men<br>\r\nWhose heads stood in their breasts? which now we find<br>\r\nEach putter-out of five for one will bring us<br>\r\nGood warrant of.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene Three, lines 44-49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Gonzalo","Stephano","Ferdinand","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFaith, sir you need not fear. When we were boys,<br>\r\nWho would believe that there were mountaineers<br>\r\nDew-lapped like bulls, whose throats had hanging at'em<br>\r\nWallets of flesh? or that there were such men<br>\r\nWhose heads stood in their breasts? which now we find<br>\r\nEach putter-out of five for one will bring us<br>\r\nGood warrant of.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene Three, lines 44-49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Sebastian","Ferdinand","Gonzalo","Alonso",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFaith, sir you need not fear. When we were boys,<br>\r\nWho would believe that there were mountaineers<br>\r\nDew-lapped like bulls, whose throats had hanging at'em<br>\r\nWallets of flesh? or that there were such men<br>\r\nWhose heads stood in their breasts? which now we find<br>\r\nEach putter-out of five for one will bring us<br>\r\nGood warrant of.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene Three, lines 44-49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn the extract a _ is laid before them","options":["problem","banquet","bed","gift",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFaith, sir you need not fear. When we were boys,<br>\r\nWho would believe that there were mountaineers<br>\r\nDew-lapped like bulls, whose throats had hanging at'em<br>\r\nWallets of flesh? or that there were such men<br>\r\nWhose heads stood in their breasts? which now we find<br>\r\nEach putter-out of five for one will bring us<br>\r\nGood warrant of.<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene Three, lines 44-49)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat happens to the spirits?","options":["they are killed","they stay on","they serve prospero","they disappear",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me, heavenly bow,<br>\r\nIf Venus or her son, as thou dost know,<br>\r\nDo now attend the queen? Since they did plot<br>\r\nThe means that dusky Dis my daughter got,<br>\r\nHer and her blind boy's scandalled company<br>\r\nI have forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 86-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Ferdinand","Miranda","Ceres","Iris",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me, heavenly bow,<br>\r\nIf Venus or her son, as thou dost know,<br>\r\nDo now attend the queen? Since they did plot<br>\r\nThe means that dusky Dis my daughter got,<br>\r\nHer and her blind boy's scandalled company<br>\r\nI have forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 86-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["Caliban","Iris","Ceres","Venus",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me, heavenly bow,<br>\r\nIf Venus or her son, as thou dost know,<br>\r\nDo now attend the queen? Since they did plot<br>\r\nThe means that dusky Dis my daughter got,<br>\r\nHer and her blind boy's scandalled company<br>\r\nI have forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 86-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe purpose of the gathering is to","options":["settle a dispute between prospero and his brother","punish Miranda for running away with Stephano","set Ariel free from his burden","celebrate the betrothal of Ferdinand and Miranda",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me, heavenly bow,<br>\r\nIf Venus or her son, as thou dost know,<br>\r\nDo now attend the queen? Since they did plot<br>\r\nThe means that dusky Dis my daughter got,<br>\r\nHer and her blind boy's scandalled company<br>\r\nI have forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 86-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is a","options":["sailor","king","spirit","man",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me, heavenly bow,<br>\r\nIf Venus or her son, as thou dost know,<br>\r\nDo now attend the queen? Since they did plot<br>\r\nThe means that dusky Dis my daughter got,<br>\r\nHer and her blind boy's scandalled company<br>\r\nI have forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act IV, scene one lines 86-91)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe 'heavenly bow' refers to","options":["Ceres","Iris","Ariel","Juno",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...The Duke of Milan<br>\r\nAnd his more braver daughter could control thee,<br>\r\nIf now't were fit to do't. At the first sight<br>\r\nThey have changed eyes. Delicate Ariet,<br>\r\nI''ll set thee free for this!<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two, lines 441-445)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Miranda","Ferdinand","Prospero","Caliban",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...The Duke of Milan<br>\r\nAnd his more braver daughter could control thee,<br>\r\nIf now't were fit to do't. At the first sight<br>\r\nThey have changed eyes. Delicate Ariet,<br>\r\nI''ll set thee free for this!<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two, lines 441-445)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Thee'' in line two refers to","options":["prospero","Sebastian","Ferdinand","Antonio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...The Duke of Milan<br>\r\nAnd his more braver daughter could control thee,<br>\r\nIf now't were fit to do't. At the first sight<br>\r\nThey have changed eyes. Delicate Ariet,<br>\r\nI''ll set thee free for this!<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two, lines 441-445)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat does ''they have changed eyes'' mean?","options":["they have exchanged looks at each other","they have met before","they have fallen in love","they have lost sight",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...The Duke of Milan<br>\r\nAnd his more braver daughter could control thee,<br>\r\nIf now't were fit to do't. At the first sight<br>\r\nThey have changed eyes. Delicate Ariet,<br>\r\nI''ll set thee free for this!<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two, lines 441-445)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''They'' in extract refers to","options":["prospero and Ariel","Prospero and Miranda","Ferdinand and Miranda","Ariel and Ferdinand",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...The Duke of Milan<br>\r\nAnd his more braver daughter could control thee,<br>\r\nIf now't were fit to do't. At the first sight<br>\r\nThey have changed eyes. Delicate Ariet,<br>\r\nI''ll set thee free for this!<br>\r\n(Act 1, scene two, lines 441-445)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed","options":["Prosepero","Miranda","Sebastian","himself",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"The above lines illustrate","options":["paradox","euphemism","personification","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"A short introductory speech delivered as part of a play is called","options":["a preamble","a prologue","an introduction","an epilogue",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The limerick","options":["is written to be sung","has a serious subject matter","is always light and humorous","uses lofty language",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Unrhymed iambic pentametre lines illustrate","options":["rhyme scheme","heroic couplet","blank verse","free verse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The major distinctive feature of drama is","options":["dialogue","setting","epilogue","plot",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The  recurrence of rhythmic pattern of stress in a poem is","options":["couplet","metre","consonance","strophe",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A poem written in praise of someone or something is","options":["a ballad","an epic","a sonnet","an ode",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''No longer mourn for me when I am dead<br>\r\nThen you shall hear the surly sullen bell<br>\r\nGive warning to the world that I am fled<br>\r\nfrom this vile world, with vilest worms to dwell''<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the poet is one of","options":["anger","humour","metancholy","gaiety",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''No longer mourn for me when I am dead<br>\r\nThen you shall hear the surly sullen bell<br>\r\nGive warning to the world that I am fled<br>\r\nfrom this vile world, with vilest worms to dwell''<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poet uses","options":["eye-rhyme","run-on-lines","end-stopped-lines","internal rhyme",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''No longer mourn for me when I am dead<br>\r\nThen you shall hear the surly sullen bell<br>\r\nGive warning to the world that I am fled<br>\r\nfrom this vile world, with vilest worms to dwell''<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyming pattern of the lines is","options":["abab","abba","aabb","aaab",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"''But at my back I always hear<br>\r\nTime's winged chariot hurrying near'' illustrates","options":["metaphor","apostrophe","oxymoron","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The central idea of a story or a poem is the","options":["title","climax","theme","conflict",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"An emphasis placed on a syllable in pronunciation is","options":["meter","rhythm","accent","rhyme",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The timing and location of a literary work is","options":["theme","plot","setting","atmosphere",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The elegy","options":["conforms to a fixed pattern of lines","is set in the countryside","has a mournful tone","celebrates heroic deeds",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"The major genres of Literature are","options":["fiction, non-fiction, drama","prose, farce, comedy","prose, drama, poetry","poetry, prose, fiction",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Pick the odd item out of the options listed","options":["the joys of the motherhood","sons and daughters","a man for all seasons","the last duty",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"''My bounty is as boundless as the sea<br>\r\nMy love as deep'' The above lines illustrate","options":["epigram","hyperbole","apostrophe","parody",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"''The strong gongs groaming as the guns born far'' illustrates","options":["metonymy","refrain","onomatopoeia","repetition",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Pick the odd item out of the options listed","options":["Euphemism","Oxymoron","Hyperbole","Rhythm",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"''Poetry gets bored of being alone. It wants to go outdoors to chew on the winds''<br>\r\nThe dominant figure of speech in the above lines is","options":["Paradox","pun","Parallelism","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat a morning!<br>\r\nThe sound of guns was everywhere<br>\r\nThe city was trapped,<br>\r\nI heave a mournful sigh-<br>\r\nRebels!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBoom Boom Boom!<br>\r\nThe heart pants at the sound of the blast<br>\r\nLord! When will all this end?<br>\r\nThis is the fourth day.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou say you are free<br>\r\nOh no, you are not<br>\r\nYou are trapped-<br>\r\nA prisoner in your own home.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe song is everywhere.<br>\r\nWhat next?<br>\r\nFood - water - a hiding place<br>\r\nFar from the sound of the gun.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is","options":["peace","war","love","death",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat a morning!<br>\r\nThe sound of guns was everywhere<br>\r\nThe city was trapped,<br>\r\nI heave a mournful sigh-<br>\r\nRebels!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBoom Boom Boom!<br>\r\nThe heart pants at the sound of the blast<br>\r\nLord! When will all this end?<br>\r\nThis is the fourth day.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou say you are free<br>\r\nOh no, you are not<br>\r\nYou are trapped-<br>\r\nA prisoner in your own home.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe song is everywhere.<br>\r\nWhat next?<br>\r\nFood - water - a hiding place<br>\r\nFar from the sound of the gun.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Boom Boom Boom'' is an example of","options":["symbols","onomatopoeia","metonymy","allusion",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat a morning!<br>\r\nThe sound of guns was everywhere<br>\r\nThe city was trapped,<br>\r\nI heave a mournful sigh-<br>\r\nRebels!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBoom Boom Boom!<br>\r\nThe heart pants at the sound of the blast<br>\r\nLord! When will all this end?<br>\r\nThis is the fourth day.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou say you are free<br>\r\nOh no, you are not<br>\r\nYou are trapped-<br>\r\nA prisoner in your own home.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe song is everywhere.<br>\r\nWhat next?<br>\r\nFood - water - a hiding place<br>\r\nFar from the sound of the gun.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe atmosphere of the poem implies","options":["danger and confusion","peace and reconciliation","happiness","hope",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat a morning!<br>\r\nThe sound of guns was everywhere<br>\r\nThe city was trapped,<br>\r\nI heave a mournful sigh-<br>\r\nRebels!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBoom Boom Boom!<br>\r\nThe heart pants at the sound of the blast<br>\r\nLord! When will all this end?<br>\r\nThis is the fourth day.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou say you are free<br>\r\nOh no, you are not<br>\r\nYou are trapped-<br>\r\nA prisoner in your own home.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe song is everywhere.<br>\r\nWhat next?<br>\r\nFood - water - a hiding place<br>\r\nFar from the sound of the gun.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe second stanza refers to","options":["the uncertainty of life","the pleasures of life","the meaning of life","the joys of life",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat a morning!<br>\r\nThe sound of guns was everywhere<br>\r\nThe city was trapped,<br>\r\nI heave a mournful sigh-<br>\r\nRebels!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBoom Boom Boom!<br>\r\nThe heart pants at the sound of the blast<br>\r\nLord! When will all this end?<br>\r\nThis is the fourth day.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYou say you are free<br>\r\nOh no, you are not<br>\r\nYou are trapped-<br>\r\nA prisoner in your own home.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe song is everywhere.<br>\r\nWhat next?<br>\r\nFood - water - a hiding place<br>\r\nFar from the sound of the gun.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The song is everywhere'' refers to","options":["freedom","anxiety","pleasure","satisfaction",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u><br>\r\n Also they are not at rest. For an hour they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged.<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then a policeman comes by on his rounds and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n ''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch, does not move at all, <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis style of writing is","options":["argumentative","epistolary","narrative","expository",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u><br>\r\n Also they are not at rest. For an hour they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged.<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then a policeman comes by on his rounds and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n ''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch, does not move at all, <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.... on the backs of the benches'' illustrates","options":["synecdoche","epithet","assonance","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u><br>\r\n Also they are not at rest. For an hour they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged.<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then a policeman comes by on his rounds and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n ''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch, does not move at all, <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage conveys a mood of","options":["defiance","hope","fear","despair",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u><br>\r\n Also they are not at rest. For an hour they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged.<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then a policeman comes by on his rounds and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n ''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch, does not move at all, <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'',....gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged....'' infers","options":["helplessness","slowness","sadness","tiredness",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u><br>\r\n Also they are not at rest. For an hour they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged.<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then a policeman comes by on his rounds and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n ''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch, does not move at all, <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''droning'' and ''have'' illustrate","options":["anecdote","epigram","allusion","epitaph",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYour leave and favour to return to France;<br>\r\nFrom whence though willingly I came to Denmark,<br>\r\nTo show my duty in your coronation.<br>\r\nYet now, I must confess, that duty done.<br>\r\nMy thoughts and wishes bend again toward France<br>\r\nAnd bow them to your gracious leave and pardon.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene two, Lines 51 -57)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Laertes","Polonius","Hamlet","Claudius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYour leave and favour to return to France;<br>\r\nFrom whence though willingly I came to Denmark,<br>\r\nTo show my duty in your coronation.<br>\r\nYet now, I must confess, that duty done.<br>\r\nMy thoughts and wishes bend again toward France<br>\r\nAnd bow them to your gracious leave and pardon.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene two, Lines 51 -57)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Hamlet","Claudius","Horatio","Marcellus",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYour leave and favour to return to France;<br>\r\nFrom whence though willingly I came to Denmark,<br>\r\nTo show my duty in your coronation.<br>\r\nYet now, I must confess, that duty done.<br>\r\nMy thoughts and wishes bend again toward France<br>\r\nAnd bow them to your gracious leave and pardon.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene two, Lines 51 -57)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Duty'' in the extract refers to","options":["job","fath","loyalty","task",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYour leave and favour to return to France;<br>\r\nFrom whence though willingly I came to Denmark,<br>\r\nTo show my duty in your coronation.<br>\r\nYet now, I must confess, that duty done.<br>\r\nMy thoughts and wishes bend again toward France<br>\r\nAnd bow them to your gracious leave and pardon.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene two, Lines 51 -57)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker intends to return to","options":["the seaside","the warfront","denmark","france",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nYour leave and favour to return to France;<br>\r\nFrom whence though willingly I came to Denmark,<br>\r\nTo show my duty in your coronation.<br>\r\nYet now, I must confess, that duty done.<br>\r\nMy thoughts and wishes bend again toward France<br>\r\nAnd bow them to your gracious leave and pardon.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene two, Lines 51 -57)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe other character present at the scene is","options":["Rosencrantz","Ophella","Guildenstern","Polonius",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDo not forget: this visitation<br>\r\nIs but to what thy almost blunted purpose<br>\r\nBut, look, amazement as thy mother sits:<br>\r\nO, step between her and her fighting soul:<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene four, lines 107 -110)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Claudius","Ghost","Gertrude","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDo not forget: this visitation<br>\r\nIs but to what thy almost blunted purpose<br>\r\nBut, look, amazement as thy mother sits:<br>\r\nO, step between her and her fighting soul:<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene four, lines 107 -110)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Polonius","Laertes","Ophelia","Hamlet",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDo not forget: this visitation<br>\r\nIs but to what thy almost blunted purpose<br>\r\nBut, look, amazement as thy mother sits:<br>\r\nO, step between her and her fighting soul:<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene four, lines 107 -110)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speech is made in the","options":["Queen' s closet","Queen's room","hall","palace",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDo not forget: this visitation<br>\r\nIs but to what thy almost blunted purpose<br>\r\nBut, look, amazement as thy mother sits:<br>\r\nO, step between her and her fighting soul:<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene four, lines 107 -110)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''blunted purpose''  implies","options":["inactivity","blindness","happiness","tiredness",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDo not forget: this visitation<br>\r\nIs but to what thy almost blunted purpose<br>\r\nBut, look, amazement as thy mother sits:<br>\r\nO, step between her and her fighting soul:<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene four, lines 107 -110)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''fighting soul'' implies","options":["clear conscience","hope","fear","guilty conscience",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nThat may be any good thing to be grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to thy country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily, foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death<br>\r\nSpeak of it:<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene one, lines 129-139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Hamlet","Mercellus","Horatio","Claudius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nThat may be any good thing to be grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to thy country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily, foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death<br>\r\nSpeak of it:<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene one, lines 129-139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["the queen","the ghost","Bernado","Reynaldo",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nThat may be any good thing to be grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to thy country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily, foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death<br>\r\nSpeak of it:<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene one, lines 129-139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speech is made after","options":["the killing of Polonius","Hamlet's arrival at the palace","the arrival of the players","the appearance of the ghost",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nThat may be any good thing to be grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to thy country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily, foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death<br>\r\nSpeak of it:<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene one, lines 129-139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker's mood is one of","options":["anger","reget","anxiety","disappointment",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nThat may be any good thing to be grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to thy country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily, foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death<br>\r\nSpeak of it:<br>\r\n(Act 1 scene one, lines 129-139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDuring the speech,","options":["the palace soldiers arrived","Hamlet attacked the speaker","the queen fainted","the cock crowed",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet.<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line, 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Gertrude","Ophelia","Claudius","Polonius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet.<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line, 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being discussed is","options":["Voltimand","Hamlet","Ophelia","Rosencrantz",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet.<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line, 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed are","options":["Marcellus and Horatio","Bernado and Francisco","Rosencrantz and Guildenstern","Marcellus and Francisco",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet.<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line, 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe response given to this speech indicates that the attempt was","options":["unsuccessful","successful","progressing","dangerous",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet.<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act 111, scene one line, 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe enquiry is about","options":["Hamlet","Laertes","Ophelia","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"A poem consisting of fourteen lines is","options":["a narrative","a sonnet","an ode","an elegy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The attitude of a writer towards the subject matter is the","options":["tone","plot","crisis","climax",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The pattern of end rhymes in a poem is called","options":["internal rhyme","rhyme scheme","rhythm","scansion",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The most exciting and tense part of a story is the","options":["epilogue","climax","prologue","exposition",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Lines of unrhymed poetry are known as","options":["blank verse","assonance","consonance","free verse",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A dramatic performance with only bodily movements and without words is","options":["a mime","an aside","a soliloquy","an opera",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"''Mathematics is my Achilles' heel'' is an example of","options":["litotes","metonymy","allusion","analogy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A short poem lamenting the death of someone is a","options":["lyric","sonnet","ballad","threnody",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"In a story, the adversary of the protagonist is the","options":["hero","heroine","antagonist","foil",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"''Tell me not, sweet, I  am unkind'' illustrates","options":["inversion","paradox","humour","mood",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The art of giving human attributes to non-human objects is","options":["personification","allegory","anecdote","allusion",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A long narrative poem which deals with heroic deeds is","options":["lyric","epic","ode","euphony",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A poem of four lines is called","options":["quatrain","sestet","sonnet","couplet",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A literary piece used to mock of ridicule a society or practice is called","options":["an allegory","a fable","a farce","a satire",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"The story of a person's life written by another is","options":["history","autobiography","biography","anthology",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A folktale is a","options":["novel","work of ficion","biography","novelette",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A poem written in an elaborate style to address or celebrate an object or event is called","options":["a ballad","an epic","a dirge","an ode",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI have to thank God I'm a woman,<br>\r\nFor in these ordered days a woman only<br>\r\nIs free to be very hungry, very lonely.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device in the above lines is","options":["burlesque","paradox","conflict","irony.",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI have to thank God I'm a woman,<br>\r\nFor in these ordered days a woman only<br>\r\nIs free to be very hungry, very lonely.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe tone of the poem is one of","options":["sorrow","sarcasm","happiness","anger",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Diversion through Larteh!'' This is the sign in the middle of the road. They have diverted the 24 - Kilometre Mamfe-Aburi-Adenta Road because of the major read works. The Mamfe-Larteh-Adenta diversion makes the journey twice as long. The longer route is the shorter.<br>\r\n\\The little jeep flashes past the deserted police checkpoint. The howling wind, like a stretching comb, stretches Kwyeiwa's hair in flapping furrows behind her as she stands clinging to metal support in the back of the open jeep, petrified. The jeep negotiates the hairpin bend below the overhang near Tamara's place at breakneck speed; now it is on the stretch to the Kodiable junction. <u>The little vehicle laps up the distance.<\/u> Presently the travellers arrive at the last crossroads. Kodiabe lies as the crow flies, Somanya to the left. The jeep turns right towards Accra.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nKyeiwa is","options":["relaxed","ecstatic","frightened","elated",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Diversion through Larteh!'' This is the sign in the middle of the road. They have diverted the 24 - Kilometre Mamfe-Aburi-Adenta Road because of the major read works. The Mamfe-Larteh-Adenta diversion makes the journey twice as long. The longer route is the shorter.<br>\r\n\\The little jeep flashes past the deserted police checkpoint. The howling wind, like a stretching comb, stretches Kwyeiwa's hair in flapping furrows behind her as she stands clinging to metal support in the back of the open jeep, petrified. The jeep negotiates the hairpin bend below the overhang near Tamara's place at breakneck speed; now it is on the stretch to the Kodiable junction. <u>The little vehicle laps up the distance<\/u>. Presently the travellers arrive at the last crossroads. Kodiabe lies as the crow flies, Somanya to the left. The jeep turns right towards Accra.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe narrative technique is","options":["third person","a soliloquy","first person","an aside",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Diversion through Larteh!'' This is the sign in the middle of the road. They have diverted the 24 - Kilometre Mamfe-Aburi-Adenta Road because of the major read works. The Mamfe-Larteh-Adenta diversion makes the journey twice as long. The longer route is the shorter.<br>\r\n\\The little jeep flashes past the deserted police checkpoint. The howling wind, like a stretching comb, stretches Kwyeiwa's hair in flapping furrows behind her as she stands clinging to metal support in the back of the open jeep, petrified. The jeep negotiates the hairpin bend below the overhang near Tamara's place at breakneck speed; now it is on the stretch to the Kodiable junction. <u>The little vehicle laps up the distance<\/u>. Presently the travellers arrive at the last crossroads. Kodiabe lies as the crow flies, Somanya to the left. The jeep turns right towards Accra.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage is","options":["expository","argumentative","narrative","analytical",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Diversion through Larteh!'' This is the sign in the middle of the road. They have diverted the 24 - Kilometre Mamfe-Aburi-Adenta Road because of the major read works. The Mamfe-Larteh-Adenta diversion makes the journey twice as long. The longer route is the shorter.<br>\r\n\\The little jeep flashes past the deserted police checkpoint. The howling wind, like a stretching comb, stretches Kwyeiwa's hair in flapping furrows behind her as she stands clinging to metal support in the back of the open jeep, petrified. The jeep negotiates the hairpin bend below the overhang near Tamara's place at breakneck speed; now it is on the stretch to the Kodiable junction. <u>The little vehicle laps up the distance<\/u>. Presently the travellers arrive at the last crossroads. Kodiabe lies as the crow flies, Somanya to the left. The jeep turns right towards Accra.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe atmosphere in the passage is one of","options":["love","fear","amger","joy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Diversion through Larteh!'' This is the sign in the middle of the road. They have diverted the 24 - Kilometre Mamfe-Aburi-Adenta Road because of the major read works. The Mamfe-Larteh-Adenta diversion makes the journey twice as long. The longer route is the shorter.<br>\r\n\\The little jeep flashes past the deserted police checkpoint. The howling wind, like a stretching comb, stretches Kwyeiwa's hair in flapping furrows behind her as she stands clinging to metal support in the back of the open jeep, petrified. The jeep negotiates the hairpin bend below the overhang near Tamara's place at breakneck speed; now it is on the stretch to the Kodiable junction. <u>The little vehicle laps up the distance<\/u>. Presently the travellers arrive at the last crossroads. Kodiabe lies as the crow flies, Somanya to the left. The jeep turns right towards Accra.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The little vehicle laps up the distance'' conveys the impression of","options":["leizure","pleasure","strength","speed",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn front of the gate, the guard stands with his rifle,<br>\r\nAbove, untidy clouds are carrying away the moon,<br>\r\nThe bedbugs are swarming around like army tanks on manoeuvers<br>\r\nWhile the mosquitoes form squadrons, attacking like fighter planes.<br>\r\nMy heart travels a thousand miles towards my native land.<br>\r\nMy dream interwines with sadness like a stein of a thousand threads,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInnocent, I have endured a whole year in prison<br>\r\nUsing my tears for ink, I turn my thoughts into verses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is about","options":["war","dirt","travelling","prison life",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn front of the gate, the guard stands with his rifle,<br>\r\nAbove, untidy clouds are carrying away the moon,<br>\r\nThe bedbugs are swarming around like army tanks on manoeuvers<br>\r\nWhile the mosquitoes form squadrons, attacking like fighter planes.<br>\r\nMy heart travels a thousand miles towards my native land.<br>\r\nMy dream interwines with sadness like a stein of a thousand threads,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInnocent, I have endured a whole year in prison<br>\r\nUsing my tears for ink, I turn my thoughts into verses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe imagery in the first four lines is predominantly","options":["agricultural","military","political","social",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"''....a thousand miles'' is an example of","options":["hyperbole","irony","antithesis","epigram",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn front of the gate, the guard stands with his rifle,<br>\r\nAbove, untidy clouds are carrying away the moon,<br>\r\nThe bedbugs are swarming around like army tanks on manoeuvers<br>\r\nWhile the mosquitoes form squadrons, attacking like fighter planes.<br>\r\nMy heart travels a thousand miles towards my native land.<br>\r\nMy dream interwines with sadness like a stein of a thousand threads,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInnocent, I have endured a whole year in prison<br>\r\nUsing my tears for ink, I turn my thoughts into verses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is written in","options":["blank verse","pentameter","free verse","trochee",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn front of the gate, the guard stands with his rifle,<br>\r\nAbove, untidy clouds are carrying away the moon,<br>\r\nThe bedbugs are swarming around like army tanks on manoeuvers<br>\r\nWhile the mosquitoes form squadrons, attacking like fighter planes.<br>\r\nMy heart travels a thousand miles towards my native land.<br>\r\nMy dream interwines with sadness like a stein of a thousand threads,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nInnocent, I have endured a whole year in prison<br>\r\nUsing my tears for ink, I turn my thoughts into verses.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe impression created of the persona is one of","options":["anger","competitiveness","reconciliation","resignation",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThink it no more:<br>\r\nFor nature, crescent, does not grow alone<br>\r\nIn <u>thews and bulk,<\/u> as this temple waxes,<br>\r\nThe inward service of the mind and soul<br>\r\nGrows wide withal. Perhaps he loves you now.<br>\r\nAnd now no soil or cantle doth besmirch<br>\r\nThe virtue of his will<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene 111, Lines 10 - 16)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Polonius","Reynaldo","Rosencrantz","Laertes",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThink it no more:<br>\r\nFor nature, crescent, does not grow alone<br>\r\nIn <u>thews and bulk,<\/u> as this temple waxes,<br>\r\nThe inward service of the mind and soul<br>\r\nGrows wide withal. Perhaps he loves you now.<br>\r\nAnd now no soil or cantle doth besmirch<br>\r\nThe virtue of his will<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene 111, Lines 10 - 16)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA character being addressed is","options":["Ophelia","Hamlet","Marcellus","Bernado",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThink it no more:<br>\r\nFor nature, crescent, does not grow alone<br>\r\nIn <u>thews and bulk,<\/u> as this temple waxes,<br>\r\nThe inward service of the mind and soul<br>\r\nGrows wide withal. Perhaps he loves you now.<br>\r\nAnd now no soil or cantle doth besmirch<br>\r\nThe virtue of his will<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene 111, Lines 10 - 16)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of discussion is","options":["Horatio","Hamlet","Marcellus","Bernado",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThink it no more:<br>\r\nFor nature, crescent, does not grow alone<br>\r\nIn <u>thews and bulk,<\/u> as this temple waxes,<br>\r\nThe inward service of the mind and soul<br>\r\nGrows wide withal. Perhaps he loves you now.<br>\r\nAnd now no soil or cantle doth besmirch<br>\r\nThe virtue of his will<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene 111, Lines 10 - 16)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["happy","confused","excited","anxious",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThink it no more:<br>\r\nFor nature, crescent, does not grow alone<br>\r\nIn <u>thews and bulk,<\/u> as this temple waxes,<br>\r\nThe inward service of the mind and soul<br>\r\nGrows wide withal. Perhaps he loves you now.<br>\r\nAnd now no soil or cantle doth besmirch<br>\r\nThe virtue of his will<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene 111, Lines 10 - 16)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Thews and bulk<\/u> means","options":["power","body and soul","strength and size","brain",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Tis gone will not answer.<br>\r\nY : How now....! You tremble and look pale;<br>\r\nIs not this something more than fantasy?<br>\r\nWhat think you on't?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZ : Before my God. I might not this believe<br>\r\nWithout the sensible and true avouch<br>\r\nOf mine own eyes.<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 52-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker X is","options":["Horatio","Marcellus","Hamlet","Laertes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Tis gone will not answer.<br>\r\nY : How now....! You tremble and look pale;<br>\r\nIs not this something more than fantasy?<br>\r\nWhat think you on't?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZ : Before my God. I might not this believe<br>\r\nWithout the sensible and true avouch<br>\r\nOf mine own eyes.<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 52-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["another part of the platform","a platform in front of the castle","the queen's palace","a room in the castle",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Tis gone will not answer.<br>\r\nY : How now....! You tremble and look pale;<br>\r\nIs not this something more than fantasy?<br>\r\nWhat think you on't?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZ : Before my God. I might not this believe<br>\r\nWithout the sensible and true avouch<br>\r\nOf mine own eyes.<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 52-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe atmosphere is","options":["frightening","peaceful","relaxed","bleak",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Tis gone will not answer.<br>\r\nY : How now....! You tremble and look pale;<br>\r\nIs not this something more than fantasy?<br>\r\nWhat think you on't?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZ : Before my God. I might not this believe<br>\r\nWithout the sensible and true avouch<br>\r\nOf mine own eyes.<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 52-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Tis gone and will not answer<\/u> refers to the","options":["gravedigger","ghost","servant","soldier",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : Tis gone will not answer.<br>\r\nY : How now....! You tremble and look pale;<br>\r\nIs not this something more than fantasy?<br>\r\nWhat think you on't?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nZ : Before my God. I might not this believe<br>\r\nWithout the sensible and true avouch<br>\r\nOf mine own eyes.<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 52-58)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Y is","options":["Bernado","Francisco","Polonius","Rosencrantz",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd for your part,..., I do wish<br>\r\nThat your good beauties be the happy cause<br>\r\nOf ...<u>wildness:<\/u> so shall I hope your virtues<br>\r\nWill bring him to his wonted way again,<br>\r\nTo both your honours,<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 37-42)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["the king","Laertes","the queen","polonius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd for your part,..., I do wish<br>\r\nThat your good beauties be the happy cause<br>\r\nOf ...<u>wildness:<\/u> so shall I hope your virtues<br>\r\nWill bring him to his wonted way again,<br>\r\nTo both your honours,<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 37-42)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAfter this speech, the speaker","options":["exits","dies","wakes up","sleeps off",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd for your part,..., I do wish<br>\r\nThat your good beauties be the happy cause<br>\r\nOf ...<u>wildness:<\/u> so shall I hope your virtues<br>\r\nWill bring him to his wonted way again,<br>\r\nTo both your honours,<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 37-42)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Laertes","Hamlet","Polonius","Ophelia",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd for your part,..., I do wish<br>\r\nThat your good beauties be the happy cause<br>\r\nOf ...<u>wildness:<\/u> so shall I hope your virtues<br>\r\nWill bring him to his wonted way again,<br>\r\nTo both your honours,<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 37-42)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnother character present on the scene is","options":["Rosencrantz","Guildenstern","Polonius","Hamlet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd for your part,..., I do wish<br>\r\nThat your good beauties be the happy cause<br>\r\nOf ...<u>wildness:<\/u> so shall I hope your virtues<br>\r\nWill bring him to his wonted way again,<br>\r\nTo both your honours,<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 37-42)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe <u>wildness<\/u> referred to can also be called","options":["love","madness","happiness","death",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nH : Where is this <u>sight?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nl : What is it ye would see?<br>\r\nIf aught of woe or wonder, cease your search<br>\r\n(Act Five, Scene 11,lines 348-350)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker H is","options":["Fortunbras","Horatio","Osric","Ambassador",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nH : Where is this <u>sight?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nl : What is it ye would see?<br>\r\nIf aught of woe or wonder, cease your search<br>\r\n(Act Five, Scene 11,lines 348-350)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker l is","options":["Horatio","Claudius","Hamlet","Osric",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nH : Where is this <u>sight?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nl : What is it ye would see?<br>\r\nIf aught of woe or wonder, cease your search<br>\r\n(Act Five, Scene 11,lines 348-350)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>sight<\/u> refers to","options":["players and drummers","soldiers from England","incest committed","dead bodies",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nH : Where is this <u>sight?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nl : What is it ye would see?<br>\r\nIf aught of woe or wonder, cease your search<br>\r\n(Act Five, Scene 11,lines 348-350)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nShortly before this speech, _ died","options":["the king","the queen","Hamlet","Polonius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nH : Where is this <u>sight?<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nl : What is it ye would see?<br>\r\nIf aught of woe or wonder, cease your search<br>\r\n(Act Five, Scene 11,lines 348-350)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOther characters who died earlier were","options":["the queen and ambassador","Hamlet and Osric","Ophelia and Horatio","Laertes and the King",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"A literary work in which action and characters represent ideas is","options":["an allusion","an epigram","an allegory","an innuendo",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"''Peter's pretty partner paid the bills'' is an example of","options":["alliteration","rhyme","satire","digression",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A stanza of four lines in poetry is","options":["a quartrain","a sestet","an actave","an elegy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"''O happy torment'' is an example of","options":["oxymoron","synecdoche","innuendo","simile",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"recurring dominant idea in a work of a art is called","options":["setting","conflict","plot","motif",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A question which does not require an answer is","options":["discourse","rhetorical","ironic","flashback",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A literary work written in from of a letter is","options":["creative","romantic","tautological","epistolary",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"''The lawyer addressed the bench'' illustrates","options":["metonymy","alliteration","simile","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The concluding part of a play where the conflict is resolved is the","options":["resolution","enjambment","denouement","climax",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A character whose flaws combined with external force lead to his suffering is a","options":["heroine","tragic-hero","hero","protagonist",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Pick the odd item out of the underlisted","options":["ode","elegy","sonnet","simile",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"''Pregnant clouds'' is an example of","options":["eliche","litotes","metaphor","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A writer's choice of words is his","options":["diction","mood","tone","setting",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"The art of creating fictional personages constitutes","options":["point of view","characterization","narrative tecnique","symbolism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A deliberate use of exaggeration for the purpose of humour\/emphasis is","options":["metaphor","irony","simile","hyperbole",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Drama is meant to","options":["teach manners only","criticize","eduate and entertain","be read and acted only",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A piece of writing which teaches morals is","options":["serious","didactic","playful","analytical",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A poem of fourteen lines is","options":["an elegy","a dirge","a sonnet","an ode",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Shakespeare's poetry consists mainly of","options":["quartrain","heroic verse","blank verse","couplet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A piece of writing or speech at the beginning of a work of art is the","options":["prologue","dialogue","monologue","epilogue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the onset of the rain<br>\r\nThe drought-stricken land<br>\r\nSuck up the wetness<br>\r\nAnd the gates to the field<br>\r\nAre flung widely open.<br>\r\nIt is the signal for planting!<br>\r\nIt is time for joyous toiling!<br>\r\nAt various times of day<br>\r\nThe hard and erect hoe<br>\r\nWould thrust and dig deep<br>\r\nInto the receiving wet soil.<br>\r\nSeeds on different quantities<br>\r\nSeeds of varying potency<br>\r\nAre broadcasted in layers<br>\r\nInto the womb of the earth<br>\r\nWith time and much labour<br>\r\nThe seed now transformed<br>\r\nBlossoms and grows into new life!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject matter of the extract is","options":["harvesting","rain","time","farming",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the onset of the rain<br>\r\nThe drought-stricken land<br>\r\nSuck up the wetness<br>\r\nAnd the gates to the field<br>\r\nAre flung widely open.<br>\r\nIt is the signal for planting!<br>\r\nIt is time for joyous toiling!<br>\r\nAt various times of day<br>\r\nThe hard and erect hoe<br>\r\nWould thrust and dig deep<br>\r\nInto the receiving wet soil.<br>\r\nSeeds on different quantities<br>\r\nSeeds of varying potency<br>\r\nAre broadcasted in layers<br>\r\nInto the womb of the earth<br>\r\nWith time and much labour<br>\r\nThe seed now transformed<br>\r\nBlossoms and grows into new life!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used in the extract is","options":["metaphor","paradox","symbolism","simile",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the onset of the rain<br>\r\nThe drought-stricken land<br>\r\nSuck up the wetness<br>\r\nAnd the gates to the field<br>\r\nAre flung widely open.<br>\r\nIt is the signal for planting!<br>\r\nIt is time for joyous toiling!<br>\r\nAt various times of day<br>\r\nThe hard and erect hoe<br>\r\nWould thrust and dig deep<br>\r\nInto the receiving wet soil.<br>\r\nSeeds on different quantities<br>\r\nSeeds of varying potency<br>\r\nAre broadcasted in layers<br>\r\nInto the womb of the earth<br>\r\nWith time and much labour<br>\r\nThe seed now transformed<br>\r\nBlossoms and grows into new life!<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The hard and erect hoe'' connotes","options":["uprooting of weeds","the sowing of seeds","digging of the soil","farming implement",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the onset of the rain<br>\r\nThe drought-stricken land<br>\r\nSuck up the wetness<br>\r\nAnd the gates to the field<br>\r\nAre flung widely open.<br>\r\nIt is the signal for planting!<br>\r\nIt is time for joyous toiling!<br>\r\nAt various times of day<br>\r\nThe hard and erect hoe<br>\r\nWould thrust and dig deep<br>\r\nInto the receiving wet soil.<br>\r\nSeeds on different quantities<br>\r\nSeeds of varying potency<br>\r\nAre broadcasted in layers<br>\r\nInto the womb of the earth<br>\r\nWith time and much labour<br>\r\nThe seed now transformed<br>\r\nBlossoms and grows into new life!<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Joyous toiling'' is an example of","options":["onomatopeia","oxymoron","irony","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAt the onset of the rain<br>\r\nThe drought-stricken land<br>\r\nSuck up the wetness<br>\r\nAnd the gates to the field<br>\r\nAre flung widely open.<br>\r\nIt is the signal for planting!<br>\r\nIt is time for joyous toiling!<br>\r\nAt various times of day<br>\r\nThe hard and erect hoe<br>\r\nWould thrust and dig deep<br>\r\nInto the receiving wet soil.<br>\r\nSeeds on different quantities<br>\r\nSeeds of varying potency<br>\r\nAre broadcasted in layers<br>\r\nInto the womb of the earth<br>\r\nWith time and much labour<br>\r\nThe seed now transformed<br>\r\nBlossoms and grows into new life!<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe last line of the extract suggested the","options":["growth of a seed","birth of a child","harvesting of fruits","flourishing of flowers",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph wormed his way<\/u> though the thicket towards the forest, keeping as far as possible beneath the smoke. Presently, he saw an open space and the green leaves of the edge of the thicket . A smallish savage was standing between him and the rest of the forest, a savage striped red and white, and carrying a spear. He was coughing, and smearing the paint about his eyes with the back of his hand as he tried to see through the increasing smoke.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph launched himself like a cat:<\/u> stabbed, snarling, with the spear, and the savage doubled up. There was a shout from beyond the thicket and then Ralph was running with the swiftness of fear through the undergrowth. He came to a pig-run, followed it for perhaps a hundred yards and then swerved off. Behind him the ululation swept across the island once more and a single voice shouted three times. He guessed that was the signal to advance and sped away again till his chest was like fire.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThen he flung himself down under a bush and waited for a moment till his breathing steadied. He passed his tongue tentatively over his teeth and lips and heard far off the ululation of the pursuers.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage is","options":["narrative","expository","descriptive","argumentative",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph wormed his way<\/u> though the thicket towards the forest, keeping as far as possible beneath the smoke. Presently, he saw an open space and the green leaves of the edge of the thicket . A smallish savage was standing between him and the rest of the forest, a savage striped red and white, and carrying a spear. He was coughing, and smearing the paint about his eyes with the back of his hand as he tried to see through the increasing smoke.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph launched himself like a cat:<\/u> stabbed, snarling, with the spear, and the savage doubled up. There was a shout from beyond the thicket and then Ralph was running with the swiftness of fear through the undergrowth. He came to a pig-run, followed it for perhaps a hundred yards and then swerved off. Behind him the ululation swept across the island once more and a single voice shouted three times. He guessed that was the signal to advance and sped away again till his chest was like fire.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThen he flung himself down under a bush and waited for a moment till his breathing steadied. He passed his tongue tentatively over his teeth and lips and heard far off the ululation of the pursuers.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Ralph wormed his way'' is an example of","options":["irony","apostrophe","metaphor","allusion",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph wormed his way<\/u> though the thicket towards the forest, keeping as far as possible beneath the smoke. Presently, he saw an open space and the green leaves of the edge of the thicket . A smallish savage was standing between him and the rest of the forest, a savage striped red and white, and carrying a spear. He was coughing, and smearing the paint about his eyes with the back of his hand as he tried to see through the increasing smoke.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph launched himself like a cat:<\/u> stabbed, snarling, with the spear, and the savage doubled up. There was a shout from beyond the thicket and then Ralph was running with the swiftness of fear through the undergrowth. He came to a pig-run, followed it for perhaps a hundred yards and then swerved off. Behind him the ululation swept across the island once more and a single voice shouted three times. He guessed that was the signal to advance and sped away again till his chest was like fire.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThen he flung himself down under a bush and waited for a moment till his breathing steadied. He passed his tongue tentatively over his teeth and lips and heard far off the ululation of the pursuers.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in ''Ralph launched himself like a cat'' is","options":["assonance","simile","contrast","personification",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph wormed his way<\/u> though the thicket towards the forest, keeping as far as possible beneath the smoke. Presently, he saw an open space and the green leaves of the edge of the thicket . A smallish savage was standing between him and the rest of the forest, a savage striped red and white, and carrying a spear. He was coughing, and smearing the paint about his eyes with the back of his hand as he tried to see through the increasing smoke.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<u>Ralph launched himself like a cat:<\/u> stabbed, snarling, with the spear, and the savage doubled up. There was a shout from beyond the thicket and then Ralph was running with the swiftness of fear through the undergrowth. He came to a pig-run, followed it for perhaps a hundred yards and then swerved off. Behind him the ululation swept across the island once more and a single voice shouted three times. He guessed that was the signal to advance and sped away again till his chest was like fire.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThen he flung himself down under a bush and waited for a moment till his breathing steadied. He passed his tongue tentatively over his teeth and lips and heard far off the ululation of the pursuers.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe writer's diction portrays","options":["repetition","irony","tension","humour",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the  question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIt is here,......thou art slain;<br>\r\nNo medicine in the world can do thee good,<br>\r\nIn thee there is not half an hour of life;<br>\r\nThe treacherous instrument is in thy hand,<br>\r\nUnbated and envenom d: the foul practice<br>\r\nHath turn'd itself on me; lo; here I lie,<br>\r\n(Act 5, Scene Two, Lines 298-303)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Fortinbras","Guildenstern","Laertes","Hamlet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the  question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIt is here,......thou art slain;<br>\r\nNo medicine in the world can do thee good,<br>\r\nIn thee there is not half an hour of life;<br>\r\nThe treacherous instrument is in thy hand,<br>\r\nUnbated and envenom d: the foul practice<br>\r\nHath turn'd itself on me; lo; here I lie,<br>\r\n(Act 5, Scene Two, Lines 298-303)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe queen has just","options":["left the scene","died","run away","arrived",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the  question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIt is here,......thou art slain;<br>\r\nNo medicine in the world can do thee good,<br>\r\nIn thee there is not half an hour of life;<br>\r\nThe treacherous instrument is in thy hand,<br>\r\nUnbated and envenom d: the foul practice<br>\r\nHath turn'd itself on me; lo; here I lie,<br>\r\n(Act 5, Scene Two, Lines 298-303)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Hamlet","the queen","the king","fortinbras",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the  question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIt is here,......thou art slain;<br>\r\nNo medicine in the world can do thee good,<br>\r\nIn thee there is not half an hour of life;<br>\r\nThe treacherous instrument is in thy hand,<br>\r\nUnbated and envenom d: the foul practice<br>\r\nHath turn'd itself on me; lo; here I lie,<br>\r\n(Act 5, Scene Two, Lines 298-303)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe addresses later","options":["kills himself","sleeps off","runs away","arrived",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract and answer the  question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIt is here,......thou art slain;<br>\r\nNo medicine in the world can do thee good,<br>\r\nIn thee there is not half an hour of life;<br>\r\nThe treacherous instrument is in thy hand,<br>\r\nUnbated and envenom d: the foul practice<br>\r\nHath turn'd itself on me; lo; here I lie,<br>\r\n(Act 5, Scene Two, Lines 298-303)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["a hall in the castle","the battlefield","a platform in front of the castle","the queen's room",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThrift, thrift,....! the funeral baked meats<br>\r\nDid coldly furnish forth the marriage tables.<br>\r\nWould I had seen that day,.....!<br>\r\nMy father! _ Me thinks I see my father.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 180-184)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Polonius","the King","Hamlet","the queen",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThrift, thrift,....! the funeral baked meats<br>\r\nDid coldly furnish forth the marriage tables.<br>\r\nWould I had seen that day,.....!<br>\r\nMy father! _ Me thinks I see my father.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 180-184)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Laertes","Polonius","Horatio","the King",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThrift, thrift,....! the funeral baked meats<br>\r\nDid coldly furnish forth the marriage tables.<br>\r\nWould I had seen that day,.....!<br>\r\nMy father! _ Me thinks I see my father.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 180-184)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The primrose path of dalliance'' means","options":["a religious life","a reckless life","the way to heaven","the way to hell",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThrift, thrift,....! the funeral baked meats<br>\r\nDid coldly furnish forth the marriage tables.<br>\r\nWould I had seen that day,.....!<br>\r\nMy father! _ Me thinks I see my father.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 180-184)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe other character who comes on the scene after this is","options":["the queen","Horatio","Polonius","the king",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThrift, thrift,....! the funeral baked meats<br>\r\nDid coldly furnish forth the marriage tables.<br>\r\nWould I had seen that day,.....!<br>\r\nMy father! _ Me thinks I see my father.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene Two, Lines 180-184)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["a room in Polonius house","a room in the castle","the queen's room","the king's room.",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI prithee, when thou seest that act afoot,<br>\r\nEven with the very comment of thy soul<br>\r\nObserve mine uncle: if his occulted guilt<br>\r\nDo not itself unkennel in one speech,<br>\r\nIt is a dammed ghost that we have seen.....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene  Two, Lines 73-77)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Hamlet","Claudius","the King","the Queen",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI prithee, when thou seest that act afoot,<br>\r\nEven with the very comment of thy soul<br>\r\nObserve mine uncle: if his occulted guilt<br>\r\nDo not itself unkennel in one speech,<br>\r\nIt is a dammed ghost that we have seen.....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene  Two, Lines 73-77)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Gertrude","Ophelia","Horatio","Claudius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI prithee, when thou seest that act afoot,<br>\r\nEven with the very comment of thy soul<br>\r\nObserve mine uncle: if his occulted guilt<br>\r\nDo not itself unkennel in one speech,<br>\r\nIt is a dammed ghost that we have seen.....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene  Two, Lines 73-77)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''uncle'' being referred to is","options":["Laertes","Claudius","Guildenstern","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI prithee, when thou seest that act afoot,<br>\r\nEven with the very comment of thy soul<br>\r\nObserve mine uncle: if his occulted guilt<br>\r\nDo not itself unkennel in one speech,<br>\r\nIt is a dammed ghost that we have seen.....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene  Two, Lines 73-77)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''occulted guilt'' here means","options":["wizardry","love","witchcraft","conscience",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI prithee, when thou seest that act afoot,<br>\r\nEven with the very comment of thy soul<br>\r\nObserve mine uncle: if his occulted guilt<br>\r\nDo not itself unkennel in one speech,<br>\r\nIt is a dammed ghost that we have seen.....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene  Two, Lines 73-77)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe scene after this consists of the","options":["closet scene","dumb show","graveyard scene","ghost scene",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"A bitter remark intended to wound the feelings is","options":["a satire","an allusion","a sarcasm","an ambiguity",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"''She waited for him for a thousand years'' illustrates","options":["euphemism","hyperbole","assonance","ellipsis",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A literary device which expresses meaning in its direct opposite is","options":["metaphor","paradox","parody","irony",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"''They also serve who only stand and wait'' illustrates","options":["an epigram","a synecdoche","a simile","an antithesis",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Pick the odd item out of the options listed below","options":["Verse","Stanza","Rhythm","Dialogue",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"In drama, ' denouement' is the same as","options":["resolution","climax","anti-climax","conflict",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT true of balled?","options":["They were originally sung","They are mostly part of oral tradition","Tehy tell a popular story","They are written in iambic metre",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy heart leaps up when I behold<br>\r\nA rainbow in the sky:<br>\r\nSo was it when my life began,<br>\r\nSo is it now that I am a man,<br>\r\nSo be it when I shall grow<br>\r\nThe child is father of the man<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the poem is that of","options":["sorrow","elation","anxiety","sarcasm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy heart leaps up when I behold<br>\r\nA rainbow in the sky:<br>\r\nSo was it when my life began,<br>\r\nSo is it now that I am a man,<br>\r\nSo be it when I shall grow<br>\r\nThe child is father of the man<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme of the poem is","options":["ab cc ac","ac bc ca","ab ca cc","ab ac bc",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy heart leaps up when I behold<br>\r\nA rainbow in the sky:<br>\r\nSo was it when my life began,<br>\r\nSo is it now that I am a man,<br>\r\nSo be it when I shall grow<br>\r\nThe child is father of the man<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of the extract is","options":["childishness","the adverse effects of the rainbow on man","the unchanging cycle of nature","the adverse effects of old age",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy heart leaps up when I behold<br>\r\nA rainbow in the sky:<br>\r\nSo was it when my life began,<br>\r\nSo is it now that I am a man,<br>\r\nSo be it when I shall grow<br>\r\nThe child is father of the man<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in line 1 is","options":["simile","alliteration","litotes","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy heart leaps up when I behold<br>\r\nA rainbow in the sky:<br>\r\nSo was it when my life began,<br>\r\nSo is it now that I am a man,<br>\r\nSo be it when I shall grow<br>\r\nThe child is father of the man<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in line 6 is an example of","options":["synecdoche","irony","paradox","hyperbole",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"''Forty hands descended on the devilish head'' illustrates","options":["epigram","synecdoche","metonymy","allegory",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Pick the odd item out of the options listed below:","options":["sonnet","epic","allusion","ode",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A deliberate violation of the rules of verification constitutes","options":["imperfect rhyme","poetic license","verbal irony","comic relief",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A praise poem is","options":["a dirge","an epic","a ballad","an ode",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Lines of regular recurrence in a poem constitutes","options":["an alliteration","a refrain","an assonance","a theme",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"An individual who acts, appears or is referred to as playing a part in a literary work is a","options":["villain","character","clown","narrator",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"A regular group of lines in poetry constitutes","options":["stanza","rhythm","verse","metre",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"''A black beautiful brilliant bride'' is an example of","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","pun",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\nBent-double, like old beggars under sacks,<br>\r\nKnock-kneed, coughing like hags, we curse through <u>sludge<\/u><br>\r\nTill on the haunting flares we turned our backs,<br>\r\nAnd towards our distant rest began to trudge,<br>\r\nMen marched asleep, many had lost their boots,<br>\r\nBut limped on, blood-shed. All went lame, all blind;<br>\r\n<u>Drunk with fatigue;<\/u> even deaf to the hoots<br>\r\nOf gas-shells dropping softy behind.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract conveys a mood of","options":["dejection","desperation","resentment","resignation",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\nBent-double, like old beggars under sacks,<br>\r\nKnock-kneed, coughing like hags, we curse through <u>sludge<\/u><br>\r\nTill on the haunting flares we turned our backs,<br>\r\nAnd towards our distant rest began to trudge,<br>\r\nMen marched asleep, many had lost their boots,<br>\r\nBut limped on, blood-shed. All went lame, all blind;<br>\r\n<u>Drunk with fatigue;<\/u> even deaf to the hoots<br>\r\nOf gas-shells dropping softy behind.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant figure of speech in the first stanza is","options":["hyperbole","simile","euphemism","pun",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\nBent-double, like old beggars under sacks,<br>\r\nKnock-kneed, coughing like hags, we curse through <u>sludge<\/u><br>\r\nTill on the haunting flares we turned our backs,<br>\r\nAnd towards our distant rest began to trudge,<br>\r\nMen marched asleep, many had lost their boots,<br>\r\nBut limped on, blood-shed. All went lame, all blind;<br>\r\n<u>Drunk with fatigue;<\/u> even deaf to the hoots<br>\r\nOf gas-shells dropping softy behind.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression Drunk with fatigue illustrates","options":["metaphor","synecdoche","litotes","irony",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\nBent-double, like old beggars under sacks,<br>\r\nKnock-kneed, coughing like hags, we curse through <u>sludge<\/u><br>\r\nTill on the haunting flares we turned our backs,<br>\r\nAnd towards our distant rest began to trudge,<br>\r\nMen marched asleep, many had lost their boots,<br>\r\nBut limped on, blood-shed. All went lame, all blind;<br>\r\n<u>Drunk with fatigue;<\/u> even deaf to the hoots<br>\r\nOf gas-shells dropping softy behind.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme of the first stanza is","options":["aabb","abab","abcd","abba",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"UNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the poem and answer the question<br>\r\nBent-double, like old beggars under sacks,<br>\r\nKnock-kneed, coughing like hags, we curse through <u>sludge<\/u><br>\r\nTill on the haunting flares we turned our backs,<br>\r\nAnd towards our distant rest began to trudge,<br>\r\nMen marched asleep, many had lost their boots,<br>\r\nBut limped on, blood-shed. All went lame, all blind;<br>\r\n<u>Drunk with fatigue;<\/u> even deaf to the hoots<br>\r\nOf gas-shells dropping softy behind.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSludge in the extract means","options":["water","fire","snow","mud",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nworld have been Heathcliff's miseries, and I watched and felt each from the beginning.My great thought in living is himself. <u>If all else perished, and he remained,<\/u> I should still continue to be. And if all else remained, and he were <u>annihilated,<\/u> the universe would be turned to a mighty stranger _ is should not seem a part of it. My love for Linton is like the foliage in the woods; time will change it, I'm well aware, as winter changes the trees. <u>My love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath<\/u> _ as source of little visible delight, but necessary. Nelly, I am Heathcliff!. He's always, always in my mind _ not as a pleasure to myself, but as my own being....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker's love for Heathcliff is","options":["platonic","indestructible","ephemeral","universal",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nworld have been Heathcliff's miseries, and I watched and felt each from the beginning.My great thought in living is himself. <u>If all else perished, and he remained,<\/u> I should still continue to be. And if all else remained, and he were <u>annihilated,<\/u> the universe would be turned to a mighty stranger _ is should not seem a part of it. My love for Linton is like the foliage in the woods; time will change it, I'm well aware, as winter changes the trees. <u>My love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath<\/u> _ as source of little visible delight, but necessary. Nelly, I am Heathcliff!. He's always, always in my mind _ not as a pleasure to myself, but as my own being....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMy love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath illustrates","options":["metaphor","allusion","euphemism","simile",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nworld have been Heathcliff's miseries, and I watched and felt each from the beginning.My great thought in living is himself. <u>If all else perished, and he remained,<\/u> I should still continue to be. And if all else remained, and he were <u>annihilated,<\/u> the universe would be turned to a mighty stranger _ is should not seem a part of it. My love for Linton is like the foliage in the woods; time will change it, I'm well aware, as winter changes the trees. <u>My love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath<\/u> _ as source of little visible delight, but necessary. Nelly, I am Heathcliff!. He's always, always in my mind _ not as a pleasure to myself, but as my own being....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nannihilated in the extract implies","options":["rebirth","death","marriage","problems",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nworld have been Heathcliff's miseries, and I watched and felt each from the beginning.My great thought in living is himself. <u>If all else perished, and he remained,<\/u> I should still continue to be. And if all else remained, and he were <u>annihilated,<\/u> the universe would be turned to a mighty stranger _ is should not seem a part of it. My love for Linton is like the foliage in the woods; time will change it, I'm well aware, as winter changes the trees. <u>My love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath<\/u> _ as source of little visible delight, but necessary. Nelly, I am Heathcliff!. He's always, always in my mind _ not as a pleasure to myself, but as my own being....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf all else perished and he remained illustrates","options":["paradox","irony","bathos","antithesis",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nworld have been Heathcliff's miseries, and I watched and felt each from the beginning.My great thought in living is himself. <u>If all else perished, and he remained,<\/u> I should still continue to be. And if all else remained, and he were <u>annihilated,<\/u> the universe would be turned to a mighty stranger _ is should not seem a part of it. My love for Linton is like the foliage in the woods; time will change it, I'm well aware, as winter changes the trees. <u>My love for Heathcliff resembles the eternal rocks beneath<\/u> _ as source of little visible delight, but necessary. Nelly, I am Heathcliff!. He's always, always in my mind _ not as a pleasure to myself, but as my own being....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe diction of the extract conveys the speaker's","options":["contempt","despair","assurance","determination",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Bernado","Horatio","Francisco","Marcellus",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Marcellus","Francisco","the ghost","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Hamlet","Francisco","Marcellus","Bernado",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis thing refers to a","options":["ghost","horse","guard","soldier",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speakers were","options":["in a room in the castle","in the courtyard","on a platform in front of the castle","on the battlefield",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What, has <u>this thing<\/u> appeared again tonight?<br>\r\nB : I have seen nothing<br>\r\n(Act I, Scene one, lines 21-22)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeakers A and B are","options":["officers","soldiers","servants","courtiers",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs thou art to thyself:<br>\r\nSuch was the very armour he had on<br>\r\nWhen he the amitious Norway combated;<br>\r\nSo frown'd he once, when , in an angry parle,<br>\r\nHe smote the sledded Polacks on the ice....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene one, lines 59-63)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Horatio","Marcellus","Bernado","Franciso",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs thou art to thyself:<br>\r\nSuch was the very armour he had on<br>\r\nWhen he the amitious Norway combated;<br>\r\nSo frown'd he once, when , in an angry parle,<br>\r\nHe smote the sledded Polacks on the ice....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene one, lines 59-63)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Marcellus","Francisco","the ghost","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs thou art to thyself:<br>\r\nSuch was the very armour he had on<br>\r\nWhen he the amitious Norway combated;<br>\r\nSo frown'd he once, when , in an angry parle,<br>\r\nHe smote the sledded Polacks on the ice....<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene one, lines 59-63)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage conveys an atmosphere of","options":["peace","celebration","war","anxiety",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"The subject of discussion is","options":["Hamlet","the ghost","Claudius","Laertes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : What is the matter?<br>\r\nY : Save yourself, my lord:<br>\r\nThe ocean, overpeering of his list,<br>\r\nEats not the flats with more impetuous haste<br>\r\nThan young Laertes....<br>\r\n(Act 4, Scene five, lines 97-101)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker x IS","options":["a messenger","the King","the Queen","Laertes",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : What is the matter?<br>\r\nY : Save yourself, my lord:<br>\r\nThe ocean, overpeering of his list,<br>\r\nEats not the flats with more impetuous haste<br>\r\nThan young Laertes....<br>\r\n(Act 4, Scene five, lines 97-101)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Y is","options":["the Queen","Polonius","an attendant","Ophelia",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : What is the matter?<br>\r\nY : Save yourself, my lord:<br>\r\nThe ocean, overpeering of his list,<br>\r\nEats not the flats with more impetuous haste<br>\r\nThan young Laertes....<br>\r\n(Act 4, Scene five, lines 97-101)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe characters who come on the scene shortly afterwards are","options":["Laertes and the Danes","the Queen and Hamlet","Ophelia and the Danes","Hamlet and Laertes",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : What is the matter?<br>\r\nY : Save yourself, my lord:<br>\r\nThe ocean, overpeering of his list,<br>\r\nEats not the flats with more impetuous haste<br>\r\nThan young Laertes....<br>\r\n(Act 4, Scene five, lines 97-101)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe other character present in the scene is","options":["the Queen","Hamlet","Horatio","Marcellus",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nX : What is the matter?<br>\r\nY : Save yourself, my lord:<br>\r\nThe ocean, overpeering of his list,<br>\r\nEats not the flats with more impetuous haste<br>\r\nThan young Laertes....<br>\r\n(Act 4, Scene five, lines 97-101)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe King had just requested that all the","options":["doors be broken","doors be guarded","windows be locked","windows be opened",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question 45-50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAngels and ministers of grace defend us!<br>\r\nBe thou a spirit of health, or goblin damn'd,<br>\r\nBring with thee airs from heaven, or blasts from hell,<br>\r\nBe thy intents wicked or charitable,<br>\r\nThou comest in such a questionable shape.....<br>\r\n(Act l, Scene four, lines 39-43)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Hamlet","Marcellus","Horatio","Laertes",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question 45-50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAngels and ministers of grace defend us!<br>\r\nBe thou a spirit of health, or goblin damn'd,<br>\r\nBring with thee airs from heaven, or blasts from hell,<br>\r\nBe thy intents wicked or charitable,<br>\r\nThou comest in such a questionable shape.....<br>\r\n(Act l, Scene four, lines 39-43)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character who just spoke before the speaker is","options":["Horatio","Laertes","Hamlet","Marcellus",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question 45-50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAngels and ministers of grace defend us!<br>\r\nBe thou a spirit of health, or goblin damn'd,<br>\r\nBring with thee airs from heaven, or blasts from hell,<br>\r\nBe thy intents wicked or charitable,<br>\r\nThou comest in such a questionable shape.....<br>\r\n(Act l, Scene four, lines 39-43)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting of the extract is","options":["a room in the castle","the platform","the queen's closet","a graveyard",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question 45-50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAngels and ministers of grace defend us!<br>\r\nBe thou a spirit of health, or goblin damn'd,<br>\r\nBring with thee airs from heaven, or blasts from hell,<br>\r\nBe thy intents wicked or charitable,<br>\r\nThou comest in such a questionable shape.....<br>\r\n(Act l, Scene four, lines 39-43)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage creates an atmosphere of","options":["surprise and determination","insecurity and resignation","security and assurance","courage and assurance",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question 45-50<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAngels and ministers of grace defend us!<br>\r\nBe thou a spirit of health, or goblin damn'd,<br>\r\nBring with thee airs from heaven, or blasts from hell,<br>\r\nBe thy intents wicked or charitable,<br>\r\nThou comest in such a questionable shape.....<br>\r\n(Act l, Scene four, lines 39-43)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLine 1 suggests the speaker's belief in","options":["ghosts","spirits","purgatory","magic",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"''....the dragon-fly<br>\r\nhangs like a blue thread<br>\r\nlosened from the sky...'' illustrates","options":["simile","litotes","contrast","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A pause within a line of a poem is a","options":["zeugma","foot","caesura","stress",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Unrhymed iambic pentametre lines illustrate a","options":["rhyme scheme","heroic couplet","blank verse","free verse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The limerick","options":["is written to be sung","has a serious subject matter","is always light and humorous","uses lofty language",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The elegy","options":["conforms to a fixed pattern of lines","is set in the countryside","has a mournful tone","celebrates heroic deeds",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"''But at my back I always hear<br>\r\nTime's winged chariot hurrying near'' illustrates","options":["metaphor","apostrophe","oxymoron","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A line of poetry is measured by the","options":["number of words","number of feet it contains","images","rhythm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The recurrence of rhythmic pattern of stress in a poem is a","options":["couplet","metre","consonance","scansion",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A humorous imitation of a serious literary work is","options":["an ode","a parody","an epitaph","a burlesque",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A struggle between opposing forces in a literary work is the","options":["plot","conflict","climax","denouement",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A metrical pattern of stressed and unstressed syllables illustrates the","options":["iambus","anapaest","dactil","trochee",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A poem with fourteen lines of rhymed iambic pentrametre is","options":["an epic","a sonnet","a quatrain","an octave",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the options listed below.","options":["Euphemism","Oxymoron","Hyperbole","Rhythm",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The specific literary term used to distinguish a novel from a play is","options":["genre","verse","diction","style",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A pair of rhymed iambic pentametre lines is a","options":["tercet","heroic couplet","sestet","blank verse",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"''Friendship is a sheltering tree'' illustrates","options":["simile","metaphor","personification","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"The dominant device used in drama is","options":["stage direction","dialogue","characterisation","solioquy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"''I don't fancy forbidden fruits of fashions and fads'' illustrates","options":["refrain","repetition","assonance","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the options listed below.","options":["Romance","Novel","Short Story","Sonnet",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"''The strong gongs groaning as the guns boom far'' illustrates","options":["metonymy","refrain","onomatopoeia","repetition",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station, it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u>. <br>\r\nAlso, they are not at rest. For an hour, they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged,<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then, a policeman comes by on his round and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch does not move at all, he sleeps on steadily. Once in a while, one of the sleepers will not wake; he will have had his wish to die in the great <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some loney room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe style of writing is","options":["argumentative","epistolary","narrative","expository",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station, it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u>. <br>\r\nAlso, they are not at rest. For an hour, they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged,<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then, a policeman comes by on his round and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch does not move at all, he sleeps on steadily. Once in a while, one of the sleepers will not wake; he will have had his wish to die in the great <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''....on the backs of the benches'' illustrates","options":["synecdoche","epithet","assonance","personification",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station, it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u>. <br>\r\nAlso, they are not at rest. For an hour, they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged,<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then, a policeman comes by on his round and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch does not move at all, he sleeps on steadily. Once in a while, one of the sleepers will not wake; he will have had his wish to die in the great <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage conveys a mood of","options":["defiance","hope","fear","despair",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station, it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u>. <br>\r\nAlso, they are not at rest. For an hour, they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged,<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then, a policeman comes by on his round and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch does not move at all, he sleeps on steadily. Once in a while, one of the sleepers will not wake; he will have had his wish to die in the great <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.....gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged'' infers","options":["helplessness","slowness","sadness","tiredness",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHere in the station, it is in no way different save that the city is busy in its snow. But the old men cling to their seats as though they were symbolic and could not be given up. Now and then they sleep, their grey old heads resting with painful awkwardness <u>on the backs of the benches<\/u>. <br>\r\nAlso, they are not at rest. For an hour, they may sleep in the <u>gasping exhaustion of the ill-nourished and aged,<\/u> who have to walk in the night. Then, a policeman comes by on his round and nudges them upright.<br>\r\n''You can't sleep here'', he growls.<br>\r\nA strange ritual then begins. An old man is difficult to wake. One man after a slight lurch does not move at all, he sleeps on steadily. Once in a while, one of the sleepers will not wake; he will have had his wish to die in the great <u>droning<\/u> centre of the <u>hive<\/u> rather than in some lonely room fulfilled.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''droning'' and ''have'' illustrate","options":["anecdote","epigram","allusion","epitaph",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSleep, O sleep<br>\r\nWith thy Rod of Incantation<br>\r\nCharm my Imagination,<br>\r\nThen, only then, I cease to weep<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy thy power,<br>\r\nThe virgin, by Time O' ertaken,<br>\r\nFor Years forlorn, forsaken,<br>\r\nEnjoys the happy Hour.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat's to sleep?<br>\r\n'Tis a visionary Blessing;<br>\r\nA dream that's past expressing;<br>\r\nOur utmost Wish possessing;<br>\r\nSo may I always keep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is","options":["an epic","an ode","a lyric","a ballad",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSleep, O sleep<br>\r\nWith thy Rod of Incantation<br>\r\nCharm my Imagination,<br>\r\nThen, only then, I cease to weep<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy thy power,<br>\r\nThe virgin, by Time O' ertaken,<br>\r\nFor Years forlorn, forsaken,<br>\r\nEnjoys the happy Hour.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat's to sleep?<br>\r\n'Tis a visionary Blessing;<br>\r\nA dream that's past expressing;<br>\r\nOur utmost Wish possessing;<br>\r\nSo may I always keep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used in the first line is","options":["Oxymoron","apostrophe","rhyme","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSleep, O sleep<br>\r\nWith thy Rod of Incantation<br>\r\nCharm my Imagination,<br>\r\nThen, only then, I cease to weep<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy thy power,<br>\r\nThe virgin, by Time O' ertaken,<br>\r\nFor Years forlorn, forsaken,<br>\r\nEnjoys the happy Hour.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat's to sleep?<br>\r\n'Tis a visionary Blessing;<br>\r\nA dream that's past expressing;<br>\r\nOur utmost Wish possessing;<br>\r\nSo may I always keep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem makes use of","options":["end-stopped lines","run-on lines","rhyme","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSleep, O sleep<br>\r\nWith thy Rod of Incantation<br>\r\nCharm my Imagination,<br>\r\nThen, only then, I cease to weep<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy thy power,<br>\r\nThe virgin, by Time O' ertaken,<br>\r\nFor Years forlorn, forsaken,<br>\r\nEnjoys the happy Hour.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat's to sleep?<br>\r\n'Tis a visionary Blessing;<br>\r\nA dream that's past expressing;<br>\r\nOur utmost Wish possessing;<br>\r\nSo may I always keep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Sleep'' in the poem is an example of","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","pun",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSleep, O sleep<br>\r\nWith thy Rod of Incantation<br>\r\nCharm my Imagination,<br>\r\nThen, only then, I cease to weep<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy thy power,<br>\r\nThe virgin, by Time O' ertaken,<br>\r\nFor Years forlorn, forsaken,<br>\r\nEnjoys the happy Hour.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat's to sleep?<br>\r\n'Tis a visionary Blessing;<br>\r\nA dream that's past expressing;<br>\r\nOur utmost Wish possessing;<br>\r\nSo may I always keep.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe power of ''sleep'' is described as","options":["majestic","magical","poetic","worshipful",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf there be any good thing to be done,<br>\r\nThat may to thee do ease and grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me:<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to the country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life,<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death,<br>\r\nSpeak of it;<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 128 - 139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Speaker is","options":["Hamlet","Marcellus","Horatio","Claudius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf there be any good thing to be done,<br>\r\nThat may to thee do ease and grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me:<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to the country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life,<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death,<br>\r\nSpeak of it;<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 128 - 139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character addressed is","options":["the queen","the ghost","Bernado","Reynaldo",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf there be any good thing to be done,<br>\r\nThat may to thee do ease and grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me:<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to the country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life,<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death,<br>\r\nSpeak of it;<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 128 - 139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speech was made after","options":["the killing of Polonius","Hamlet's arrival at the palace","the arrival of the players","the appearance of the ghost",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Hamlet<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf thou hast any sound, or use of voice,<br>\r\nSpeak to me;<br>\r\nIf there be any good thing to be done,<br>\r\nThat may to thee do ease and grace to me,<br>\r\nSpeak to me:<br>\r\nIf thou art privy to the country's fate,<br>\r\nWhich, happily foreknowing may avoid,<br>\r\nO, speak!<br>\r\nOr if thou has uphoarded in thy life,<br>\r\nExtorted treasure in the womb of earth,<br>\r\nFor which, they say, you spirits oft walk in death,<br>\r\nSpeak of it;<br>\r\n(Act One, Scene I, lines 128 - 139)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker's mood is","options":["anger","regret","anxiety","disappointment",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"During this speech","options":["the palace soldiers arrived","Hamlet attacked the speaker","the queen fainted","a cock crowed",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY : Do you know me, my lord?<br>\r\nZ : Excellent well; <u>you are a fishmonger<\/u><br>\r\nY : Not I, my lord.<br>\r\nZ : Then I would you were so honest a man.<br>\r\nY : Honest, my lord!<br>\r\nZ : Ay, sir; to be honest, as this world goes. Is to be one man picked out of ten thousand.<br>\r\n(Act Two, Scene II, lines 173-179)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeakers Y and Z are","options":["Polonius and Hamlet","Claudius and Laertes","Laertes and Horatio","Marcellus and Reynaldo",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY : Do you know me, my lord?<br>\r\nZ : Excellent well; <u>you are a fishmonger<\/u><br>\r\nY : Not I, my lord.<br>\r\nZ : Then I would you were so honest a man.<br>\r\nY : Honest, my lord!<br>\r\nZ : Ay, sir; to be honest, as this world goes. Is to be one man picked out of ten thousand.<br>\r\n(Act Two, Scene II, lines 173-179)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Z's responses suggest that he is","options":["planning revenge","pretending to be mad","telling a lie","preparing to commit suicide",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY : Do you know me, my lord?<br>\r\nZ : Excellent well; <u>you are a fishmonger<\/u><br>\r\nY : Not I, my lord.<br>\r\nZ : Then I would you were so honest a man.<br>\r\nY : Honest, my lord!<br>\r\nZ : Ay, sir; to be honest, as this world goes. Is to be one man picked out of ten thousand.<br>\r\n(Act Two, Scene II, lines 173-179)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe two characters who just left this scene are","options":["Rosencrantz and Guildenstern","Hamlet and the ghost","The king and the question","Polonius and Ophelia",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY : Do you know me, my lord?<br>\r\nZ : Excellent well; <u>you are a fishmonger<\/u><br>\r\nY : Not I, my lord.<br>\r\nZ : Then I would you were so honest a man.<br>\r\nY : Honest, my lord!<br>\r\nZ : Ay, sir; to be honest, as this world goes. Is to be one man picked out of ten thousand.<br>\r\n(Act Two, Scene II, lines 173-179)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker Z thinks Y is","options":["very honest","as dishonest as most people","more dishonest than anyone","more dishonest than ten thousand people",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nY : Do you know me, my lord?<br>\r\nZ : Excellent well; <u>you are a fishmonger<\/u><br>\r\nY : Not I, my lord.<br>\r\nZ : Then I would you were so honest a man.<br>\r\nY : Honest, my lord!<br>\r\nZ : Ay, sir; to be honest, as this world goes. Is to be one man picked out of ten thousand.<br>\r\n(Act Two, Scene II, lines 173-179)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined statement illustrates","options":["metaphor","simile","hyperbole","irony",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet,<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Gertrude","Ophelia","Claudius","Polonius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet,<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person being discussed is","options":["Voltimand","Hamlet","Ophelia","Rosencrantz",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet,<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe characters being addressed are","options":["Marcellus and Horatio","Bernado and Francisco","Rosencrantz and Guildenstern","Marcellus and Francisco",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet,<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe response given to this speech indicates that the attempt was","options":["unsuccesful","successful","progressing","dangerous",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAnd can you, by no drift of circumstance,<br>\r\nGet from him why he puts on this confusion,<br>\r\nGrating so harshly all his days of quiet,<br>\r\nWith turbulent and dangerous lunacy?<br>\r\n(Act Three, Scene I, lines 1-4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character being addressed is","options":["Hamlet","Laertes","Ophelia","Horatio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy, now you speak<br>\r\nLike a good child and a true gentleman.<br>\r\nThat I am most sensible in grief for it,<br>\r\nIt shall as level to your judgement pierce<br>\r\n<u>As day does to your eye.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act Four Scene V, lines 128 - 133)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["the king","the queen","the ghost","polonius",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy, now you speak<br>\r\nLike a good child and a true gentleman.<br>\r\nThat I am most sensible in grief for it,<br>\r\nIt shall as level to your judgement pierce<br>\r\n<u>As day does to your eye.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act Four Scene V, lines 128 - 133)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined statement illustrates","options":["irony","metaphor","paradox","simile",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy, now you speak<br>\r\nLike a good child and a true gentleman.<br>\r\nThat I am most sensible in grief for it,<br>\r\nIt shall as level to your judgement pierce<br>\r\n<u>As day does to your eye.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act Four Scene V, lines 128 - 133)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe character who has just been murdered is","options":["Hamlet","Gertrude","Polonius","Claudius",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy, now you speak<br>\r\nLike a good child and a true gentleman.<br>\r\nThat I am most sensible in grief for it,<br>\r\nIt shall as level to your judgement pierce<br>\r\n<u>As day does to your eye.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act Four Scene V, lines 128 - 133)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis speech can be best be interpreted to mean","options":["that the murder was an act of revenge","a denial of responsibility for the murder","that it is not easy to know who the murderer is","that the murderer is present on the scene",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy, now you speak<br>\r\nLike a good child and a true gentleman.<br>\r\nThat I am most sensible in grief for it,<br>\r\nIt shall as level to your judgement pierce<br>\r\n<u>As day does to your eye.<\/u><br>\r\n(Act Four Scene V, lines 128 - 133)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting is","options":["the graveyard","a platform in front of the castle","a room in Polonius house","a room in the castle",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"A device that reveals a discrepancy between appearance and reality is","options":["oxymoron","irony","antithesis","bathos",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A situation in which the audience knows more than the character does, is an instance of","options":["comic relief","interior monologue","dramatic irony","poetic licence",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the options below","options":["Elegy","Epitaph","Dirge","Ode",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"A narrative poem in the manner of oral folk tradition is","options":["a pastoral","a lyric","a ballad","an elegy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"In ''my finger click with a Snicker And, chuckling, they knuckle the key'' the dominant figure of speech used is","options":["parallelism","litotes","hyperbole","onomatopoeia",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the options below","options":["Plot","Theme","Metre","Subject",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"''Horrendous horrors haunted Helen's happiness'' illustrates","options":["alliteration","rhythm","repetition","assonance",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Which of the following poems is based on travel and adventure?","options":["Ode to the West Wind","Freetown","Ulysses","No coffin, No grave",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"It runs through the reeds And away it proceeds, Through meadows and glade, In sun and in shade. The dominant device used in the above extract is","options":["imagery","symbolism","rhyme","pun",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the options below","options":["Simile","Metaphor","Synecdoche","Ballad",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The metrical pattern in, ''In mist or cloud, On mast or shroud'' is","options":["iambic","trochaic","anapaestic","dactylic",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Which of the following is a praise poem?","options":["Freetown","Ulysses","Is my team ploughing?","Ode to the West Wind",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Poetry that avoids the use of regular metre is","options":["lyric","lumerick","free verse","blank verse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The mood in ''Nothing so true as what you once let fall Most women have no characters at all'' is","options":["pessimistic","juibilant","anticipatory","optimistic",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Rhyming words","options":["have similar spellings","are parallel lines","sound alike","convey meaning",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"He sits under the bough utters a loud cough, wipes his sweating brow and gives the dog a blow. The extract illustrates......rhyme","options":["masculine","eye","internal","end",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"''Death be not proud'' illustrates","options":["euphemism","personification","metaphor","litotes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Lines that usualling have a set pattern of metre and rhyme constitute","options":["stanza","verse","rhyme scheme","falling metre",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me not (sweet) I am unkinde,<br>\r\nThat from <u>the Nunnerie<\/u><br>\r\n<u>of thy chaste breast<\/u> and quiet minde,<br>\r\nTo warre and Armes I flie.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrue, a new Mistresse now I chase,<br>\r\nThe first Foe in the field;<br>\r\nAnd with a stronger faith imbrace,<br>\r\nA Sword, a Horse, a Shield.<br>\r\nYet this <u>Inconstancy<\/u> is such,<br>\r\nAs you too shall adore;<br>\r\nI could not love thee (Deare) so much,<br>\r\nLov'd I not Honour more.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used is","options":["contrast","paradox","oxymoron","parallelism",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me not (sweet) I am unkinde,<br>\r\nThat from <u>the Nunnerie<\/u><br>\r\n<u>of thy chaste breast<\/u> and quiet minde,<br>\r\nTo warre and Armes I flie.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrue, a new Mistresse now I chase,<br>\r\nThe first Foe in the field;<br>\r\nAnd with a stronger faith imbrace,<br>\r\nA Sword, a Horse, a Shield.<br>\r\nYet this <u>Inconstancy<\/u> is such,<br>\r\nAs you too shall adore;<br>\r\nI could not love thee (Deare) so much,<br>\r\nLov'd I not Honour more.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe reference to ''......the Nunnerie of thy chaste breast'' suggests that the woman is being","options":["praised","mocked","scorned","admired",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me not (sweet) I am unkinde,<br>\r\nThat from <u>the Nunnerie<\/u><br>\r\n<u>of thy chaste breast<\/u> and quiet minde,<br>\r\nTo warre and Armes I flie.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrue, a new Mistresse now I chase,<br>\r\nThe first Foe in the field;<br>\r\nAnd with a stronger faith imbrace,<br>\r\nA Sword, a Horse, a Shield.<br>\r\nYet this <u>Inconstancy<\/u> is such,<br>\r\nAs you too shall adore;<br>\r\nI could not love thee (Deare) so much,<br>\r\nLov'd I not Honour more.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme pattern of the poem is","options":["abab","aabb","abcd","abba",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me not (sweet) I am unkinde,<br>\r\nThat from <u>the Nunnerie<\/u><br>\r\n<u>of thy chaste breast<\/u> and quiet minde,<br>\r\nTo warre and Armes I flie.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrue, a new Mistresse now I chase,<br>\r\nThe first Foe in the field;<br>\r\nAnd with a stronger faith imbrace,<br>\r\nA Sword, a Horse, a Shield.<br>\r\nYet this <u>Inconstancy<\/u> is such,<br>\r\nAs you too shall adore;<br>\r\nI could not love thee (Deare) so much,<br>\r\nLov'd I not Honour more.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Inconstancy'' in the poem implies that the","options":["man is unfaithful","woman is pure","woman is a nun","man loves war",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTell me not (sweet) I am unkinde,<br>\r\nThat from <u>the Nunnerie<\/u><br>\r\n<u>of thy chaste breast<\/u> and quiet minde,<br>\r\nTo warre and Armes I flie.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nTrue, a new Mistresse now I chase,<br>\r\nThe first Foe in the field;<br>\r\nAnd with a stronger faith imbrace,<br>\r\nA Sword, a Horse, a Shield.<br>\r\nYet this <u>Inconstancy<\/u> is such,<br>\r\nAs you too shall adore;<br>\r\nI could not love thee (Deare) so much,<br>\r\nLov'd I not Honour more.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is the pursuit of","options":["war","religion","honour","a horse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStella had to do her midweek shopping. There were four people before her in the queue. She watched the blond at the counter striking feverishly away at the numbers on the cold, light-flickering machine. There seemed to be a raging war between two mechanical contraptions, one, robot-like and the other stationary, but able to respond to the extent of punching, by sharp flickers of red light. It was an all consuming battle, as <u>a swift hand positioned the price label of the ceaseless flow of item on the coneyor belt and the right delivered the punches.<\/u> The intending owners were more unnoticed onlookers. Anyway, there is a belated recognition of them in ''thank you, call again balance sheet. '' It's all so mechanical, she thought. I mean, any creature-baboon, extraterrestial being or anything - could as well receive the same treatment as long as the conditions are met- ''bring to the counter, labelled items from the shelves.'' <u>Where is the human touch?<\/u> She wondered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the passage is","options":["litotes","personification","synecdoche","onomatopoeia",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStella had to do her midweek shopping. There were four people before her in the queue. She watched the blond at the counter striking feverishly away at the numbers on the cold, light-flickering machine. There seemed to be a raging war between two mechanical contraptions, one, robot-like and the other stationary, but able to respond to the extent of punching, by sharp flickers of red light. It was an all consuming battle, as <u>a swift hand positioned the price label of the ceaseless flow of item on the coneyor belt and the right delivered the punches.<\/u> The intending owners were more unnoticed onlookers. Anyway, there is a belated recognition of them in ''thank you, call again balance sheet. '' It's all so mechanical, she thought. I mean, any creature-baboon, extraterrestial being or anything - could as well receive the same treatment as long as the conditions are met- ''bring to the counter, labelled items from the shelves.'' <u>Where is the human touch?<\/u> She wondered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Where is the human touch?'' conveys an impression of","options":["dissappointment","expectation","discontent","indifference",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStella had to do her midweek shopping. There were four people before her in the queue. She watched the blond at the counter striking feverishly away at the numbers on the cold, light-flickering machine. There seemed to be a raging war between two mechanical contraptions, one, robot-like and the other stationary, but able to respond to the extent of punching, by sharp flickers of red light. It was an all consuming battle, as <u>a swift hand positioned the price label of the ceaseless flow of item on the coneyor belt and the right delivered the punches.<\/u> The intending owners were more unnoticed onlookers. Anyway, there is a belated recognition of them in ''thank you, call again balance sheet. '' It's all so mechanical, she thought. I mean, any creature-baboon, extraterrestial being or anything - could as well receive the same treatment as long as the conditions are met- ''bring to the counter, labelled items from the shelves.'' <u>Where is the human touch?<\/u> She wondered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe narrative technique used in the passage is","options":["omniscient","third person","flashback","first person",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStella had to do her midweek shopping. There were four people before her in the queue. She watched the blond at the counter striking feverishly away at the numbers on the cold, light-flickering machine. There seemed to be a raging war between two mechanical contraptions, one, robot-like and the other stationary, but able to respond to the extent of punching, by sharp flickers of red light. It was an all consuming battle, as <u>a swift hand positioned the price label of the ceaseless flow of item on the coneyor belt and the right delivered the punches.<\/u> The intending owners were more unnoticed onlookers. Anyway, there is a belated recognition of them in ''thank you, call again balance sheet. '' It's all so mechanical, she thought. I mean, any creature-baboon, extraterrestial being or anything - could as well receive the same treatment as long as the conditions are met- ''bring to the counter, labelled items from the shelves.'' <u>Where is the human touch?<\/u> She wondered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant mood in the passage is one of","options":["excitement","fear","anxiety","joy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nStella had to do her midweek shopping. There were four people before her in the queue. She watched the blond at the counter striking feverishly away at the numbers on the cold, light-flickering machine. There seemed to be a raging war between two mechanical contraptions, one, robot-like and the other stationary, but able to respond to the extent of punching, by sharp flickers of red light. It was an all consuming battle, as <u>a swift hand positioned the price label of the ceaseless flow of item on the coneyor belt and the right delivered the punches.<\/u> The intending owners were more unnoticed onlookers. Anyway, there is a belated recognition of them in ''thank you, call again balance sheet. '' It's all so mechanical, she thought. I mean, any creature-baboon, extraterrestial being or anything - could as well receive the same treatment as long as the conditions are met- ''bring to the counter, labelled items from the shelves.'' <u>Where is the human touch?<\/u> She wondered.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.....a swift left hand....and the right hand delivered the punches'' illustrates","options":["symbolism","hyperbole","parallelism","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I can catch him once upon the hip,<br>\r\n<u> I will feed fat the ancient grudge<\/u> I bear him.<br>\r\nHe hates our sacred nation, and he rails,<br>\r\nEven there where merchants most do congregate,<br>\r\nOn me, my bargains, and my well-won thrift,<br>\r\nWhich he calls interest;......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene  Three, lines 39-)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Tubal","Antonio","Shylock","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I can catch him once upon the hip,<br>\r\n<u> I will feed fat the ancient grudge<\/u> I bear him.<br>\r\nHe hates our sacred nation, and he rails,<br>\r\nEven there where merchants most do congregate,<br>\r\nOn me, my bargains, and my well-won thrift,<br>\r\nWhich he calls interest;......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene  Three, lines 39-)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is an example of","options":["epilogue","soliloquy","monologue","aside",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I can catch him once upon the hip,<br>\r\n<u> I will feed fat the ancient grudge<\/u> I bear him.<br>\r\nHe hates our sacred nation, and he rails,<br>\r\nEven there where merchants most do congregate,<br>\r\nOn me, my bargains, and my well-won thrift,<br>\r\nWhich he calls interest;......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene  Three, lines 39-)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression illustrates","options":["assonance","metaphor","wit","euphemism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I can catch him once upon the hip,<br>\r\n<u> I will feed fat the ancient grudge<\/u> I bear him.<br>\r\nHe hates our sacred nation, and he rails,<br>\r\nEven there where merchants most do congregate,<br>\r\nOn me, my bargains, and my well-won thrift,<br>\r\nWhich he calls interest;......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene  Three, lines 39-)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''my well-won thrift'' is","options":["sarcasm","a parody","an understatement","an allegory",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIf I can catch him once upon the hip,<br>\r\n<u> I will feed fat the ancient grudge<\/u> I bear him.<br>\r\nHe hates our sacred nation, and he rails,<br>\r\nEven there where merchants most do congregate,<br>\r\nOn me, my bargains, and my well-won thrift,<br>\r\nWhich he calls interest;......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene  Three, lines 39-)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the extract the speaker is","options":["kind","tricky","vindictive","angry",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nAlack, what heinous sin is it in me<br>\r\nTo be ashamed to be my father's child!<br>\r\n<u>But though I am a daughter to his blood<\/u><br>\r\n<u>I am not to his manners<\/u>.....<br>\r\n(Act 11 Scene Three lines 15 - 18)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is","options":["a soliloguy","an epilogue","an aside","a flashback",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAlack, what heinous sin is it in me<br>\r\nTo be ashamed to be my father's child!<br>\r\n<u>But though I am a daughter to his blood<br>\r\nI am not to his manners<\/u>.....<br>\r\n(Act 11 Scene Three lines 15 - 18)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is in love with","options":["Gratiano","Lorenzo","Antonio","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAlack, what heinous sin is it in me<br>\r\nTo be ashamed to be my father's child!<br>\r\n<u>But though I am a daughter to his blood<br>\r\nI am not to his manners<\/u>.....<br>\r\n(Act 11 Scene Three lines 15 - 18)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker has been addressing","options":["Solanio","Portia","Lancelot","Nerissa",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAlack, what heinous sin is it in me<br>\r\nTo be ashamed to be my father's child!<br>\r\n<u>But though I am a daughter to his blood<br>\r\nI am not to his manners<\/u>.....<br>\r\n(Act 11 Scene Three lines 15 - 18)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Tubal","Portia","Morocco","Jessica",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAlack, what heinous sin is it in me<br>\r\nTo be ashamed to be my father's child!<br>\r\n<u>But though I am a daughter to his blood<br>\r\nI am not to his manners<\/u>.....<br>\r\n(Act 11 Scene Three lines 15 - 18)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''I will feed fat the ancient gradge'' illustrates","options":["metonymy","contrast","apostrophe","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......'twere damnation<br>\r\nTo think so base a<u>though;<\/u> it were too gross<br>\r\nTo rib her cerecloth in the obscure grave; \u2015 <br>\r\nOr shall I think in silver she's immured;<br>\r\n<u>Being ten times undervalued to tried gold?<\/u><br>\r\n(Act 11 scene seven, lines 49 - 53)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Arragon","Antonio","Morocco","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......'twere damnation<br>\r\nTo think so base a<u>though;<\/u> it were too gross<br>\r\nTo rib her cerecloth in the obscure grave; \u2015 <br>\r\nOr shall I think in silver she's immured;<br>\r\n<u>Being ten times undervalued to tried gold?<\/u><br>\r\n(Act 11 scene seven, lines 49 - 53)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person referred to in the extract is","options":["Jessica","Antonio","Balthazar","Portia",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......'twere damnation<br>\r\nTo think so base a<u>though;<\/u> it were too gross<br>\r\nTo rib her cerecloth in the obscure grave; \u2015 <br>\r\nOr shall I think in silver she's immured;<br>\r\n<u>Being ten times undervalued to tried gold?<\/u><br>\r\n(Act 11 scene seven, lines 49 - 53)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Though'' in the extract implies","options":["meditating on his love","associating the portrait with lead","challenging rival suitors","reflecting on his fate",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......'twere damnation<br>\r\nTo think so base a<u>though;<\/u> it were too gross<br>\r\nTo rib her cerecloth in the obscure grave; \u2015 <br>\r\nOr shall I think in silver she's immured;<br>\r\n<u>Being ten times undervalued to tried gold?<\/u><br>\r\n(Act 11 scene seven, lines 49 - 53)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAfter this speech, the speaker","options":["unlocks the gold casket","engages his lover","unfolds his marriage plans","celebrates his victory",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......'twere damnation<br>\r\nTo think so base a<u>though;<\/u> it were too gross<br>\r\nTo rib her cerecloth in the obscure grave; \u2015 <br>\r\nOr shall I think in silver she's immured;<br>\r\n<u>Being ten times undervalued to tried gold?<\/u><br>\r\n(Act 11 scene seven, lines 49 - 53)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'' Being ten times undervalued to try gold?'' reveals the speaker's","options":["strength of love","assessment of his lover's character","value of gold","estimate of his lover's worth.",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhen it is paid, according to the tenor.<br>\r\nIt doth appear you are a worthy judge,<br>\r\nYou know the law, <u>your exposition<\/u><br>\r\nHath been most sound. I charge you by the law;....<br>\r\nProceed to judgement;.....<br>\r\n(Act IV Scene On, lines 231 - 236)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Antonio","Shylock","Bassanio","Nerissa",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhen it is paid, according to the tenor.<br>\r\nIt doth appear you are a worthy judge,<br>\r\nYou know the law, <u>your exposition<\/u><br>\r\nHath been most sound. I charge you by the law;....<br>\r\nProceed to judgement;.....<br>\r\n(Act IV Scene On, lines 231 - 236)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is","options":["Jessica","Duke","Portia","Lorenzo",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhen it is paid, according to the tenor.<br>\r\nIt doth appear you are a worthy judge,<br>\r\nYou know the law, <u>your exposition<\/u><br>\r\nHath been most sound. I charge you by the law;....<br>\r\nProceed to judgement;.....<br>\r\n(Act IV Scene On, lines 231 - 236)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract conveys a feeling of","options":["dejection","anxiety","tolerance","confidence",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhen it is paid, according to the tenor.<br>\r\nIt doth appear you are a worthy judge,<br>\r\nYou know the law, <u>your exposition<\/u><br>\r\nHath been most sound. I charge you by the law;....<br>\r\nProceed to judgement;.....<br>\r\n(Act IV Scene On, lines 231 - 236)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Your exposition'' refers to","options":["legal knowledge","plea for mercy","exercise of justice","enactment of the law",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhen it is paid, according to the tenor.<br>\r\nIt doth appear you are a worthy judge,<br>\r\nYou know the law, <u>your exposition<\/u><br>\r\nHath been most sound. I charge you by the law;....<br>\r\nProceed to judgement;.....<br>\r\n(Act IV Scene On, lines 231 - 236)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA the end of the speech, the speaker","options":["proceeds to execte the bond","accepts the judgement of  the court","submits to the Duke's authority","declares his unalterable stand",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2005"},{"question":"The persons created of presented in a literary work are","options":["heroes","actorrs","clowns","characters",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["fiction","monologue","aside","soliloguy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A group of lines separated from other groups in a poem is known as","options":["verse","caesura","stanza","metre",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Dialogue is the predominant feature of","options":["genre","drama","poetry","prose",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["comedy","prose","drama","poetry",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A literary work in which animals are used as characters is a","options":["memoir","fable","biography","farce",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"''True wit is nature to advantage drest.<br>\r\nWhat oft was thought but ne'er so well expressed''.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is an example of","options":["rhythm","pun","rhyme","paradox",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A character who creates humour in a play is a","options":["flat character","heroine","round character","clown",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A short witty statement in poetry constitutes a\/an","options":["lyric","ode","epigram","elegy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A literary work is didactic f it","options":["entertains","comforts","criticizes","teaches",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["''Elegy written in a country churchyard''","''Ulysses''","''No coffin, no grave''","''Ode to the West Wind''",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A poem that expresses grief over the death of a notable figure in society is a\/an","options":["ode","ballad","limerick","elegy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["Daniel Defoe","Thomas Gray","John Donne","Alfred Tennyson",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A recurrent image in a literary work is the","options":["theme","motif","episode","mood",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A dominant feature of poetry is its","options":["economy of language","depiction of scences","use of dialogue","narration of tales",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The position from which a story is presented is the","options":["narrative technique","point of view","setting","plot",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"''For my yoke is easy and my burden is light'' illustrates the use of","options":["bathos","euphemism","paradox","irony",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The dominant literary device used in ''A drowsing numbness pains my sense'' is","options":["parallelism","symbolism","repetition","diction",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Setting has to do with","options":["time and place","incidents and events","tone and mood","rhythm and rhyme",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"''And yonder all before us lie. Deserts of vast eternity'' illustrates the use of","options":["allegory","personification","oxymoron","allusion",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe fact was that, no sooner had the sickles began o play than, the <br>\r\natmosphere suddenly felt as if cress would grow in it without other<br>\r\nnourishment. it rubbed people's cheeks like damp flannel when they<br>\r\nwalked abroad: There was a gusty, high warm wind: isolated raindrops atarred the window-panes at remote distancees; the sunlight<br>\r\nwould flap out like a quickly opened fan, throw the pattern of the window<br>\r\nupon the floor of the room in a milky, colourless shine, and withdraw as suddenly as it had passed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage deals with","options":["atmosphere","temperature","scene","clouds",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe fact was that, no sooner had the sickles began o play than, the <br>\r\natmosphere suddenly felt as if cress would grow in it without other<br>\r\nnourishment. it rubbed people's cheeks like damp flannel when they<br>\r\nwalked abroad: There was a gusty, high warm wind: isolated raindrops atarred the window-panes at remote distancees; the sunlight<br>\r\nwould flap out like a quickly opened fan, throw the pattern of the window<br>\r\nupon the floor of the room in a milky, colourless shine, and withdraw as suddenly as it had passed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage illustrates the use of .....prose.","options":["descriptive","narrative","expository","imaginative",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe fact was that, no sooner had the sickles began o play than, the <br>\r\natmosphere suddenly felt as if cress would grow in it without other<br>\r\nnourishment. it rubbed people's cheeks like damp flannel when they<br>\r\nwalked abroad: There was a gusty, high warm wind: isolated raindrops atarred the window-panes at remote distancees; the sunlight<br>\r\nwould flap out like a quickly opened fan, throw the pattern of the window<br>\r\nupon the floor of the room in a milky, colourless shine, and withdraw as suddenly as it had passed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the passage is","options":["metaphor","simile","oxymoron","hyperbole",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The last five lines make use of......imagery","options":["tacile","auditory","gustatory","visual",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe fact was that, no sooner had the sickles began o play than, the <br>\r\natmosphere suddenly felt as if cress would grow in it without other<br>\r\nnourishment. it rubbed people's cheeks like damp flannel when they<br>\r\nwalked abroad: There was a gusty, high warm wind: isolated raindrops atarred the window-panes at remote distancees; the sunlight<br>\r\nwould flap out like a quickly opened fan, throw the pattern of the window<br>\r\nupon the floor of the room in a milky, colourless shine, and withdraw as suddenly as it had passed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe feeling induced is one of","options":["excitement","indifference","anger","despondency",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDillgent foot-worker<br>\r\nlegs lithe, foot loose<br>\r\nto frantic drums<br>\r\nand frenetic flutes<br>\r\nAcrobat strokes swift in the air<br>\r\nwrought masterly like<br>\r\na frenzied antelope<br>\r\nGyrating to the April music<br>\r\nof the lush Savannah<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem describes","options":["dancing","wrestling","hunting","drumming",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDillgent foot-worker<br>\r\nlegs lithe, foot loose<br>\r\nto frantic drums<br>\r\nand frenetic flutes<br>\r\nAcrobat strokes swift in the air<br>\r\nwrought masterly like<br>\r\na frenzied antelope<br>\r\nGyrating to the April music<br>\r\nof the lush Savannah<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe atmosphere of the poem is one of","options":["anxiety","excitement","eagerness","despair",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDillgent foot-worker<br>\r\nlegs lithe, foot loose<br>\r\nto frantic drums<br>\r\nand frenetic flutes<br>\r\nAcrobat strokes swift in the air<br>\r\nwrought masterly like<br>\r\na frenzied antelope<br>\r\nGyrating to the April music<br>\r\nof the lush Savannah<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''frenetic flutes'' illustrates the use of","options":["hyperbole","symbolism","metaphor","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"The dominant literary device in the poem is","options":["personification","simile","onomatopoeia","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDillgent foot-worker<br>\r\nlegs lithe, foot loose<br>\r\nto frantic drums<br>\r\nand frenetic flutes<br>\r\nAcrobat strokes swift in the air<br>\r\nwrought masterly like<br>\r\na frenzied antelope<br>\r\nGyrating to the April music<br>\r\nof the lush Savannah<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is an example of a\/an","options":["lyric","ode","pastoral","ballad",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I pray thee over -name them, and as thou namest them, I will describe them. And according to my description level at my affection.<br>\r\nB : First there is the neapolitan prince.<br>\r\nA : Ay, that's a colt indeedd, for he doth nothing but talk of his horse, and he makes it a great appropriation his own good parts that he can shoe him himself. I am much afeared my lady his mother played false with a smith <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Nerissa","Portia","Jessica","Duke",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I pray thee over -name them, and as thou namest them, I will describe them. And according to my description level at my affection.<br>\r\nB : First there is the neapolitan prince.<br>\r\nA : Ay, that's a colt indeedd, for he doth nothing but talk of his horse, and he makes it a great appropriation his own good parts that he can shoe him himself. I am much afeared my lady his mother played false with a smith <br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Portia","Antonio","Nerissa","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I pray thee over -name them, and as thou namest them, I will describe them. And according to my description level at my affection.<br>\r\nB : First there is the neapolitan prince.<br>\r\nA : Ay, that's a colt indeedd, for he doth nothing but talk of his horse, and he makes it a great appropriation his own good parts that he can shoe him himself. I am much afeared my lady his mother played false with a smith <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe attitude of Speaker A to the person mentioned by Speaker B is one of","options":["affection","contempt","indifference","resignation",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis kindness will I show.<br>\r\nGo with me to a notary; seal me there<br>\r\nYour single bond, and , in a merry sport,<br>\r\nIf you repay me not on such a day,<br>\r\n....let the forfeit<br>\r\nBe nominated for an equal pound....<br>\r\n(Act One Scene 111)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''Kindness'' the speaker has agreed to ''show'' is","options":["debt rescheduling","sponsorship of pilgrimage","payment of dowry","interest-free loan",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis kindness will I show.<br>\r\nGo with me to a notary; seal me there<br>\r\nYour single bond, and , in a merry sport,<br>\r\nIf you repay me not on such a day,<br>\r\n....let the forfeit<br>\r\nBe nominated for an equal pound....<br>\r\n(Act One Scene 111)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''Kindness'' is to be repaid within","options":["one month","three months","one year","a life -time",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis kindness will I show.<br>\r\nGo with me to a notary; seal me there<br>\r\nYour single bond, and , in a merry sport,<br>\r\nIf you repay me not on such a day,<br>\r\n....let the forfeit<br>\r\nBe nominated for an equal pound....<br>\r\n(Act One Scene 111)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''merry sport'' in line 3 means a","options":["feast","game","joke","carnival",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let me choose,<br>\r\nFor as I am, live upon the rack.<br>\r\nB : Upon the rack, Bassanio? then confess<br>\r\nWhat treason there is mingled with your love.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Lorenzo","Nerissa","Portia","Gratiano",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let me choose,<br>\r\nFor as I am, live upon the rack.<br>\r\nB : Upon the rack, Bassanio? then confess<br>\r\nWhat treason there is mingled with your love.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''rack'' symbolizes","options":["confession","torture","penitence","danger",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let me choose,<br>\r\nFor as I am, live upon the rack.<br>\r\nB : Upon the rack, Bassanio? then confess<br>\r\nWhat treason there is mingled with your love.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A had earlier been advised to","options":["pause a day or two","forgo the opportunity","pause a week or month","exploit the opportunity",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n....if you pick us, do we not bleed? if <br>\r\nYou tickle us, do we not laugh? If you poison us, do we not<br>\r\ndie? -And if you wrong us, shall we not revenge? If we are like you in the rest, we will resemble you in that.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''you'' refers to","options":["Merchants","Venetians","Christians","Jews",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n....if you pick us, do we not bleed? if <br>\r\nYou tickle us, do we not laugh? If you poison us, do we not<br>\r\ndie? -And if you wrong us, shall we not revenge? If we are like you in the rest, we will resemble you in that.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''you'' and ''we'' are related by their common","options":["religion","humanity","profession","nationality",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n....if you pick us, do we not bleed? if <br>\r\nYou tickle us, do we not laugh? If you poison us, do we not<br>\r\ndie? -And if you wrong us, shall we not revenge? If we are like you in the rest, we will resemble you in that.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speech asserts the speaker's demand for","options":["mercy","reprieve","parole","justice",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow to choose right, but then I am forsworm;<br>\r\nSo will I never be; so you may miss me;<br>\r\nBut if you do, you'll make me whish a sin,<br>\r\nThat l had been forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scence ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Duke","Arragon","Bassanio","Morocco",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow to choose right, but then I am forsworm;<br>\r\nSo will I never be; so you may miss me;<br>\r\nBut if you do, you'll make me whish a sin,<br>\r\nThat l had been forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scence ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy  the expression ''I am forsworn'', the reader becomes aware of the speaker's","options":["inheritance","fiancee","predicament","tradition",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow to choose right, but then I am forsworm;<br>\r\nSo will I never be; so you may miss me;<br>\r\nBut if you do, you'll make me whish a sin,<br>\r\nThat l had been forsworn.<br>\r\n(Act Three Scence ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''....you may miss me'' implies","options":["separation","fear","death","failure",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis house, these servants, and this same myself<br>\r\nAre yours, my Lord! I give them with this ring,<br>\r\nWhich when you part from, lose, or give away,<br>\r\nLet it presage the ruin of your love,<br>\r\nAnd be my vantage to exclaim on you .<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ring symbolizes","options":["love","marriage","engagement","surrender",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis house, these servants, and this same myself<br>\r\nAre yours, my Lord! I give them with this ring,<br>\r\nWhich when you part from, lose, or give away,<br>\r\nLet it presage the ruin of your love,<br>\r\nAnd be my vantage to exclaim on you .<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Nerissa","Portia","Antonio","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis house, these servants, and this same myself<br>\r\nAre yours, my Lord! I give them with this ring,<br>\r\nWhich when you part from, lose, or give away,<br>\r\nLet it presage the ruin of your love,<br>\r\nAnd be my vantage to exclaim on you .<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''....my Lord'' in line 2 refers to","options":["Duke","Arragon","Morocco","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis house, these servants, and this same myself<br>\r\nAre yours, my Lord! I give them with this ring,<br>\r\nWhich when you part from, lose, or give away,<br>\r\nLet it presage the ruin of your love,<br>\r\nAnd be my vantage to exclaim on you .<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''...And be my vantage to exclaim on you'' means the opportunity to...him","options":["hate","love","embrace","reject",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis house, these servants, and this same myself<br>\r\nAre yours, my Lord! I give them with this ring,<br>\r\nWhich when you part from, lose, or give away,<br>\r\nLet it presage the ruin of your love,<br>\r\nAnd be my vantage to exclaim on you .<br>\r\n(Act Three Scene 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn ''Let it presage with the ruin of your love'', ''it'' implies","options":["commitment","friendship","betrayal","hatred",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2004"},{"question":"A narrative in the oral tradition that may include legends and fables is a","options":["balled","pastoral","folkale","romance",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A short poem written on a tomb is a\/an","options":["dirge","panegyric","epigram","epitaph",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["tragedy","comedy","stanza","farce",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A long narrative which depicts country life is a\/an","options":["ballad","epic","ode","pastoral",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"One of the following is not an African poet","options":["lenrie Peters","Thomas Gray","J.P. Clark","Sly Cheney-Coker",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A recurrent image in a literary work that illustrates theme is","options":["symbol","dramatic irony","motif","pathetic fallacy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Diction is writers choice of","options":["styles","plot","theme","words",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"''Enjambment'' is the poetic term referring to the use of","options":["run-on-lines","rhyme lines","rhythm","metre",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Stanza refers to..in a poem","options":["devices","lines","sections","divisions",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"''Life is an empty dream'' illustrates the use of","options":["synecdoche","peripeteia","litotes","allusion",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The term used for the unraveling  of the complications of the plot at the end of a literary works is","options":["climax","denouement","conflict","tension",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Pick the odd item","options":["elergy","ballad","metaphor","ode",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"The feelings and attitudes of a water are conveyed by","options":["mood","style","theme","setting",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A author's story about himself is a\/an","options":["biography","essay","diary","autobiography",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHis mind flitted back memory lane. He remembered how time walked quietly in. like a thief in the night and then put a sword in the heart of the land. He remembered all his life's sweat. drained away by the strife.He remembered his wife and two lovely kids, all slain pitilessly by the beasts in khaki. He remembered his only sister, a tender rose, defiled in turns by them and then slaughtered like a lamb upon the ritual table.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the extract is one of","options":["gloom","serenity","anxiety","indifference",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHis mind flitted back memory lane. He remembered how time walked quietly in. like a thief in the night and then put a sword in the heart of the land. He remembered all his life's sweat. drained away by the strife.He remembered his wife and two lovely kids, all slain pitilessly by the beasts in khaki. He remembered his only sister, a tender rose, defiled in turns by them and then slaughtered like a lamb upon the ritual table.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is about","options":["armed robbery","ritual killing","the tragedy of war","the tragedy of oppression",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHis mind flitted back memory lane. He remembered how time walked quietly in. like a thief in the night and then put a sword in the heart of the land. He remembered all his life's sweat. drained away by the strife.He remembered his wife and two lovely kids, all slain pitilessly by the beasts in khaki. He remembered his only sister, a tender rose, defiled in turns by them and then slaughtered like a lamb upon the ritual table.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used is","options":["metaphor","repetition","simile","personification",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHis mind flitted back memory lane. He remembered how time walked quietly in. like a thief in the night and then put a sword in the heart of the land. He remembered all his life's sweat. drained away by the strife.He remembered his wife and two lovely kids, all slain pitilessly by the beasts in khaki. He remembered his only sister, a tender rose, defiled in turns by them and then slaughtered like a lamb upon the ritual table.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''....a tender rose'' is an example of a\/an","options":["personification","imagery","symbolism","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHis mind flitted back memory lane. He remembered how time walked quietly in. like a thief in the night and then put a sword in the heart of the land. He remembered all his life's sweat. drained away by the strife.He remembered his wife and two lovely kids, all slain pitilessly by the beasts in khaki. He remembered his only sister, a tender rose, defiled in turns by them and then slaughtered like a lamb upon the ritual table.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.....put a sword in the heart of the land'' implies","options":["murder","danger","strife","destruction.",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMove him into the sun<br>\r\nGently its touch awoke him once,<br>\r\nAt home, whispering of fields unsown<br>\r\nAlways it woke him even in France<br>\r\nUntil this morning  and this snow<br>\r\nIf anything might rouse him now<br>\r\nThis kind old sun will know<br>\r\nThink how it wakes the seeds<br>\r\nWoke,once, the clays of a cold star<br>\r\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are sides,<br>\r\nFull-nerved still warm too hard to stir?<br>\r\nWas it for this the clay grew tall?<br>\r\nO what made fatuous sunbeams toil<br>\r\nTo break earth's sleep at all?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is a\/an","options":["elegy","epic","sonnet","lyric",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMove him into the sun<br>\r\nGently its touch awoke him once,<br>\r\nAt home, whispering of fields unsown<br>\r\nAlways it woke him even in France<br>\r\nUntil this morning  and this snow<br>\r\nIf anything might rouse him now<br>\r\nThis kind old sun will know<br>\r\nThink how it wakes the seeds<br>\r\nWoke,once, the clays of a cold star<br>\r\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are sides,<br>\r\nFull-nerved still warm too hard to stir?<br>\r\nWas it for this the clay grew tall?<br>\r\nO what made fatuous sunbeams toil<br>\r\nTo break earth's sleep at all?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOne of the dominant literary devices used in the poem is","options":["hyperbole","simile","assonance","metaphhor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMove him into the sun<br>\r\nGently its touch awoke him once,<br>\r\nAt home, whispering of fields unsown<br>\r\nAlways it woke him even in France<br>\r\nUntil this morning  and this snow<br>\r\nIf anything might rouse him now<br>\r\nThis kind old sun will know<br>\r\nThink how it wakes the seeds<br>\r\nWoke,once, the clays of a cold star<br>\r\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are sides,<br>\r\nFull-nerved still warm too hard to stir?<br>\r\nWas it for this the clay grew tall?<br>\r\nO what made fatuous sunbeams toil<br>\r\nTo break earth's sleep at all?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is the ...of life","options":["vanity","creation","distortion","futility",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMove him into the sun<br>\r\nGently its touch awoke him once,<br>\r\nAt home, whispering of fields unsown<br>\r\nAlways it woke him even in France<br>\r\nUntil this morning  and this snow<br>\r\nIf anything might rouse him now<br>\r\nThis kind old sun will know<br>\r\nThink how it wakes the seeds<br>\r\nWoke,once, the clays of a cold star<br>\r\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are sides,<br>\r\nFull-nerved still warm too hard to stir?<br>\r\nWas it for this the clay grew tall?<br>\r\nO what made fatuous sunbeams toil<br>\r\nTo break earth's sleep at all?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood in the last two lines is one of","options":["surprise","lament","uncertainty","indifference",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMove him into the sun<br>\r\nGently its touch awoke him once,<br>\r\nAt home, whispering of fields unsown<br>\r\nAlways it woke him even in France<br>\r\nUntil this morning  and this snow<br>\r\nIf anything might rouse him now<br>\r\nThis kind old sun will know<br>\r\nThink how it wakes the seeds<br>\r\nWoke,once, the clays of a cold star<br>\r\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are sides,<br>\r\nFull-nerved still warm too hard to stir?<br>\r\nWas it for this the clay grew tall?<br>\r\nO what made fatuous sunbeams toil<br>\r\nTo break earth's sleep at all?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant images are associated with","options":["Death","Nature","Life","Age",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My people do already know my mind,<br>\r\nAnd will acknowledge you and Jessica<br>\r\nIn place of Lord Bassanio and myself<br>\r\nSo fare thee till we shall meet again<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Fair thoughts and happy hours attend on you<br>\r\n(Act 111, sc IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Jessica","Gratiano","Portia","Nerissa",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My people do already know my mind,<br>\r\nAnd will acknowledge you and Jessica<br>\r\nIn place of Lord Bassanio and myself<br>\r\nSo fare thee till we shall meet again<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Fair thoughts and happy hours attend on you<br>\r\n(Act 111, sc IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Lorenzo","Solerio","Solarino","Launcelot",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My people do already know my mind,<br>\r\nAnd will acknowledge you and Jessica<br>\r\nIn place of Lord Bassanio and myself<br>\r\nSo fare thee till we shall meet again<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Fair thoughts and happy hours attend on you<br>\r\n(Act 111, sc IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the extract speaker A intends","options":["forgiving the merchant","eloping to the city","going to a monastery","challenging the Jew",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My people do already know my mind,<br>\r\nAnd will acknowledge you and Jessica<br>\r\nIn place of Lord Bassanio and myself<br>\r\nSo fare thee till we shall meet again<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Fair thoughts and happy hours attend on you<br>\r\n(Act 111, sc IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is in the company of","options":["Antonio","Solanio","Bassanio","Jessica",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My people do already know my mind,<br>\r\nAnd will acknowledge you and Jessica<br>\r\nIn place of Lord Bassanio and myself<br>\r\nSo fare thee till we shall meet again<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Fair thoughts and happy hours attend on you<br>\r\n(Act 111, sc IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''My people'' refers to the speaker's","options":["friends","enemies","household","relatives",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs much as I deserve: why, that's the lady<br>\r\nI do in birth deserve her, and in fortunes<br>\r\nIn graces, and in qualities of breeding <br>\r\nBut more than these, in love I do deserves<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc VII)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Arragon","Bassanio","Morocco","Gratiano",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs much as I deserve: why, that's the lady<br>\r\nI do in birth deserve her, and in fortunes<br>\r\nIn graces, and in qualities of breeding <br>\r\nBut more than these, in love I do deserves<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc VII)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of the extract is","options":["a declaration of love","the choice of caskets","the elopement of two lovers","a marriage proposal",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs much as I deserve: why, that's the lady<br>\r\nI do in birth deserve her, and in fortunes<br>\r\nIn graces, and in qualities of breeding <br>\r\nBut more than these, in love I do deserves<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc VII)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAfter the speech, the speaker","options":["marries his lover","betrays his emotions","fails in his venture","breaks the engagement",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs much as I deserve: why, that's the lady<br>\r\nI do in birth deserve her, and in fortunes<br>\r\nIn graces, and in qualities of breeding <br>\r\nBut more than these, in love I do deserves<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc VII)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''The lady'' in the extract refers to","options":["Balthazar","Nerissa","Jessica","Portia",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAs much as I deserve: why, that's the lady<br>\r\nI do in birth deserve her, and in fortunes<br>\r\nIn graces, and in qualities of breeding <br>\r\nBut more than these, in love I do deserves<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc VII)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speech is an example of a\/an","options":["mnologue","aside","soliloquy","epilogue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n.....I owe you much, and like a wilful youth<br>\r\nThat which I owe is lost: but if you please<br>\r\n<u>To shoot another arrow<\/u> that self way<br>\r\nwhich you did shoot the first.<br>\r\nAnd thankfully rest debtor for the first <br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Solanio","Launcelot","Bassanio","Lorenzo",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n.....I owe you much, and like a wilful youth<br>\r\nThat which I owe is lost: but if you please<br>\r\n<u>To shoot another arrow<\/u> that self way<br>\r\nwhich you did shoot the first.<br>\r\nAnd thankfully rest debtor for the first <br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is","options":["Antonio","Shylock","Gratiano","Solanio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n.....I owe you much, and like a wilful youth<br>\r\nThat which I owe is lost: but if you please<br>\r\n<u>To shoot another arrow<\/u> that self way<br>\r\nwhich you did shoot the first.<br>\r\nAnd thankfully rest debtor for the first <br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker intends to","options":["fulfil his part of the bond","raise money for suit","seek redress in court","elope with his fiancee",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n.....I owe you much, and like a wilful youth<br>\r\nThat which I owe is lost: but if you please<br>\r\n<u>To shoot another arrow<\/u> that self way<br>\r\nwhich you did shoot the first.<br>\r\nAnd thankfully rest debtor for the first <br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe first line of the extract illustrates","options":["irony","sarcasm","parallelism","simile",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n.....I owe you much, and like a wilful youth<br>\r\nThat which I owe is lost: but if you please<br>\r\n<u>To shoot another arrow<\/u> that self way<br>\r\nwhich you did shoot the first.<br>\r\nAnd thankfully rest debtor for the first <br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression is an example of","options":["symbolism","imagery","metaphor","allusion",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the Question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.....Thus ornament is but the guilded shore<br>\r\nTo a most dangerous sea...........<br>\r\n<u>The seeming truth which cunning times put on<\/u><br>\r\nTo entrap the wisest. Therefore thou gaudy gold<br>\r\nHard food for Midas. I will none of thee.....<br>\r\n(Act 111 sc 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Arragon","Lorenzo","Bassanio","Morocco",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the Question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.....Thus ornament is but the guilded shore<br>\r\nTo a most dangerous sea...........<br>\r\n<u>The seeming truth which cunning times put on<\/u><br>\r\nTo entrap the wisest. Therefore thou gaudy gold<br>\r\nHard food for Midas. I will none of thee.....<br>\r\n(Act 111 sc 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe first two lines convey an impression of","options":["radiance","deception","beauty","destruction",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the Question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.....Thus ornament is but the guilded shore<br>\r\nTo a most dangerous sea...........<br>\r\n<u>The seeming truth which cunning times put on<\/u><br>\r\nTo entrap the wisest. Therefore thou gaudy gold<br>\r\nHard food for Midas. I will none of thee.....<br>\r\n(Act 111 sc 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression is an example of","options":["onomatopoeia","personification","hyperbole","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the Question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.....Thus ornament is but the guilded shore<br>\r\nTo a most dangerous sea...........<br>\r\n<u>The seeming truth which cunning times put on<\/u><br>\r\nTo entrap the wisest. Therefore thou gaudy gold<br>\r\nHard food for Midas. I will none of thee.....<br>\r\n(Act 111 sc 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n '' Midas'' in the extract illustrates a\/an","options":["anecdote","pun","allusion","allegory",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the Question<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.....Thus ornament is but the guilded shore<br>\r\nTo a most dangerous sea...........<br>\r\n<u>The seeming truth which cunning times put on<\/u><br>\r\nTo entrap the wisest. Therefore thou gaudy gold<br>\r\nHard food for Midas. I will none of thee.....<br>\r\n(Act 111 sc 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n After the speech, the speaker proceeds to","options":["make the right choice","marry her lover","unlock the silver casket","expose the secret",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2003"},{"question":"A couplet is","options":["a pastorial poem","two successive rhyming lines","a love poem","two successive unrhyming lines",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The first eight lines of a sonnet is a\/an","options":["tercet","sestet","octave","quatrain",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"An ode is a","options":["poem about love","poem of mouring","praise poem","narrative poem",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The expression of unpleasant experiences in a mild way is","options":["hyperbole","metaphor","euphemism","paradox",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A poem which tells a story in the form of a song is a\/an","options":["epic","ballad","pastoral","eulogy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The paragraph in prose can be compared to _ in poetry","options":["couplet","line","stanza","verse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In to eat of the tree, the device used is","options":["Irony","personificatio","allusion","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Poetry is defined by","options":["words written in sequence","condensed use of language","evocation of feelings","legends and myths",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Salute to the Elephant is an example of  _ poetry","options":["traditional","dramatic","epic","narrative",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The juxtaposition of two seemingly contradictory words is","options":["contrast","anti-climax","oxymoron","anti-thesis",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"''A little learning is dangerous<br>\r\nDrink deep or taste not the Pierian spring''<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract illustrates a","options":["quatrain","hexameter","couplet","sestet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Grace me no grace, nor uncle me no uncle; <br>\r\nI am no traitors uncle;<br>\r\nand that word ''grace'' in an ungracious mouth<br>\r\nis but profane.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the extract is","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","repetition",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"You are the salt of my life illustrates a","options":["metaphor","simile","irony","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The sequence of beats in a poem is its","options":["rhythm","rhyme","irony","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Charm strikes the sight, but merit wins the soul is an example of","options":["oxymoron","epigram","epithet","bathos",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A literary device that creates a mental picture of a situation is","options":["imagery","symbolism","flashback","epilogue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"A short witty statement is an","options":["epistle","eulogy","epigram","anecdote",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"The whole town was present at the wedding ceremony is an example of","options":["oxymoron","hyperbole","onomatopoeia","repetition",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"In a literary work, a clown normally","options":["directs the action","creates comic relief","supports the protagonist","creats the atmosphere",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in. The sky, like a hooded monk wore black, as in mourning, ready to shed its load. The sun was mystified while heaps of sand and dust spiralled high up in the sky, sending <u>high and low alike <\/u>scurrying into hiding. The town had never known such a downpour, it was forty-eight hours of weeping by both the heavens and the inhabitants of Olusi who lost most of their life's savings in this destructive blessing.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of the passage is","options":["cloud","climate","rainfall","flood",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in. The sky, like a hooded monk wore black, as in mourning, ready to shed its load. The sun was mystified while heaps of sand and dust spiralled high up in the sky, sending <u>high and low alike <\/u>scurrying into hiding. The town had never known such a downpour, it was forty-eight hours of weeping by both the heavens and the inhabitants of Olusi who lost most of their life's savings in this destructive blessing.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in is an example of","options":["metaphor","synecdoche","imagery","apostrophe",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in. The sky, like a hooded monk wore black, as in mourning, ready to shed its load. The sun was mystified while heaps of sand and dust spiralled high up in the sky, sending <u>high and low alike <\/u>scurrying into hiding. The town had never known such a downpour, it was forty-eight hours of weeping by both the heavens and the inhabitants of Olusi who lost most of their life's savings in this destructive blessing.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression the sky, like a hooded monk wore black, illustrates","options":["symbolism","paradox","personification","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in. The sky, like a hooded monk wore black, as in mourning, ready to shed its load. The sun was mystified while heaps of sand and dust spiralled high up in the sky, sending <u>high and low alike <\/u>scurrying into hiding. The town had never known such a downpour, it was forty-eight hours of weeping by both the heavens and the inhabitants of Olusi who lost most of their life's savings in this destructive blessing.<br>\r\n...........high and low alike refers to the","options":["rulers of the village","women and their children","chiefs and their subjects","rich and the poor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe month of July crept in. The sky, like a hooded monk wore black, as in mourning, ready to shed its load. The sun was mystified while heaps of sand and dust spiralled high up in the sky, sending <u>high and low alike <\/u>scurrying into hiding. The town had never known such a downpour, it was forty-eight hours of weeping by both the heavens and the inhabitants of Olusi who lost most of their life's savings in this destructive blessing.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n........destructive blessing shows the use of","options":["antithesis","oxymoron","apostrophe","parallelism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the poem below  and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney here, Money there<br>\r\nEverywhere, anywhere, whatever you want, Money<br>\r\nBut where is the Money to spend?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nChildren and family matters, you're useful<br>\r\nHealth and education matters<br>\r\nFood and transport<br>\r\nNight and day<br>\r\nChurch and Mosque<br>\r\nIn the Lord's name you're needed everywhere<br>\r\nLife is tough without you<br>\r\nNothing comes easy without you.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney O! where are you?<br>\r\nYou are as hard as a nut to crack<br>\r\nWithout you our problems are like my mother's <br>\r\nPaying beads<br>\r\nWill you desert the commoners like that?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey search<br>\r\nThey count<br>\r\nThey wait<br>\r\nThey cry<br>\r\nYet their is life of beaded needs<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the poem is","options":["religion","enlightenment","struggle","hardship",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the poem below  and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney here, Money there<br>\r\nEverywhere, anywhere, whatever you want, Money<br>\r\nBut where is the Money to spend?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nChildren and family matters, you're useful<br>\r\nHealth and education matters<br>\r\nFood and transport<br>\r\nNight and day<br>\r\nChurch and Mosque<br>\r\nIn the Lord's name you're needed everywhere<br>\r\nLife is tough without you<br>\r\nNothing comes easy without you.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney O! where are you?<br>\r\nYou are as hard as a nut to crack<br>\r\nWithout you our problems are like my mother's <br>\r\nPaying beads<br>\r\nWill you desert the commoners like that?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey search<br>\r\nThey count<br>\r\nThey wait<br>\r\nThey cry<br>\r\nYet their is life of beaded needs<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant poetic devices used are","options":["onomatopoeia and refrain","metaphor and simile","repetition and personification","pun and hyperbole",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the poem below  and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney here, Money there<br>\r\nEverywhere, anywhere, whatever you want, Money<br>\r\nBut where is the Money to spend?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nChildren and family matters, you're useful<br>\r\nHealth and education matters<br>\r\nFood and transport<br>\r\nNight and day<br>\r\nChurch and Mosque<br>\r\nIn the Lord's name you're needed everywhere<br>\r\nLife is tough without you<br>\r\nNothing comes easy without you.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney O! where are you?<br>\r\nYou are as hard as a nut to crack<br>\r\nWithout you our problems are like my mother's <br>\r\nPaying beads<br>\r\nWill you desert the commoners like that?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey search<br>\r\nThey count<br>\r\nThey wait<br>\r\nThey cry<br>\r\nYet their is life of beaded needs<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe tone of the poem is one of","options":["sadness and lamentation","happiness and excitement","apathy and non-challance","resignation and joy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the poem below  and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney here, Money there<br>\r\nEverywhere, anywhere, whatever you want, Money<br>\r\nBut where is the Money to spend?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nChildren and family matters, you're useful<br>\r\nHealth and education matters<br>\r\nFood and transport<br>\r\nNight and day<br>\r\nChurch and Mosque<br>\r\nIn the Lord's name you're needed everywhere<br>\r\nLife is tough without you<br>\r\nNothing comes easy without you.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney O! where are you?<br>\r\nYou are as hard as a nut to crack<br>\r\nWithout you our problems are like my mother's <br>\r\nPaying beads<br>\r\nWill you desert the commoners like that?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey search<br>\r\nThey count<br>\r\nThey wait<br>\r\nThey cry<br>\r\nYet their is life of beaded needs<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe use of rhetorical questions _ the poet's message","options":["emphasizes","repeats","recasts","dramatizes",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the poem below  and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney here, Money there<br>\r\nEverywhere, anywhere, whatever you want, Money<br>\r\nBut where is the Money to spend?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nChildren and family matters, you're useful<br>\r\nHealth and education matters<br>\r\nFood and transport<br>\r\nNight and day<br>\r\nChurch and Mosque<br>\r\nIn the Lord's name you're needed everywhere<br>\r\nLife is tough without you<br>\r\nNothing comes easy without you.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMoney O! where are you?<br>\r\nYou are as hard as a nut to crack<br>\r\nWithout you our problems are like my mother's <br>\r\nPaying beads<br>\r\nWill you desert the commoners like that?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey search<br>\r\nThey count<br>\r\nThey wait<br>\r\nThey cry<br>\r\nYet their is life of beaded needs<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLines 13-15 illustrate the use of","options":["metaphor","alliteration","simile","pun",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNot in love neither? Then let us say you are sad<br>\r\nBecause you are not merry; and 'twere as easy<br>\r\n<u>for you to laugh and leap,<\/u> and say you are merry<br>\r\nBecause you are not sad.<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n The speaker is","options":["Portia","Solanio","Gratiano","Bassanio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNot in love neither? Then let us say you are sad<br>\r\nBecause you are not merry; and 'twere as easy<br>\r\n<u>for you to laugh and leap,<\/u> and say you are merry<br>\r\nBecause you are not sad.<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n The person addressed is","options":["Antonio","Nerissa","Lorenzo","Salarino",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNot in love neither? Then let us say you are sad<br>\r\nBecause you are not merry; and 'twere as easy<br>\r\n<u>for you to laugh and leap,<\/u> and say you are merry<br>\r\nBecause you are not sad.<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing the addressee's","options":["elopement","synecdoche","engagement","melancholy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: The Merchant of Venice<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNot in love neither? Then let us say you are sad<br>\r\nBecause you are not merry; and 'twere as easy<br>\r\n<u>for you to laugh and leap,<\/u> and say you are merry<br>\r\nBecause you are not sad.<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression illustrates","options":["assonance","synecdoche","alliteration","irony",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry thou wilt leave my father so<br>\r\nOur house is hell, and thou a merry devil<br>\r\nDidst rob it of some taste of tediousness<br>\r\nBut fare thee well: there is a ducat for thee<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc lll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Jessica","Servingman","Nerissa","Portia",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry thou wilt leave my father so<br>\r\nOur house is hell, and thou a merry devil<br>\r\nDidst rob it of some taste of tediousness<br>\r\nBut fare thee well: there is a ducat for thee<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc lll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou in the extract refers to","options":["Gobbo","Launcelot","Salerio","Leonardo",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry thou wilt leave my father so<br>\r\nOur house is hell, and thou a merry devil<br>\r\nDidst rob it of some taste of tediousness<br>\r\nBut fare thee well: there is a ducat for thee<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc lll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nDuring this speech, the speaker","options":["betrays his conscience","chooses the right partner","gives the addressee a letter","changes the course of action",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry thou wilt leave my father so<br>\r\nOur house is hell, and thou a merry devil<br>\r\nDidst rob it of some taste of tediousness<br>\r\nBut fare thee well: there is a ducat for thee<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc lll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nMerry devil illustrates","options":["oxymoron","simile","paradox","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry thou wilt leave my father so<br>\r\nOur house is hell, and thou a merry devil<br>\r\nDidst rob it of some taste of tediousness<br>\r\nBut fare thee well: there is a ducat for thee<br>\r\n(Act 11, sc lll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is contemplating on","options":["marriage","love","elopement","disguise",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\n....very vilely in the morning when he is sober, and most vilely<br>\r\nin the afternoon when he is drunk. When he is best he is a little<br>\r\nworse than a man, and when he is worst he is a little better than a beast<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Portia","Launcelot","Jessica","Antonio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\n....very vilely in the morning when he is sober, and most vilely<br>\r\nin the afternoon when he is drunk. When he is best he is a little<br>\r\nworse than a man, and when he is worst he is a little better than a beast<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is","options":["Gobbo","Nerissa","Bassanjo","Lorenzo",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\n....very vilely in the morning when he is sober, and most vilely<br>\r\nin the afternoon when he is drunk. When he is best he is a little<br>\r\nworse than a man, and when he is worst he is a little better than a beast<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of discussion is the","options":["Prince of Morocco","Young Baron of England","Prince of Arragon","Duke of Saxony's nephew",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\n....very vilely in the morning when he is sober, and most vilely<br>\r\nin the afternoon when he is drunk. When he is best he is a little<br>\r\nworse than a man, and when he is worst he is a little better than a beast<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is contemplating on the","options":["choice of caskets","loss of his fortune","most eligible suitor","outcome of the trial",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\n....very vilely in the morning when he is sober, and most vilely<br>\r\nin the afternoon when he is drunk. When he is best he is a little<br>\r\nworse than a man, and when he is worst he is a little better than a beast<br>\r\n(Act 1 sc ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the extract is","options":["simile","paradox","repetition","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLock up my doors, and when you hear the drum<br>\r\n<u>And the vile squealing of the wry-necked fife.<\/u><br>\r\nClamber not you up to the casements then<br>\r\nNor thrust you up to the casements then<br>\r\nTO GAZE ON CHRISTIAN FOOLS WITH VARNISHED FACES.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(Act 11 sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Gratiano","Shylock","Lorenzo","Solanio",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLock up my doors, and when you hear the drum<br>\r\n<u>And the vile squealing of the wry-necked fife.<\/u><br>\r\nClamber not you up to the casements then<br>\r\nNor thrust you up to the casements then<br>\r\nTO GAZE ON CHRISTIAN FOOLS WITH VARNISHED FACES.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(Act 11 sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant literary device used in the extract is","options":["allusion","irony","symbolism","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLock up my doors, and when you hear the drum<br>\r\n<u>And the vile squealing of the wry-necked fife.<\/u><br>\r\nClamber not you up to the casements then<br>\r\nNor thrust you up to the casements then<br>\r\nTO GAZE ON CHRISTIAN FOOLS WITH VARNISHED FACES.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(Act 11 sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is","options":["Bassanio","Antonio","Launcelot","Jessica",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLock up my doors, and when you hear the drum<br>\r\n<u>And the vile squealing of the wry-necked fife.<\/u><br>\r\nClamber not you up to the casements then<br>\r\nNor thrust you up to the casements then<br>\r\nTO GAZE ON CHRISTIAN FOOLS WITH VARNISHED FACES.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(Act 11 sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nAfter this scene the person addressed","options":["portrays love for his suitor","informs of the loss at sea","elopes with her lover","delivers letter to a suitor",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question <br>\r\n<br>\r\nLock up my doors, and when you hear the drum<br>\r\n<u>And the vile squealing of the wry-necked fife.<\/u><br>\r\nClamber not you up to the casements then<br>\r\nNor thrust you up to the casements then<br>\r\nTO GAZE ON CHRISTIAN FOOLS WITH VARNISHED FACES.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n(Act 11 sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression illustrates","options":["alliteration","metaphor","synecdoche","personification",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2002"},{"question":"One of the following plays is based on the mistakes of a night","options":["The Gods are not to Blame","The marriage of Anansewa","Arms and the Man","She stoops to Conquer",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The genres of Literature are","options":["dialogue, stage and actng","prose, tales and verse","prose, poetry and drama","drama, actors and poetry",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A seemingly absurd statement is a\/an","options":["climax","anti-climax","hyperbole","paradox",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A play is watched by a\/an","options":["congregation","group","audience","entourage",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Poetry differs from prose by its use of","options":["song","condensed language","flat character","rhythm",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Pick out the odd item","options":["Actors","Stage","Dialogue","Chapters",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A piece of writing about oneself is a\/an","options":["autobiography","biography","autography","mimeography",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A short poem expressing intense emotions and usually sung is a\/an","options":["ode","pastoral","elegy","lyric",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Pick out the odd item","options":["The Gods are not to Blame","The Concubine","Things Fall Apart","The African Child",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In ''Biodun did his best but was first from behind'', first from behind'' is an example of","options":["sarcasm","euphemism","hyperbole","paradox",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A literary work that ridicules ideas or the follies of people is a\/an","options":["satire","elegy","lullaby","masque",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In ''the wretched beggar cleaned his nails with dry saliva'' the device used is","options":["anti-climax","oxymoron","anecdote","antithesis",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A symbolic representation of ideas, actions and situations in a work of art is a\/an","options":["fable","allegory","romance","parody",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"''The cell is a cruel place; sometimes a haven'', illustrates the use of","options":["paradox","sarcasm","anti-climax","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"An elegy is a poem that usually expresses a state of","options":["euphoria","confusion and chaos","grandeur","sorrow and grief",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In ''I am so famished, I can devour a whole cow'', the device used is","options":["hyperbole","metaphor","irony","sarcasm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The repetition of initial consonant sounds in poetry is","options":["assonance","rhyme","alliteration","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"''Here comes the princess now heaven walks on earth'', illustrates the use of","options":["contrast","metaphor","metonymy","meiosis",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"In the line '' I walk upon the thorns of life'', the metre is","options":["trochaic","anapaestic","iambic","dactylic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"An ode is usually a poem written for","options":["condemnation","celebration","instruction","entertainment",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe killing of a whale at sea isn't pleasant to witness or even to contemplate. Hunted down through solar and other highly specialized equipment, the whale has no more chance of escape like a steer in a slaughterhouse. The manner of his death, however, is very different. A grenade-tipped harpoon explodes deep within his body, often causing prolonged suffering before the gentle-giant, whose intelligence may be second only to our own, is reduced to a carcass ready for processing into crayons, lipstick, shoe polish, fertilizer, margarine and pet food.<br>\r\n<u>The inhumane manner of death<\/u>, however, is the least part of the scandal known as the whaling industry. Much more important is the fact that the killing is quite unnecessary. Adeguate substitutes exist for every single use to which the whale carcasses are currently put, and although some 32,000 whales are killed every year, the sum of commodities are provide is insignificant in the world's economy.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe passage is","options":["descriptive","narrative","argumentative","expository",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe killing of a whale at sea isn't pleasant to witness or even to contemplate. Hunted down through solar and other highly specialized equipment, the whale has no more chance of escape like a steer in a slaughterhouse. The manner of his death, however, is very different. A grenade-tipped harpoon explodes deep within his body, often causing prolonged suffering before the gentle-giant, whose intelligence may be second only to our own, is reduced to a carcass ready for processing into crayons, lipstick, shoe polish, fertilizer, margarine and pet food.<br>\r\n<u>The inhumane manner of death<\/u>, however, is the least part of the scandal known as the whaling industry. Much more important is the fact that the killing is quite unnecessary. Adeguate substitutes exist for every single use to which the whale carcasses are currently put, and although some 32,000 whales are killed every year, the sum of commodities are provide is insignificant in the world's economy.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the passage is (that)","options":["whales are a menace to mankind","the killing of whale is unnecessary","the importance of whale-hunting","whales are highly intelligent",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe killing of a whale at sea isn't pleasant to witness or even to contemplate. Hunted down through solar and other highly specialized equipment, the whale has no more chance of escape like a steer in a slaughterhouse. The manner of his death, however, is very different. A grenade-tipped harpoon explodes deep within his body, often causing prolonged suffering before the gentle-giant, whose intelligence may be second only to our own, is reduced to a carcass ready for processing into crayons, lipstick, shoe polish, fertilizer, margarine and pet food.<br>\r\n<u>The inhumane manner of death<\/u>, however, is the least part of the scandal known as the whaling industry. Much more important is the fact that the killing is quite unnecessary. Adeguate substitutes exist for every single use to which the whale carcasses are currently put, and although some 32,000 whales are killed every year, the sum of commodities are provide is insignificant in the world's economy.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression suggests that the writer","options":["has an aversion for the process","finds the activity fascinating","is aloof to the activity","does not dislike the process",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe killing of a whale at sea isn't pleasant to witness or even to contemplate. Hunted down through solar and other highly specialized equipment, the whale has no more chance of escape like a steer in a slaughterhouse. The manner of his death, however, is very different. A grenade-tipped harpoon explodes deep within his body, often causing prolonged suffering before the gentle-giant, whose intelligence may be second only to our own, is reduced to a carcass ready for processing into crayons, lipstick, shoe polish, fertilizer, margarine and pet food.<br>\r\n<u>The inhumane manner of death<\/u>, however, is the least part of the scandal known as the whaling industry. Much more important is the fact that the killing is quite unnecessary. Adeguate substitutes exist for every single use to which the whale carcasses are currently put, and although some 32,000 whales are killed every year, the sum of commodities are provide is insignificant in the world's economy.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''.....gentle giant'' conveys the picture of being","options":["ferocious","tame","timid","brave",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the passage below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe killing of a whale at sea isn't pleasant to witness or even to contemplate. Hunted down through solar and other highly specialized equipment, the whale has no more chance of escape like a steer in a slaughterhouse. The manner of his death, however, is very different. A grenade-tipped harpoon explodes deep within his body, often causing prolonged suffering before the gentle-giant, whose intelligence may be second only to our own, is reduced to a carcass ready for processing into crayons, lipstick, shoe polish, fertilizer, margarine and pet food.<br>\r\n<u>The inhumane manner of death<\/u>, however, is the least part of the scandal known as the whaling industry. Much more important is the fact that the killing is quite unnecessary. Adeguate substitutes exist for every single use to which the whale carcasses are currently put, and although some 32,000 whales are killed every year, the sum of commodities are provide is insignificant in the world's economy.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''...like a steer in a slaughterhouse'' is an example of","options":["simile","metaphor","personification","assonance",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou art the judge of man<br>\r\nJudging his plans and behaviour<br>\r\nJudging his speech and egotism<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNations plan without having thee in view<br>\r\nThey boast of their will<br>\r\nBut soon you show them their follies<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTomorrow and Tomorrow, go here and there<br>\r\nTime smiles and laughs<br>\r\nHe frowns his face and consults with fate<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poetic device used in the first line is","options":["apostrophe","personification","euphemism","litotes",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou art the judge of man<br>\r\nJudging his plans and behaviour<br>\r\nJudging his speech and egotism<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNations plan without having thee in view<br>\r\nThey boast of their will<br>\r\nBut soon you show them their follies<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTomorrow and Tomorrow, go here and there<br>\r\nTime smiles and laughs<br>\r\nHe frowns his face and consults with fate<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe last line of each stanza illustrates","options":["repetition","refrain","chorus","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou art the judge of man<br>\r\nJudging his plans and behaviour<br>\r\nJudging his speech and egotism<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNations plan without having thee in view<br>\r\nThey boast of their will<br>\r\nBut soon you show them their follies<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTomorrow and Tomorrow, go here and there<br>\r\nTime smiles and laughs<br>\r\nHe frowns his face and consults with fate<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used in stanza three is","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou art the judge of man<br>\r\nJudging his plans and behaviour<br>\r\nJudging his speech and egotism<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNations plan without having thee in view<br>\r\nThey boast of their will<br>\r\nBut soon you show them their follies<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTomorrow and Tomorrow, go here and there<br>\r\nTime smiles and laughs<br>\r\nHe frowns his face and consults with fate<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is about","options":["judgement","fate","time","life",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThou art the judge of man<br>\r\nJudging his plans and behaviour<br>\r\nJudging his speech and egotism<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nNations plan without having thee in view<br>\r\nThey boast of their will<br>\r\nBut soon you show them their follies<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge <br>\r\n<br>\r\nTomorrow and Tomorrow, go here and there<br>\r\nTime smiles and laughs<br>\r\nHe frowns his face and consults with fate<br>\r\nYou are the patient Judge<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract teaches us to use time","options":["to the fullest","wisely","to plan","for pleasure",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night.<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nO that I served that lady,<br>\r\nAnd might not be delivered to the world<br>\r\nTill I had made mine own occasion mellow,<br>\r\nWhat my estate is!<br>\r\n(Act 1 Sc. 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Orsino","Sir Andrew","Viola","Valentine",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night.<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nO that I served that lady,<br>\r\nAnd might not be delivered to the world<br>\r\nTill I had made mine own occasion mellow,<br>\r\nWhat my estate is!<br>\r\n(Act 1 Sc. 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''That lady'' refers to","options":["Olivia","Maria","Viola","the Duchess",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night.<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nO that I served that lady,<br>\r\nAnd might not be delivered to the world<br>\r\nTill I had made mine own occasion mellow,<br>\r\nWhat my estate is!<br>\r\n(Act 1 Sc. 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["a sea captain, friend to Sebastian","a sea captain, friend to Viola","Sir Toby, uncle to Olivia","Malvolio, steward to Olivia",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night.<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nO that I served that lady,<br>\r\nAnd might not be delivered to the world<br>\r\nTill I had made mine own occasion mellow,<br>\r\nWhat my estate is!<br>\r\n(Act 1 Sc. 11)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe word ''delivered'' in line 2 means","options":["condemned","sent away","made known","forgotten",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I could marry this wenchfor this device<br>\r\nB : So could I too.<br>\r\nA : And ask no other dowry with her but such another jest.<br>\r\nB : Nor I neither.<br>\r\nC : Here comes my noble gull-catcher.<br>\r\nA : Wilt thou set thy foot o my neck?<br>\r\nB : Or o' mine either?<br>\r\nA : Shall I play my freedom at tray: and become thy bondslave? <br>\r\nB : I faith, or I either?<br>\r\n(Act 2 Sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Anotonio","The Duke","Sir Toby","Fabian",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I could marry this wenchfor this device<br>\r\nB : So could I too.<br>\r\nA : And ask no other dowry with her but such another jest.<br>\r\nB : Nor I neither.<br>\r\nC : Here comes my noble gull-catcher.<br>\r\nA : Wilt thou set thy foot o my neck?<br>\r\nB : Or o' mine either?<br>\r\nA : Shall I play my freedom at tray: and become thy bondslave? <br>\r\nB : I faith, or I either?<br>\r\n(Act 2 Sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Sir Andrew","Feste","Curio","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I could marry this wenchfor this device<br>\r\nB : So could I too.<br>\r\nA : And ask no other dowry with her but such another jest.<br>\r\nB : Nor I neither.<br>\r\nC : Here comes my noble gull-catcher.<br>\r\nA : Wilt thou set thy foot o my neck?<br>\r\nB : Or o' mine either?<br>\r\nA : Shall I play my freedom at tray: and become thy bondslave? <br>\r\nB : I faith, or I either?<br>\r\n(Act 2 Sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A and B are discussing","options":["Viola","Olivia","M,aria","Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : I could marry this wenchfor this device<br>\r\nB : So could I too.<br>\r\nA : And ask no other dowry with her but such another jest.<br>\r\nB : Nor I neither.<br>\r\nC : Here comes my noble gull-catcher.<br>\r\nA : Wilt thou set thy foot o my neck?<br>\r\nB : Or o' mine either?<br>\r\nA : Shall I play my freedom at tray: and become thy bondslave? <br>\r\nB : I faith, or I either?<br>\r\n(Act 2 Sc V)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe conversation reveals that Speaker B is","options":["very confident","very shy","easily persuaded","easily confused",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Save thee, friend and thy music. Dost thou live by thy labor?<br>\r\nB : No, sir, I live by the church.<br>\r\nA : Art thou a churchman?<br>\r\nB : No such matter, sir, I do live by the church, for I do live at my hose, and my house doth stand by the church.<br>\r\n(Act 3 Sc 1.)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Feste","Viola","Clown","Olivia",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Save thee, friend and thy music. Dost thou live by thy labor?<br>\r\nB : No, sir, I live by the church.<br>\r\nA : Art thou a churchman?<br>\r\nB : No such matter, sir, I do live by the church, for I do live at my hose, and my house doth stand by the church.<br>\r\n(Act 3 Sc 1.)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Sir Andrew","Clown","Feste","The Duke",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Save thee, friend and thy music. Dost thou live by thy labor?<br>\r\nB : No, sir, I live by the church.<br>\r\nA : Art thou a churchman?<br>\r\nB : No such matter, sir, I do live by the church, for I do live at my hose, and my house doth stand by the church.<br>\r\n(Act 3 Sc 1.)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe phrase ''live by'' as used in the extract is an example of","options":["onomatopoeia","anthithesis","pun","irony",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Save thee, friend and thy music. Dost thou live by thy labor?<br>\r\nB : No, sir, I live by the church.<br>\r\nA : Art thou a churchman?<br>\r\nB : No such matter, sir, I do live by the church, for I do live at my hose, and my house doth stand by the church.<br>\r\n(Act 3 Sc 1.)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeakers A and B are","options":["at the sea-coat","in the theatre","in Orsino's palace","at Olivia's garden",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Fie, thou dishonest Satan! I call thee by the most modest<br>\r\nterms, for I am one of those gentle ones that will use the devil<br>\r\nhimself with courtesy. Sayest thou that house is dark?<br>\r\nB : As hell, Sir Topas<br>\r\n(Act 4 sc. ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Feste","Clown","Sir Toby","Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Fie, thou dishonest Satan! I call thee by the most modest<br>\r\nterms, for I am one of those gentle ones that will use the devil<br>\r\nhimself with courtesy. Sayest thou that house is dark?<br>\r\nB : As hell, Sir Topas<br>\r\n(Act 4 sc. ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed is","options":["Febian","Sir Andrew","Sir Toby","Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Fie, thou dishonest Satan! I call thee by the most modest<br>\r\nterms, for I am one of those gentle ones that will use the devil<br>\r\nhimself with courtesy. Sayest thou that house is dark?<br>\r\nB : As hell, Sir Topas<br>\r\n(Act 4 sc. ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A, wants the audience to believe that he is","options":["dealing with a mad person","daling with a stranger","addressing a stranger","addressing a sane person",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Fie, thou dishonest Satan! I call thee by the most modest<br>\r\nterms, for I am one of those gentle ones that will use the devil<br>\r\nhimself with courtesy. Sayest thou that house is dark?<br>\r\nB : As hell, Sir Topas<br>\r\n(Act 4 sc. ll)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSir Topas is expected to be a","options":["tacher","physician","parson","lunatic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry, madam, I have hurt your kinsman,<br>\r\nBut had it been the brother of my blood,<br>\r\nI must have done no less with wit and safety.<br>\r\nYou throw a strange regard upon me, and by that <br>\r\nI do perceieve it hath offended you;<br>\r\nPardon me, sweet one, even for the vows<br>\r\nWe made each other but so late ago.<br>\r\n(Act 5 Sc. 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Sir Toby","Sebastian","Viola","Sir Andrew",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry, madam, I have hurt your kinsman,<br>\r\nBut had it been the brother of my blood,<br>\r\nI must have done no less with wit and safety.<br>\r\nYou throw a strange regard upon me, and by that <br>\r\nI do perceive it hath offended you;<br>\r\nPardon me, sweet one, even for the vows<br>\r\nWe made each other but so late ago.<br>\r\n(Act 5 Sc. 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n.......''the brother o my blood'' implies he is","options":["your (own) brother","my (own) brother","our (own) brother","their (own) brother",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry, madam, I have hurt your kinsman,<br>\r\nBut had it been the brother of my blood,<br>\r\nI must have done no less with wit and safety.<br>\r\nYou throw a strange regard upon me, and by that <br>\r\nI do perceive it hath offended you;<br>\r\nPardon me, sweet one, even for the vows<br>\r\nWe made each other but so late ago.<br>\r\n(Act 5 Sc. 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''the vows'' refers to","options":["divorce","love","marriage","courtship",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"The speaker is replied by","options":["Antonio","Olivia","Sebastian","Orsino",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am sorry, madam, I have hurt your kinsman,<br>\r\nBut had it been the brother of my blood,<br>\r\nI must have done no less with wit and safety.<br>\r\nYou throw a strange regard upon me, and by that <br>\r\nI do perceieve it hath offended you;<br>\r\nPardon me, sweet one, even for the vows<br>\r\nWe made each other but so late ago.<br>\r\n(Act 5 Sc. 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is replied by","options":["Antonio","Olivia","Sebastian","Orsino",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2001"},{"question":"A short and witty poem is known as","options":["a ballad","an epigram","an epic","a lyric",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A literary work which extols one's virtues and accomplishments is","options":["a eulogy","a pastoral","an elegy","an allegory",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"George Orwell's Animal Farm is an example of a","options":["farce","burlesque","satire","lampoon",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A poem of lamentation on death is","options":["a lyric","a  ballad","an ode","an elegy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The misuse of words that sound somewhat similar is","options":["malapropism","metonymy","onomatopoeia","pun",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The main character in a literary work is the","options":["anatagonist","protagonist","narrator","villan",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A speech delivered by a character who is alone on the stage is","options":["a soliloquy","a  chorus","a dialogue","an aside",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A sonnet may be divided into an octave and a","options":["tercet","quatrain","sestet","couplet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"''All hands on deck'' is an example of","options":["personification","metonymy","metaphor","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"In poetry.....consist of four lines","options":["a sestet","a quatrain","an octave","a tercet",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The dominant device used in the lines above is","options":["oxymoron","mock-heroic","pathetic fallacy","satire",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"In the above lines, ''flow,'' and ''show''","options":["alliterate","contrast","rhyme","parallel",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The above lines constitute a","options":["couplet","rhythm","tercet","rhyme",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"''I have read Shakespeare' is an example of","options":["litotes","paradox","parody","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Twelfth Night is an example of","options":["farce","comedy","tragi-comedy","burlesque",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"In ''The fair breeze below, the white foam flew, The furrow followed free, the dominant device used is","options":["metaphor","personification","alliteration","assonance",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"An address to an object or person not present is","options":["apostrophe","synecdoche","paradox","epigram",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"The expression '' poisonous pleasure of wine'' Illustrates the use of","options":["metonymy","synecdoche","paradox","oxymoron",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A non-verbal story-telling by a character on stage is","options":["imitation","farce","mime","comedy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A character that develops with events and situations in a novel is a ......character","options":["flat","sound","minor","main",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNow, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>\r\nAnd Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>\r\nThough Pleasure's free, she cannot sing <br>\r\nAs sweet a song as Joy confined.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>\r\nAnd dances by false glare at night;<br>\r\nBut joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>\r\nTo spread its wings in Nature's light.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem says that ''Joy'' is","options":["for the poor","natural and satisfying","artificial and transitory","for lovers",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNow, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>\r\nAnd Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>\r\nThough Pleasure's free, she cannot sing <br>\r\nAs sweet a song as Joy confined.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>\r\nAnd dances by false glare at night;<br>\r\nBut joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>\r\nTo spread its wings in Nature's light.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dominant device used in presenting ''Joy'' and ''Pleasure'' in the first stanza is","options":["diction","oxymoron","personification","conceit",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNow, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>\r\nAnd Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>\r\nThough Pleasure's free, she cannot sing <br>\r\nAs sweet a song as Joy confined.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>\r\nAnd dances by false glare at night;<br>\r\nBut joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>\r\nTo spread its wings in Nature's light.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe feelings associated with ''Jy'' and ''Pleasure'' in the first stanza is","options":["rhyme","euphemism","assonance","contrast",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNow, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>\r\nAnd Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>\r\nThough Pleasure's free, she cannot sing <br>\r\nAs sweet a song as Joy confined.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>\r\nAnd dances by false glare at night;<br>\r\nBut joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>\r\nTo spread its wings in Nature's light.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''False glare'' refers to","options":["man-made light","nature's light","the moon's light","the sun's light",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\nRead the poem below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNow, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>\r\nAnd Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>\r\nThough Pleasure's free, she cannot sing <br>\r\nAs sweet a song as Joy confined.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nPleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>\r\nAnd dances by false glare at night;<br>\r\nBut joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>\r\nTo spread its wings in Nature's light.<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Pleasure's moth'' is an example of a (n)","options":["irony","hyperbole","metaphor","simile",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA suitable title for the passage is the","options":["March of Soldiers","Agony of War","Pangs of Hunger","Dread of Desease",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe writer's mood is one of","options":["anger","fear","pity","disappointment",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood is expressed through the use of","options":["objects","scenery","syntax","diction",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe attitude of the survivors is best summed up by the word","options":["indifference","persistence","resignation","victory",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the passage below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe device used in the last sentence is","options":["climax","sarcasm","euphemism","hyperbole",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>\r\nBut from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>\r\nThe element itself, till seven years heat,<br>\r\nShall not behold her face at ample view......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Cesario","Fabian","Valentine","Feste",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>\r\nBut from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>\r\nThe element itself, till seven years heat,<br>\r\nShall not behold her face at ample view......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\n''Element'' in the third line refers to the","options":["sky","weather","sun","cloud",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>\r\nBut from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>\r\nThe element itself, till seven years heat,<br>\r\nShall not behold her face at ample view......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe report is made to","options":["Olivia","Malvolio","Viola","Orsino",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>\r\nBut from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>\r\nThe element itself, till seven years heat,<br>\r\nShall not behold her face at ample view......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe one referred to by the speaker is","options":["Maria","Olivia","Sir Tony","Viola",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSo please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>\r\nBut from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>\r\nThe element itself, till seven years heat,<br>\r\nShall not behold her face at ample view......<br>\r\n(Act 1 Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe message is in connection with","options":["warfare","love","revenge","shipwreck",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>\r\nB : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the <br>\r\nMalignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>\r\ntherefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>\r\n(Act II Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe above dialogue is between","options":["Viola and Captain","Captain and Sebastian","Antonio and Sebastian","Sebastian and Olivia",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>\r\nB : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the <br>\r\nMalignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>\r\ntherefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>\r\n(Act II Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B requests Speaker A to","options":["be patient","stay behind","go back home","pray for his friend",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>\r\nB : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the <br>\r\nMalignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>\r\ntherefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>\r\n(Act II Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["grateful","happy","angry","sad",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>\r\nB : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the <br>\r\nMalignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>\r\ntherefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>\r\n(Act II Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe scene of his action is","options":["a street","the sea-coast","Orsino's palace","Olivia's palace",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>\r\nB : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the <br>\r\nMalignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>\r\ntherefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>\r\n(Act II Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined sentence means that my","options":["faith will rescue you","malice will destroy you","ill-luck may affect you","bad temper will hurt you",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : How dost thou like this tune?<br>\r\nB : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>\r\n Where Love is throned<br>\r\nA : Thou dost speak masterly<br>\r\nMy life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>\r\nHath stayed upon some favour that it loves; <br>\r\nHath is not, boy?<br>\r\nB : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Sir Toby","Sir Andrew","Duke Orsino","Countess Olivia",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : How dost thou like this tune?<br>\r\nB : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>\r\n Where Love is throned<br>\r\nA : Thou dost speak masterly<br>\r\nMy life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>\r\nHath stayed upon some favour that it loves; <br>\r\nHath is not, boy?<br>\r\nB : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe two speakers are in","options":["the garden","a ship","the Duke's palace","Olivia's house",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : How dost thou like this tune?<br>\r\nB : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>\r\n Where Love is throned<br>\r\nA : Thou dost speak masterly<br>\r\nMy life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>\r\nHath stayed upon some favour that it loves; <br>\r\nHath is not, boy?<br>\r\nB : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe relationship between speaker A and B is","options":["master-servant","brother-sister","husband-wife","mistress-steward",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : How dost thou like this tune?<br>\r\nB : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>\r\n Where Love is throned<br>\r\nA : Thou dost speak masterly<br>\r\nMy life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>\r\nHath stayed upon some favour that it loves; <br>\r\nHath is not, boy?<br>\r\nB : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe scene reveals","options":["Orsino's love for Olivia","Viola's love for Orsino","Olivia's love for Sebastian","Olivia's love for Cesario",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : How dost thou like this tune?<br>\r\nB : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>\r\n Where Love is throned<br>\r\nA : Thou dost speak masterly<br>\r\nMy life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>\r\nHath stayed upon some favour that it loves; <br>\r\nHath is not, boy?<br>\r\nB : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe dialogue shows that the characters are","options":["in love with each other","truly in love with music","in love with the same person","both victims of unreturned love",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>\r\nI pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>\r\nWith the memorials and the things of fame<br>\r\nThat do renown this city<br>\r\n(Act III Scene 3)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Malvolio","Viola","Antonio","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>\r\nI pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>\r\nWith the memorials and the things of fame<br>\r\nThat do renown this city<br>\r\n(Act III Scene 3)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is addressing","options":["Malvolio","Antonio","Valentine","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>\r\nI pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>\r\nWith the memorials and the things of fame<br>\r\nThat do renown this city<br>\r\n(Act III Scene 3)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person addressed responds to the speaker's request by","options":["declining it","accepting it","being undecided","being angry",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n                           ......;she<br>\r\nSends him purpose that I may appear stub<br>\r\nborn to him ; for she incites me to that in the letter.<br>\r\n''Cast thy humble slough,''<br>\r\nsays she; ''be opposite with a kinsman, surly<br>\r\nwith servant;.......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Malvolio","Sebastian","Orsino","Sir Toby",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n                           ......;she<br>\r\nSends him purpose that I may appear stub<br>\r\nborn to him ; for she incites me to that in the letter.<br>\r\n''Cast thy humble slough,''<br>\r\nsays she; ''be opposite with a kinsman, surly<br>\r\nwith servant;.......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe letter referred to is from","options":["Sir Andrew","Maria","Olivia","Cesario",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2000"},{"question":"A short speech at the end a play is the","options":["epilogue","denouement","peroration","conclusion",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"An elegy is a poem","options":["commemorating a birth","commemorating a national celebration","mourning the dead","mourning the passage of time",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A couplet is formed by","options":["five lines of poetry","two rhymed lines of poetry","two lines of poetry","five rhymed lines of poetry",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Literary works are classified into","options":["cantose","episodes","eras","genres",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A word that sounds like what it names is a (n)","options":["alliteration","assonance","onomatopoeia","rhyme",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The repetition of similar vowel sounds within lines is","options":["parallelism","allusion","assonance","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"One of the following is a literary device","options":["Sonnet","Ode","Suspense","Lyric",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The theme of a work of art is the","options":["concluding part","central thought","central role","introductory part",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The characters in a play constitute the","options":["performers","chorus","audience","cast",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A play that thrives on exaggeration of humour, plot and character is a","options":["mime","tragedy","farce","lampoon",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The hero in a story is the","options":["observer","protagonist","antagonist","actor",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A verbal irony occurs when a speaker on stage","options":["intends more than he says","is alone","tries to deceive the audience","is misunderstood",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"An 'Aside' occurs when a speaker on stage","options":["addresses another speaker","mumbles words intended for the audience only","mumbles words heard by the audience and actors","reveals his intentions",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"'The stars blinked and the wind wailed' is an example of","options":["euphemism","personification","parody","antithesis",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A stanza of four lines is a (n)","options":["octave","couplet","quatrain","tercet",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"A sonnet is made up of a rhyming sestet and two","options":["rhyming couplets","rhyming quatrains","rhyming lines","rhyming stanzas",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The climax in a literary work is the","options":["middle of the work","beginning of the story","central part of  the dialogue","most intense point of the conflict",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a type of drama?","options":["burleque","resolution","tragedy","pantomime",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The main effect of comedy on an audience is","options":["anxiety","sadness","laughter","suspense",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"The ending of most comedies is","options":["happy","natural","calm","uncertain",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite,<br>\r\nShall share with me this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\nOn, for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I can't you capture,<br>\r\nJust at the time I snore deep. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis is strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one of you is my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe subject of the poem is a","options":["mosquito","flea","bedbug","louse",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite,<br>\r\nShall share with me this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\nOn, for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I can't you capture,<br>\r\nJust at the time I snore deep. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis is strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one of you is my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nLines 1 and 2 of the second stanza illustrate the use of","options":["caesura","metre","enjambment","ellipsis",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite,<br>\r\nShall share with me this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\nOn, for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I can't you capture,<br>\r\nJust at the time I snore deep. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis is strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one of you is my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe creature in the poem is best described as","options":["clever","sluggish","awkward","tiny",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite,<br>\r\nShall share with me this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\nOn, for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I can't you capture,<br>\r\nJust at the time I snore deep. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis is strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one of you is my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person's mood is one of","options":["sarcasm","indifference","despair","joy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the poem and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nUNSEEN POETRY AND PROSE<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI wonder how long, you awful parasite,<br>\r\nShall share with me this little bed,<br>\r\nAnd make me, from sweet dreams be lost<br>\r\nBy sucking blood from my poor head.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI should but say man has much<br>\r\nBlood, which you and your families do feed<br>\r\nOn, for supper, dinner, and lunch,<br>\r\nAnd besides, you do in my bed breed.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nClever thou art, tiny creature;<br>\r\nYou attend me when I am deep asleep<br>\r\nWhen thou art sure, I can't you capture,<br>\r\nJust at the time I snore deep. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Tis is strange that before twilight,<br>\r\nThe bed clear of you would seem;<br>\r\nFor not one of you is my sight<br>\r\nAs if your presence was in a dream.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe device used in ''Tis so strange'' is","options":["assonance","alliteration","onomatopoeia","pun",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the prose passage and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNgotho was pleased. And Nyolabi and Njeri were full of joy at the news. For the first time many years something like a glimmer of light shone in Ngotho's eyes. He could even be seen making an effort to walk upright. Here at last was a son who might eventually be a match for the Howlands and Jacobos and any others who at all despised him. Kamanu too was pleased. He hoped he could go on helping  Njoroge. Njoroge might do something for the family.<br>\r\nNjoroge was happy. His first impulse when he learnt what he had gone through was to kneel down and thank God for all He had done for him. ' Give me more and more learning and make me the instrument of thy light and peace. 'To go to Secondary School, the big mission at Siriana, was no small achievement. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the people in the extract is that of","options":["sadness and  tiredness","depression andd anixiety","happiness and hope","anger and aggression",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the prose passage and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNgotho was pleased. And Nyolabi and Njeri were full of joy at the news. For the first time many years something like a glimmer of light shone in Ngotho's eyes. He could even be seen making an effort to walk upright. Here at last was a son who might eventually be a match for the Howlands and Jacobos and any others who at all despised him. Kamanu too was pleased. He hoped he could go on helping  Njoroge. Njoroge might do something for the family.<br>\r\nNjoroge was happy. His first impulse when he learnt what he had gone through was to kneel down and thank God for all He had done for him. ' Give me more and more learning and make me the instrument of thy light and peace. 'To go to Secondary School, the big mission at Siriana, was no small achievement. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe theme of the extract is the","options":["resistance to oppression","ambition to become a priest","quest for education","desire for happiness",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the prose passage and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNgotho was pleased. And Nyolabi and Njeri were full of joy at the news. For the first time many years something like a glimmer of light shone in Ngotho's eyes. He could even be seen making an effort to walk upright. Here at last was a son who might eventually be a match for the Howlands and Jacobos and any others who at all despised him. Kamanu too was pleased. He hoped he could go on helping  Njoroge. Njoroge might do something for the family.<br>\r\nNjoroge was happy. His first impulse when he learnt what he had gone through was to kneel down and thank God for all He had done for him. ' Give me more and more learning and make me the instrument of thy light and peace. 'To go to Secondary School, the big mission at Siriana, was no small achievement. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat does the expression ''Instrument of thy light and peace'' tell us about the speaker?","options":["His filial bond","His humility","His pride","His sympathy",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the prose passage and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nNgotho was pleased. And Nyolabi and Njeri were full of joy at the news. For the first time many years something like a glimmer of light shone in Ngotho's eyes. He could even be seen making an effort to walk upright. Here at last was a son who might eventually be a match for the Howlands and Jacobos and any others who at all despised him. Kamanu too was pleased. He hoped he could go on helping  Njoroge. Njoroge might do something for the family.<br>\r\nNjoroge was happy. His first impulse when he learnt what he had gone through was to kneel down and thank God for all He had done for him. ' Give me more and more learning and make me the instrument of thy light and peace. 'To go to Secondary School, the big mission at Siriana, was no small achievement. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe expression '' a glimmer of light'' stands for","options":["courage","disaster","tolerance","hope",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night <br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI  have said too much unto a heart of stone,<br>\r\nAnd laid my honour too unchary on 't;<br>\r\nThere's something in me that reproves my fault,<br>\r\nBut such a headstrong potent fault it is<br>\r\nThat it but mocks reproof.<br>\r\n(Acts iii, Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe figure of speech used in '' a heart of stone'' is","options":["hyperbole","metonymy","paradox","metaphor",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night <br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI  have said too much unto a heart of stone,<br>\r\nAnd laid my honour too unchary on 't;<br>\r\nThere's something in me that reproves my fault,<br>\r\nBut such a headstrong potent fault it is<br>\r\nThat it but mocks reproof.<br>\r\n(Acts iii, Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis person has","options":["refused to accept the ring","refused to see Orsino","decided not to go out with Antonio","tricked Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night <br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI  have said too much unto a heart of stone,<br>\r\nAnd laid my honour too unchary on 't;<br>\r\nThere's something in me that reproves my fault,<br>\r\nBut such a headstrong potent fault it is<br>\r\nThat it but mocks reproof.<br>\r\n(Acts iii, Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe ''Headstrong potent fault'' is","options":["falling in love","showing sympathy","proposing marriage","seeking revenge",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night <br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI  have said too much unto a heart of stone,<br>\r\nAnd laid my honour too unchary on 't;<br>\r\nThere's something in me that reproves my fault,<br>\r\nBut such a headstrong potent fault it is<br>\r\nThat it but mocks reproof.<br>\r\n(Acts iii, Scene 4)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe person being referred to in the figure of speech is","options":["Olivia","Malvolio","Viola","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI do I know not what, and fear to find<br>\r\nMine eye to great a flatterer for my mind<br>\r\nFate, show thy force; ourselves we do not owe,<br>\r\n'What is decreed must be, and be this so <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat has the speaker just done?","options":["sent a ring to Orsino","Written a letter to Malvolio","Met her brother who is presumed dead","sent a ring to Cesario",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI do I know not what, and fear to find<br>\r\nMine eye to great a flatterer for my mind<br>\r\nFate, show thy force; ourselves we do not owe,<br>\r\n'What is decreed must be, and be this so <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn lines 1 and 2, the speaker admits","options":["having very attractive eyes","acting unreasonably","falling in love","not taking advantage of an opportunity",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI do I know not what, and fear to find<br>\r\nMine eye to great a flatterer for my mind<br>\r\nFate, show thy force; ourselves we do not owe,<br>\r\n'What is decreed must be, and be this so <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nHow does fate treat the speaker at the end of the play?","options":["She marries Sebastian","He marries Maria","She marries Orsino","He falls in love with Olivia",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a heart,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWho is speaking?","options":["Orsino","Sebastian","Cesario","Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a hert,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe figure of speech used in the underlined expression is","options":["personification","paradox","metaphor","irony",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a hert,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe effect of the figure of speech is to highlight Olivia's","options":["glittering eyes","state of mind","determination and hope","beauty and purity",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a hert,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn lines 3 to 5 the dominant image is taken from","options":["a hart","hunting","cruel hounds","a desire",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a hert,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe image is itself based on","options":["pun","alliteration","allusion","wit",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n......O, when mine eyes did see Olivia first,<br>\r\nMe thought <u>she purged the air of pestilence;<\/u><br>\r\nThat instant was, I turned into a hart,<br>\r\nAnd my desires, like fell and cruel hounds,<br>\r\nE'er since pursue me.<br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 1)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe lines mean that the speaker","options":["is being pursued by cruel hounds","has been turn into a hart","is a victim of his desires","does not understand himself.",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...... Lady, you are <u>the cruell'st she alive<\/u><br>\r\nif you will lead these graces to the grave<br>\r\nAnd leave the world no copy. <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWho is speaking and to whom?","options":["Sir Toby to Maria","Viola to Olivia","Sebastian to Olivia","Orsino to Olivia",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...... Lady, you are <u>the cruell'st she alive<\/u><br>\r\nif you will lead these graces to the grave<br>\r\nAnd leave the world no copy. <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhere are they?","options":["On a street","At the Duke's palace","At the sea Coast","At Olivia's house",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...... Lady, you are <u>the cruell'st she alive<\/u><br>\r\nif you will lead these graces to the grave<br>\r\nAnd leave the world no copy. <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat has prompted the speech?","options":["The lady is about to kill herself","The speaker is unable to woo the lady","The lady will not marry Orsino","The lady is unforgiving",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...... Lady, you are <u>the cruell'st she alive<\/u><br>\r\nif you will lead these graces to the grave<br>\r\nAnd leave the world no copy. <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression is a","options":["hyperbole","satire","climax","bathos",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n...... Lady, you are <u>the cruell'st she alive<\/u><br>\r\nif you will lead these graces to the grave<br>\r\nAnd leave the world no copy. <br>\r\n(Act 1, Scene 5)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn the last line, the word 'copy' alludes to a","options":["painting","will","child","photograph",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1999"},{"question":"Which of the following is common to all forms of literature?","options":["language","chorus","action","narrator",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The three major forms of literature are","options":["tragedy,comedy, tragi-comedy","poetry,drama,folktales","drama,lyric,prose fiction","poetry, drama,prose",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Beauty in poetry depends mainly on","options":["expression and rhythm","length and theme","vowels and consonants","mood and verse form",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer this question.<br>\r\nBut the towering  earth was tired of sitting in one position. She moved, suddenly, and the houses crumbled, the mountains heaved horribly, and the work of a million years was lost.<br>\r\nThe predominant figure of speech in the above extracts is","options":["Oxymoron","Metaphor","Simile","Personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer this question.<br>\r\nBut the towering  earth was tired of sitting in one position. She moved, suddenly, and the houses crumbled, the mountains heaved horribly, and the work of a million years was lost.<br>\r\nThe subject matter of the above extract is","options":["earthquake","house movement","sea waves","storm",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBut the towering  earth was tired of sitting in one position. She moved, suddenly, and the houses crumbled, the mountains heaved horribly, and the work of a million years was lost.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe image depicted in the extract is one of","options":["destruction","merriment","happiness","amiration",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the list below","options":["Night Rain","Things fall Apart","Stanley Meets Mutesa","Nightfall in Soweto",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The birds fly high over<br>\r\nthe hills beyond the corn fields.<br>\r\nThe poetic device used in the above extract is","options":["assonance","alliteration","metaphor","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The birds fly high over<br>\r\nthe hills beyond the corn fields.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA poem written or rendered in praise of a person or thing is called","options":["a lyric","an ode","an elegy","a panegyric",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The basic elements of drama are","options":["character, plot, episode","dialogue, chorus, plot","character, action, setting","character, monoloue, plot",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The choice of appropriate words to convey the thoughts of an author is called","options":["idiomatic language","setting","figure of speech","diction",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The state of mind of a poet can be described as","options":["style","mood","setting","theme",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following is a likely source of traditional oral poetry?","options":["Theatre","fiction","books","songs",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"An African author who has written plays, poems and prose is","options":["Wole Soyinka","Zaynab Alkali","Chinua Achebe","Flora Nwapa",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In a novel, the antagonist is","options":["a fully developed character","a flat character","the main female character","the archrival of the hero",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe <u>pattering<\/u> rain was kicking up little <br>\r\nexplosions of dust in the glade.He heard the <br>\r\n<u>faint whisper of the stream as it stole across<\/u><br>\r\nthe land and disappeared into the bush.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe figure of speech underlined in line 1 is","options":["assonance","consonance","onomatopoeia","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer this question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe <u>pattering<\/u> rain was kicking up little <br>\r\nexplosions of dust in the glade.He heard the <br>\r\n<u>faint whisper of the stream as it stole across<\/u><br>\r\nthe land and disappeared into the bush.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underline expression in line regular pattern of","options":["vowels and consonants","long and short words","stressed and unstressed syllables","stressed syllables and rhymes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following is an African poet?","options":["Dennis Brutus","William Wordsworth","Rober Frost","W.B.Yeats",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In a play, a long speech by a single character in the presence of other characters is called","options":["soliloguy","monologue","aside","prologue",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A play that is full of exaggerated ridicule and laughter is called","options":["farce","comedy","tragi-comedy","masque",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the list below","options":["tragedy","comedy","epilogue","tragi-comedy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A group of actors in a play is called","options":["characters","cast","chorus","prompters",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A novel is usually written in","options":["prose","verse","scenes","stanzas",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"What distinguishes a novel from a play is","options":["characters","setting","narration","theme",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following best describes Literature? It","options":["tells the story of great men and women","is a reflection of man's life in society","is a record of past events","describes what never happened and cannot happen",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The literary device in the statement - 'Students are to come to class with their Shakespeare' is called","options":["metonymy","litotes","synecdoche","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The first person narrator is usually","options":["the protagonist","a villain in the novel","the antagonist","a character in the novel",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The first person narrator is usually","options":["the protagonist","a villain in the novel","the antagonist","a character in the novel",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Which of the following is closest to the novel?","options":["the short story","fable","tale","epic",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"''The people's voices rutted like pigs in the mud'' is an example of","options":["simile","metaphor","personification","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThat age is best which is the first<br>\r\nWhen youth and blood are warmer<br>\r\nBut being spent, the worse, and worst<br>\r\nTimes still succeed the former.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme is known as","options":["abba","abab","aabb","bbaa",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThat age is best which is the first<br>\r\nWhen youth and blood are warmer<br>\r\nBut being spent, the worse, and worst<br>\r\nTimes still succeed the former.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThis kind of rhyme scheme is known as","options":["alternate","irregular","free verse","couplet",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A poem of 14 lines is known as a","options":["quatrain","octave","sestet","sonnet",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"\u00bb Read the extract below and answer the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThat age is best which is the first<br>\r\nWhen youth and blood are warmer<br>\r\nBut being spent, the worse, and worst<br>\r\nTimes still succeed the former.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA poem of four lines is known as a","options":["sonnet","couplet","sestet","quatrain",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the list","options":["prose","poetry","drama","tragedy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A play on words is","options":["innuendo","humour","pun","jest",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A play is fully realized when it is","options":["studied","memorized","acted","read",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"An epitaph is","options":["poem of lamentation","a poem of fourteen lines","an inscription on a tomb","the life history of an author",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The essential function of a tragedy is to make people","options":["laught at mankind","think and feel more deeply","think and laugh","know their enemies",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Mime is the art of acting that involves the use of","options":["songs only","speeches only","gestures only","dances only",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A short witty statement is called an","options":["epigram","anecdote","epistle","analogy",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"'penny wise; pound foolish' is an example of","options":["metonymy","hyperbole","metaphor","paradox",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"All fingers are not equal' is an example of","options":["meiosis","oxymoron","huperbole","synecdoche",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Any expression which creates a mental picture is known as","options":["paradox","exaggeration","imagery","symbolism",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bees are <u>buzzing<\/u> and <u>humming<\/u> with great zest, the doves are cooing; and the children <u>chatter<\/u> as they <u>clatter<\/u> downstairs to come and dabble in the cool system.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe predominant sound device in the extract is","options":["assonance","consonance","onomatopoeia","alliteration",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe bees are <u>buzzing<\/u> and <u>humming<\/u> with great zest, the doves are cooing; and the children chatter as they <u>clatter<\/u> downstairs to come and dabble in the cool system.<br>\r\nThe underlined words in lines 1 and 4 are example of","options":["external rhyme","internal rhyme","end rhyme","alternate rhyme",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The omniscient narrator","options":["uses flashback","knows all about character and events","makes reference to future incidents","knows all about the author",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The main female character in a play is called","options":["hero","heroine","clown","antagonist",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The character that opposses the hero in a novel is called the","options":["protagonist","antagonist","villan","clown",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Pick the odd item from the list","options":["sentence","paragraph","expression","fiction",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJoseph turned around, Be careful you don't slip, he called. Her heel dug for a third step and then the moss stripped off a little. Her hands gripped the moss and tore it out. Joseph saw her head describe a little  arc and strike the ground. As he ran toward her, she turned slowly on her side. Her whole body shuddered violently for a second and then relaxed. He stood over her for an instant before he ran to the spring and filled his hands with water. But when he came back to her, he let the water fall to the ground, for he saw the position of her neck, and <u>the grey that was stealing into her cheeks.<\/u> 'It was too simple, to easy, too quick, he said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe setting of this extract is the","options":["field","stream","farm","mountain",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJoseph turned around, Be careful you don't slip, he called. Her heel dug for a third step and then the moss stripped off a little. Her hands gripped the moss and tore it out. Joseph saw her head describe a little  arc and strike the ground. As he ran toward her, she turned slowly on her side. Her whole body shuddered violently for a second and then relaxed. He stood over her for an instant before he ran to the spring and filled his hands with water. But when he came back to her, he let the water fall to the ground, for he saw the position of her neck, and <u>the grey that was stealing into her cheeks.<\/u> 'It was too simple, to easy, too quick, he said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the narrator is one of","options":["shock","indifference","happiness","kindness",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJoseph turned around, Be careful you don't slip, he called. Her heel dug for a third step and then the moss stripped off a little. Her hands gripped the moss and tore it out. Joseph saw her head describe a little  arc and strike the ground. As he ran toward her, she turned slowly on her side. Her whole body shuddered violently for a second and then relaxed. He stood over her for an instant before he ran to the spring and filled his hands with water. But when he came back to her, he let the water fall to the ground, for he saw the position of her neck, and <u>the grey that was stealing into her cheeks.<\/u> 'It was too simple, to easy, too quick, he said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe narrator's companion has just","options":["died","arrived","relaxed","collapsed",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJoseph turned around, Be careful you don't slip, he called. Her heel dug for a third step and then the moss stripped off a little. Her hands gripped the moss and tore it out. Joseph saw her head describe a little  arc and strike the ground. As he ran toward her, she turned slowly on her side. Her whole body shuddered violently for a second and then relaxed. He stood over her for an instant before he ran to the spring and filled his hands with water. But when he came back to her, he let the water fall to the ground, for he saw the position of her neck, and <u>the grey that was stealing into her cheeks.<\/u> 'It was too simple, to easy, too quick, he said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe extract is an example of","options":["narrative prose","descriptive prose","imaginative prose","expository prose",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>\r\n<br>\r\nJoseph turned around, Be careful you don't slip, he called. Her heel dug for a third step and then the moss stripped off a little. Her hands gripped the moss and tore it out. Joseph saw her head describe a little  arc and strike the ground. As he ran toward her, she turned slowly on her side. Her whole body shuddered violently for a second and then relaxed. He stood over her for an instant before he ran to the spring and filled his hands with water. But when he came back to her, he let the water fall to the ground, for he saw the position of her neck, and <u>the grey that was stealing into her cheeks.<\/u> 'It was too simple, to easy, too quick, he said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression is an example of","options":["hyperbole","metaphor","simile","personification",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In England, her love for Henry blossomed like spring flowers after a hard winter. But she abhored the way he dressed in England. They fell in love when she was working in a little coffee shop across from the Crystal Palace. Tall and jovial, he fell romantically in love with her at first sight. After a brief and hilarious courtship, they got married in a small Presbyterian Chapel in North London. Her people came and her mother shed a tear when it was announced that the newly-wed couple would go to Africa. From that day,her world collapsed. He had never even hinted that he had joined the colonial service. Nor did she know that her honeymoon would be a hurried affair in Brighton.She wept most of the time on board the M.V Apapa that took them to Africa. Eight years and her temper grew worse. She got farther and farther away from her husband. They never had a child.  A child would have made all the difference in the world. <br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe figure of speech used in the first sentence is","options":["personification","metaphor","simile","metonymy",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In England, her love for Henry blossomed like spring flowers after a hard winter. But she abhored the way he dressed in England. They fell in love when she was working in a little coffee shop across from the Crystal Palace. Tall and jovial, he fell romantically in love with her at first sight. After a brief and hilarious courtship, they got married in a small Presbyterian Chapel in North London. Her people came and her mother shed a tear when it was announced that the newly-wed couple would go to Africa. From that day,her world collapsed. He had never even hinted that he had joined the colonial service. Nor did she know that her honeymoon would be a hurried affair in Brighton.She wept most of the time on board the M.V Apapa that took them to Africa. Eight years and her temper grew worse. She got farther and farther away from her husband. They never had a child.  A child would have made all the difference in the world. <br>\r\n<br>\r\nIn England, she had loved her husband, in Africa, She","options":["resented him","accepted him","enjoyed her honeymoon","encouraged him",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In England, her love for Henry blossomed like spring flowers after a hard winter. But she abhored the way he dressed in England. They fell in love when she was working in a little coffee shop across from the Crystal Palace. Tall and jovial, he fell romantically in love with her at first sight. After a brief and hilarious courtship, they got married in a small Presbyterian Chapel in North London. Her people came and her mother shed a tear when it was announced that the newly-wed couple would go to Africa. From that day,her world collapsed. He had never even hinted that he had joined the colonial service. Nor did she know that her honeymoon would be a hurried affair in Brighton.She wept most of the time on board the M.V Apapa that took them to Africa. Eight years and her temper grew worse. She got farther and farther away from her husband. They never had a child.  A child would have made all the difference in the world. <br>\r\n<br>\r\n'From that day her world collapsed' shows that the woman is","options":["better off","wise","afraid","unhappy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In England, her love for Henry blossomed like spring flowers after a hard winter. But she abhored the way he dressed in England. They fell in love when she was working in a little coffee shop across from the Crystal Palace. Tall and jovial, he fell romantically in love with her at first sight. After a brief and hilarious courtship, they got married in a small Presbyterian Chapel in North London. Her people came and her mother shed a tear when it was announced that the newly-wed couple would go to Africa. From that day,her world collapsed. He had never even hinted that he had joined the colonial service. Nor did she know that her honeymoon would be a hurried affair in Brighton.She wept most of the time on board the M.V Apapa that took them to Africa. Eight years and her temper grew worse. She got farther and farther away from her husband. They never had a child.  A child would have made all the difference in the world. <br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhat made the woman's  world collapse is","options":["falling in love with her husband in winter","cutting short their honeymoon","travelling aboard a ship","their movement to Africa",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"In England, her love for Henry blossomed like spring flowers after a hard winter. But she abhored the way he dressed in England. They fell in love when she was working in a little coffee shop across from the Crystal Palace. Tall and jovial, he fell romantically in love with her at first sight. After a brief and hilarious courtship, they got married in a small Presbyterian Chapel in North London. Her people came and her mother shed a tear when it was announced that the newly-wed couple would go to Africa. From that day,her world collapsed. He had never even hinted that he had joined the colonial service. Nor did she know that her honeymoon would be a hurried affair in Brighton.She wept most of the time on board the M.V Apapa that took them to Africa. Eight years and her temper grew worse. She got farther and farther away from her husband. They never had a child.  A child would have made all the difference in the world. <br>\r\n<br>\r\nFrom the last sentence, it is obvious that the couple","options":["is happy","is lonely","is childless","has a child",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is an example of","options":["a lyric","a dirge","an ode","an epic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is an example of","options":["a lyric","a dirge","an ode","an epic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe predominant literary device used in the extract is","options":["hyperbole","epigram","oxymoron","apostrophe",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe feeling of the poet is one of","options":["anxiety","gaiety","sadness","frustration",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression contains a","options":["simile","metaphor","personification","litotes",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nI love you, my gentle one;<br>\r\nMy love is the fresh milk in the rubindi<br>\r\nWhich you drank on the wedding day;<br>\r\nMy love is the butter we were smeared with<br>\r\nTo seal fidelity into our hearts<br>\r\nYou are the cattle-bird's egg.<br>\r\nFor those who say you are wealthy;<br>\r\n<u>You are the papyrus read of the lake;<\/u><br>\r\n<u>Which they pull out with both hands.<\/u><br>\r\nAnd I sing for you with tears<br>\r\nBecause you possess my heart.<br>\r\nI love you my gentle one.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe poem is a blank verse because","options":["there is no rhyme","there is rhyme","the rhyme is alternate","it contains couplets",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nO stealing time, the subject of delay,<br>\r\nDelay the rack of unrefrained desire,<br>\r\nWhat strange design has thou my hopes to stay?<br>\r\nMy hopes which do but to mine own aspire?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOld age is wise, and full of constant truth,<br>\r\nOld age well stayed from ranging humours lives,<br>\r\nOld age hath known, whatever was in youth,<br>\r\nOld age overcome the greater honour gives.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe rhyme scheme of the above extract is","options":["alternate","irregular","free verse","couplet",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nO stealing time, the subject of delay,<br>\r\nDelay the rack of unrefrained desire,<br>\r\nWhat strange design has thou my hopes to stay?<br>\r\nMy hopes which do but to mine own aspire?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOld age is wise, and full of constant truth,<br>\r\nOld age well stayed from ranging humours lives,<br>\r\nOld age hath known, whatever was in youth,<br>\r\nOld age overcome the greater honour gives.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in line 1 is an example of","options":["climax","apostrophe","metonymy","euphemism",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nO stealing time, the subject of delay,<br>\r\nDelay the rack of unrefrained desire,<br>\r\nWhat strange design has thou my hopes to stay?<br>\r\nMy hopes which do but to mine own aspire?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOld age is wise, and full of constant truth,<br>\r\nOld age well stayed from ranging humours lives,<br>\r\nOld age hath known, whatever was in youth,<br>\r\nOld age overcome the greater honour gives.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe literary device used in lines 3 and 4 of stanza 1 is","options":["paradox","antithesis","apostrophe","rhetorical question",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nO stealing time, the subject of delay,<br>\r\nDelay the rack of unrefrained desire,<br>\r\nWhat strange design has thou my hopes to stay?<br>\r\nMy hopes which do but to mine own aspire?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOld age is wise, and full of constant truth,<br>\r\nOld age well stayed from ranging humours lives,<br>\r\nOld age hath known, whatever was in youth,<br>\r\nOld age overcome the greater honour gives.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe predominant figure of speech in stanza ll is","options":["consonance","alliteration","personification","epigram",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the following poem carefully and answer the questions that follow:<br>\r\nO stealing time, the subject of delay,<br>\r\nDelay the rack of unrefrained desire,<br>\r\nWhat strange design has thou my hopes to stay?<br>\r\nMy hopes which do but to mine own aspire?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nOld age is wise, and full of constant truth,<br>\r\nOld age well stayed from ranging humours lives,<br>\r\nOld age hath known, whatever was in youth,<br>\r\nOld age overcome the greater honour gives.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe mood of the poet is that of","options":["carelessness","happiness","gaiety","helplessness",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: <u>Twelfth Night<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What country, friends, is this?<br>\r\nB : This is lllyria, Lady,<br>\r\nA : And what should I do in lllyria?<br>\r\n    My brother he is in Elysium.<br>\r\n    Perchance he is not drowned - What think you,      sailors?<br>\r\nB : It is perchance that you yourself where saved<br>\r\nA : <u>O my poor brother.<\/u> and so perchance may he be<br>\r\n   (Act 1 Scene II)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Maria","Olivia","Valentine","Viola",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: <u>Twelfth Night<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What country, friends, is this?<br>\r\nB : This is lllyria, Lady,<br>\r\nA : And what should I do in lllyria?<br>\r\n    My brother he is in Elysium.<br>\r\n    Perchance he is not drowned - What think you,      sailors?<br>\r\nB : It is perchance that you yourself where saved<br>\r\nA : <u>O my poor brother.<\/u> and so perchance may he be<br>\r\n   (Act 1 Scene II)<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Sir Toby","Sir Andrew","Captain","Olivia",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: <u>Twelfth Night<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What country, friends, is this?<br>\r\nB : This is lllyria, Lady,<br>\r\nA : And what should I do in lllyria?<br>\r\n    My brother he is in Elysium.<br>\r\n    Perchance he is not drowned - What think you,      sailors?<br>\r\nB : It is perchance that you yourself where saved<br>\r\nA : <u>O my poor brother.<\/u> and so perchance may he be<br>\r\n   (Act 1 Scene II)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is worried about lllyria because the lady","options":["is new to lllyria","is not familiar with the language","does not understand the government","is afraid of the people",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: <u>Twelfth Night<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What country, friends, is this?<br>\r\nB : This is lllyria, Lady,<br>\r\nA : And what should I do in lllyria?<br>\r\n    My brother he is in Elysium.<br>\r\n    Perchance he is not drowned - What think you,      sailors?<br>\r\nB : It is perchance that you yourself where saved<br>\r\nA : <u>O my poor brother.<\/u> and so perchance may he be<br>\r\n   (Act 1 Scene II)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhy is speaker A afraid the brother might be drowned? It is because","options":["the crew was unfaithful","the ship captain threw him overboard","they fought with pirates","they were shipwrecked",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: <u>Twelfth Night<\/u><br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : What country, friends, is this?<br>\r\nB : This is lllyria, Lady,<br>\r\nA : And what should I do in lllyria?<br>\r\n    My brother he is in Elysium.<br>\r\n    Perchance he is not drowned - What think you,      sailors?<br>\r\nB : It is perchance that you yourself where saved<br>\r\nA : <u>O my poor brother.<\/u> and so perchance may he be<br>\r\n   (Act 1 Scene II)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe figure of speech underlined in the extract is known as","options":["apostrophe","alliteration","assonance","personification",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let all the rest give place<br>\r\n(Exeunt Curio and attendants),<br>\r\nOnce more, Cesario,<br>\r\nGet  thee to yond same sovereign cruelty;<br>\r\nTell her, my love, more noble than the world,<br>\r\nPrizes, not quantity of dirty land,<br>\r\nThe parts that forune hath bestowed upon her,<br>\r\nTell her, I hold as giddily as fortune,<br>\r\nBut 'tis that miracles and queen of gems<br>\r\nthat nature pranks her in, attracts my soul. <br>\r\n(Act ll Scene IV)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Sebastian","Fabian","Duke","Sir Andrew",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let all the rest give place<br>\r\n(Exeunt Curio and attendants),<br>\r\nOnce more, Cesario,<br>\r\nGet  thee to yond same sovereign cruelty;<br>\r\nTell her, my love, more noble than the world,<br>\r\nPrizes, not quantity of dirty land,<br>\r\nThe parts that forune hath bestowed upon her,<br>\r\nTell her, I hold as giddily as fortune,<br>\r\nBut 'tis that miracles and queen of gems<br>\r\nthat nature pranks her in, attracts my soul. <br>\r\n(Act ll Scene IV)<br>\r\nSpeaker A's object of love is","options":["Maria","Olivia","Viola","Feste",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let all the rest give place<br>\r\n(Exeunt Curio and attendants),<br>\r\nOnce more, Cesario,<br>\r\nGet  thee to yond same sovereign cruelty;<br>\r\nTell her, my love, more noble than the world,<br>\r\nPrizes, not quantity of dirty land,<br>\r\nThe parts that forune hath bestowed upon her,<br>\r\nTell her, I hold as giddily as fortune,<br>\r\nBut 'tis that miracles and queen of gems<br>\r\nthat nature pranks her in, attracts my soul. <br>\r\n(Act ll Scene IV)<br>\r\nThe hero of the play is","options":["Antonio","Sebastian","Fabian","Duke",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let all the rest give place<br>\r\n(Exeunt Curio and attendants),<br>\r\nOnce more, Cesario,<br>\r\nGet  thee to yond same sovereign cruelty;<br>\r\nTell her, my love, more noble than the world,<br>\r\nPrizes, not quantity of dirty land,<br>\r\nThe parts that forune hath bestowed upon her,<br>\r\nTell her, I hold as giddily as fortune,<br>\r\nBut 'tis that miracles and queen of gems<br>\r\nthat nature pranks her in, attracts my soul. <br>\r\n(Act ll Scene IV)<br>\r\nThe mood of Speaker A in the above scene is one of","options":["sadness","hope","joy","anxiety",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Let all the rest give place<br>\r\n(Exeunt Curio and attendants),<br>\r\nOnce more, Cesario,<br>\r\nGet  thee to yond same sovereign cruelty;<br>\r\nTell her, my love, more noble than the world,<br>\r\nPrizes, not quantity of dirty land,<br>\r\nThe parts that forune hath bestowed upon her,<br>\r\nTell her, I hold as giddily as fortune,<br>\r\nBut 'tis that miracles and queen of gems<br>\r\nthat nature pranks her in, attracts my soul. <br>\r\n(Act ll Scene IV)<br>\r\nThe play 'Twelfth Night' is a","options":["tragi-comedy","farce","tragedy","comedy",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Would you'd pardon me<br>\r\nI do not without danger walk these streets;<br>\r\nOnce, in a sea-fight against the Count his galleys,<br>\r\nI did some service-of such note, indeed.<br>\r\nThat were I ta'en here<br>\r\nIt would scarce be answered<br>\r\nB : Be like you slew great number of his people<br>\r\nA : The offence is not of such a bloody nature,<br>\r\nAlbeit the quality of the time and quarrel<br>\r\nMight well have given us bloody argument<br>\r\n(Act III Scene III)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Sir Andrew","Sir Toby","Antonio","Feste",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Would you'd pardon me<br>\r\nI do not without danger walk these streets;<br>\r\nOnce, in a sea-fight against the Count his galleys,<br>\r\nI did some service-of such note, indeed.<br>\r\nThat were I ta'en here<br>\r\nIt would scarce be answered<br>\r\nB : Be like you slew great number of his people<br>\r\nA : The offence is not of such a bloody nature,<br>\r\nAlbeit the quality of the time and quarrel<br>\r\nMight well have given us bloody argument<br>\r\n(Act III Scene III)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Olivia","Viola","Antonio","Sebastian",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Would you'd pardon me<br>\r\nI do not without danger walk these streets;<br>\r\nOnce, in a sea-fight against the Count his galleys,<br>\r\nI did some service-of such note, indeed.<br>\r\nThat were I ta'en here<br>\r\nIt would scarce be answered<br>\r\nB : Be like you slew great number of his people<br>\r\nA : The offence is not of such a bloody nature,<br>\r\nAlbeit the quality of the time and quarrel<br>\r\nMight well have given us bloody argument<br>\r\n(Act III Scene III)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe Count referred to in the extract is","options":["Orsino","Sir Andrew","Toby","Malvolio",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Would you'd pardon me<br>\r\nI do not without danger walk these streets;<br>\r\nOnce, in a sea-fight against the Count his galleys,<br>\r\nI did some service-of such note, indeed.<br>\r\nThat were I ta'en here<br>\r\nIt would scarce be answered<br>\r\nB : Be like you slew great number of his people<br>\r\nA : The offence is not of such a bloody nature,<br>\r\nAlbeit the quality of the time and quarrel<br>\r\nMight well have given us bloody argument<br>\r\n(Act III Scene III)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey mood of Speaker A, is that of","options":["gaiety","courage","melancholy","fear",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Would you'd pardon me<br>\r\nI do not without danger walk these streets;<br>\r\nOnce, in a sea-fight against the Count his galleys,<br>\r\nI did some service-of such note, indeed.<br>\r\nThat were I ta'en here<br>\r\nIt would scarce be answered<br>\r\nB : Be like you slew great number of his people<br>\r\nA : The offence is not of such a bloody nature,<br>\r\nAlbeit the quality of the time and quarrel<br>\r\nMight well have given us bloody argument<br>\r\n(Act III Scene III)<br>\r\n<br>\r\nBy the offence in the extract, Speaker A is a","options":["nuisance,","pirate","fighter","businessman",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLA ROTIMI: The Gods Are Not To Blame<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: No, no, do not thank me. I am only doing my duty<br>\r\nDo not thank me. Instead, let me only you one quuestion<br>\r\nNow you have all come here sprawing, vomiting, rubbling tears on one another, begging me to do my duty, and help you. But what about you yourselves?<br>\r\nWhat have you done to help yourselves?<br>\r\nAnswer. Or is the land at peace? Are not people ailing and dying ?<br>\r\nSpeaker A: We are suffering my Lord, we are........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["first chief","priest","Odewale","second chief",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLA ROTIMI: The Gods Are Not To Blame<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: No, no, do not thank me. I am only doing my duty<br>\r\nDo not thank me. Instead, let me only you one quuestion<br>\r\nNow you have all come here sprawing, vomiting, rubbling tears on one another, begging me to do my duty, and help you. But what about you yourselves?<br>\r\nWhat have you done to help yourselves?<br>\r\nAnswer. Or is the land at peace? Are not people ailing and dying ?<br>\r\nSpeaker A: We are suffering my Lord, we are........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is addressing","options":["second chief","towns people","third chief","Ojuola",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLA ROTIMI: The Gods Are Not To Blame<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: No, no, do not thank me. I am only doing my duty<br>\r\nDo not thank me. Instead, let me only you one quuestion<br>\r\nNow you have all come here sprawing, vomiting, rubbling tears on one another, begging me to do my duty, and help you. But what about you yourselves?<br>\r\nWhat have you done to help yourselves?<br>\r\nAnswer. Or is the land at peace? Are not people ailing and dying ?<br>\r\nSpeaker A: We are suffering my Lord, we are........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe land is not at peace because of","options":["sickness and death","famine and war","chieftaincy tussle","political unrest",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLA ROTIMI: The Gods Are Not To Blame<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: No, no, do not thank me. I am only doing my duty<br>\r\nDo not thank me. Instead, let me only you one quuestion<br>\r\nNow you have all come here sprawing, vomiting, rubbling tears on one another, begging me to do my duty, and help you. But what about you yourselves?<br>\r\nWhat have you done to help yourselves?<br>\r\nAnswer. Or is the land at peace? Are not people ailing and dying ?<br>\r\nSpeaker A: We are suffering my Lord, we are........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A's duty is to","options":["cure the people's illness","guard the palace","visit sick people","rule and protect the people",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLA ROTIMI: The Gods Are Not To Blame<br>\r\n<br>\r\nRead the extract below and answer questions:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: No, no, do not thank me. I am only doing my duty<br>\r\nDo not thank me. Instead, let me only you one quuestion<br>\r\nNow you have all come here sprawing, vomiting, rubbling tears on one another, begging me to do my duty, and help you. But what about you yourselves?<br>\r\nWhat have you done to help yourselves?<br>\r\nAnswer. Or is the land at peace? Are not people ailing and dying ?<br>\r\nSpeaker A: We are suffering my Lord, we are........<br>\r\n<br>\r\nWhere are speakers A and B when the above statements are made? They are at","options":["Speaker A's clinic","the house of Speaker","the farm","the palace",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My Lord, you make charges sometimes without grounds<br>\r\nB : I do, do I? Very well then, tell me this<br>\r\nBedsharer, You heard it. Didn't you?<br>\r\nThat blind bat who calls himself<br>\r\nSeer says I am a bedsharer'.......<br>\r\nWhat do you think of that? You don't answer?<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'My Lord' refers to","options":["third chief","Aderopo","Odewale","first Chief",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My Lord, you make charges sometimes without grounds<br>\r\nB : I do, do I? Very well then, tell me this<br>\r\nBedsharer, You heard it. Didn't you?<br>\r\nThat blind bat who calls himself<br>\r\nSeer says I am a bedsharer'.......<br>\r\nWhat do you think of that? You don't answer?<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'The charges' are made on the basis of","options":["treason","murder","jealousy","suspicion",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My Lord, you make charges sometimes without grounds<br>\r\nB : I do, do I? Very well then, tell me this<br>\r\nBedsharer, You heard it. Didn't you?<br>\r\nThat blind bat who calls himself<br>\r\nSeer says I am a bedsharer'.......<br>\r\nWhat do you think of that? You don't answer?<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Bedsharer' implies","options":["adultery","matrimony","divorce","separation",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My Lord, you make charges sometimes without grounds<br>\r\nB : I do, do I? Very well then, tell me this<br>\r\nBedsharer, You heard it. Didn't you?<br>\r\nThat blind bat who calls himself<br>\r\nSeer says I am a bedsharer'.......<br>\r\nWhat do you think of that? You don't answer?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe 'blind bat' is","options":["first chief","Odewale","third chief","baba Fakunle",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : My Lord, you make charges sometimes without grounds<br>\r\nB : I do, do I? Very well then, tell me this<br>\r\nBedsharer, You heard it. Didn't you?<br>\r\nThat blind bat who calls himself<br>\r\nSeer says I am a bedsharer'.......<br>\r\nWhat do you think of that? You don't answer?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["first chief","Odewale","third chief","Ojuola",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\nSpeaker A : Pray son, tell us the word from Ifa<br>\r\n            No matter how bad it is, we are ready to hear it. The horns cannot be too heavy for the head of the cow that must bear them. To remain silent is to make light of the the troubles in the land.<br>\r\nSpeaker B: I am not  making light of them, mother. It is that the word is heard that must be said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Odewale","Iya aburo","Ojuola","third chief",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\nSpeaker A : Pray son, tell us the word from Ifa<br>\r\n            No matter how bad it is, we are ready to hear it. The horns cannot be too heavy for the head of the cow that must bear them. To remain silent is to make light of the the troubles in the land.<br>\r\nSpeaker B: I am not  making light of them, mother. It is that the word is heard that must be said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe trouble in the land is","options":["an epidemic","famine","war","land dispute",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\nSpeaker A : Pray son, tell us the word from Ifa<br>\r\n            No matter how bad it is, we are ready to hear it. The horns cannot be too heavy for the head of the cow that must bear them. To remain silent is to make light of the the troubles in the land.<br>\r\nSpeaker B: I am not  making light of them, mother. It is that the word is heard that must be said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Aderopo","Odewale","Priest","Baba Fakunle",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\nSpeaker A : Pray son, tell us the word from Ifa<br>\r\n            No matter how bad it is, we are ready to hear it. The horns cannot be too heavy for the head of the cow that must bear them. To remain silent is to make light of the the troubles in the land.<br>\r\nSpeaker B: I am not  making light of them, mother. It is that the word is heard that must be said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nIfa oracle is consulted at","options":["Ede","Osogbo","Ife","Kutuje",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\nSpeaker A : Pray son, tell us the word from Ifa<br>\r\n            No matter how bad it is, we are ready to hear it. The horns cannot be too heavy for the head of the cow that must bear them. To remain silent is to make light of the the troubles in the land.<br>\r\nSpeaker B: I am not  making light of them, mother. It is that the word is heard that must be said.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe cause of the trouble is","options":["rivalry","incest","jealousy","war",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLIVER GOLDSMITH: She Stoops To Conquer<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Ay, and bring back vanity and affection to last them the whole year.<br>\r\nI wonder why London cannot keep its own fools at home!. In my time, the follies of the town crept slowly among us, but now they travel faster than a stage coach. Its fopperies come down, not only as inside passengers, but in the very basket.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Ay, your times were fine times indeed, you have telling us of them for many a long year. Here we live in an old rumbling mansion, that looks for all the world like an inn, but that we never see company....'<br>\r\n<br>\r\n' Them' in line 1 refers to","options":["Mr. and Mrs Hardcastle","Tony Lumpkin and Diggory","The neighbours","The two Miss Hoggs and Mrs. Grigsby",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLIVER GOLDSMITH: She Stoops To Conquer<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Ay, and bring back vanity and affection to last them the whole year.<br>\r\nI wonder why London cannot keep its own fools at home!. In my time, the follies of the town crept slowly among us, but now they travel faster than a stage coach. Its fopperies come down, not only as inside passengers, but in the very basket.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Ay, your times were fine times indeed, you have telling us of them for many a long year. Here we live in an old rumbling mansion, that looks for all the world like an inn, but that we never see company....'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B wishes to take a trip to","options":["the countryside","France","London","a village",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"OLIVER GOLDSMITH: She Stoops To Conquer<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Ay, and bring back vanity and affection to last them the whole year.<br>\r\nI wonder why London cannot keep its own fools at home!. In my time, the follies of the town crept slowly among us, but now they travel faster than a stage coach. Its fopperies come down, not only as inside passengers, but in the very basket.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Ay, your times were fine times indeed, you have telling us of them for many a long year. Here we live in an old rumbling mansion, that looks for all the world like an inn, but that we never see company....'<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A and B are in","options":["a chamber","the town","London","a stage coach",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Then to be plain with you .......<br>\r\nI expect the young gentleman I have chosen to be your husband from town this very day.<br>\r\nI have his father's letter, in which he informs me his son is set out and that he intends to follow himself shortly after.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Indeed! I wish I had known something of this before. Bless me, how shall I behave?<br>\r\nIt's a thousand to one<br>\r\nI shan't like him, <u>Our meeting will be so formal, and so like a thing of business<\/u> that I shall find no room for friendship or esteem.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe name of the youngman coming form town is","options":["Sir Charles Marlow","Tony Lumpkin","Diggory","Young Marlow",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Then to be plain with you .......<br>\r\nI expect the young gentleman I have chosen to be your husband from town this very day.<br>\r\nI have his father's letter, in which he informs me his son is set out and that he intends to follow himself shortly after.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Indeed! I wish I had known something of this before. Bless me, how shall I behave?<br>\r\nIt's a thousand to one<br>\r\nI shan't like him, <u>Our meeting will be so formal, and so like a thing of business<\/u> that I shall find no room for friendship or esteem.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is the father of","options":["Kate Hardcastle","Tony Lumpkin","Hastings","Diggory",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Then to be plain with you .......<br>\r\nI expect the young gentleman I have chosen to be your husband from town this very day.<br>\r\nI have his father's letter, in which he informs me his son is set out and that he intends to follow himself shortly after.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Indeed! I wish I had known something of this before. Bless me, how shall I behave?<br>\r\nIt's a thousand to one<br>\r\nI shan't like him, <u>Our meeting will be so formal, and so like a thing of business<\/u> that I shall find no room for friendship or esteem.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe news of the suitor's visit makes Speaker B","options":["happy","sad","anxious","pessimistic",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the extract below carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Then to be plain with you .......<br>\r\nI expect the young gentleman I have chosen to be your husband from town this very day.<br>\r\nI have his father's letter, in which he informs me his son is set out and that he intends to follow himself shortly after.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : Indeed! I wish I had known something of this before. Bless me, how shall I behave?<br>\r\nIt's a thousand to one<br>\r\nI shan't like him, <u>Our meeting will be so formal, and so like a thing of business<\/u> that I shall find no room for friendship or esteem.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe underlined expression reveals that speaker B","options":["likes contracted marriages","disapproves of contracted marriages","is indifferent to the marriage contract","suspects the meeting may not hold",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of <br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe gentlemen are","options":["Mr Hardcastle and Sir Marlow","Tony Lumpkin and Landlord","Hastings and Diggory","Young Marlow and Hastings",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey are both welcome to the house of Mr. and Mrs","options":["Hardcastle","Diggory","Hastings","Marlo",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThey are both welcome to the house of Mr. and Mrs","options":["Hardcastle","Diggory","Hastings","Marlo",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is happy to receive his","options":["friends","sons -in-law","brothers","daughter's suitor",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B believes Speaker A is","options":["a steward","the landlord","an inn keeper","a porter",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"A : Gentlemen, once more you are heartily welcome...Sir, you're heartily welcome.<br>\r\nIt's not my way, you see, to receive my friends with my back to the fire. I like to give them a hearty reception in the old style at my gate. I like to see their horse and trunks taken care of<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (Aside): He has got our names from the servants already. (To him): We approve your caution and hospitality, Sir.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Tony Lumpkin","Mr. Hardcastle","Sir Charles Marlow","Young Marlow",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"The heroine of the play, She Stoops to Conquer is","options":["Miss Hardcastle","Miss Neville","Mrs Hardcastle","Mrs Grigsby",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Mrs. Hardcastle is best described as","options":["dumb","petty","modest","vain",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Mrs. Hardcastle dotes very much on","options":["Kate","Tony","Neville","Marlow",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"EFUAT. SUTHERLAND: The Marriage of Anansewa<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: Haven't you stayed at home for nearly<br>\r\ntwo weeks because your fees are owing?<br>\r\nAnd am I not still straining to find the money?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B: Yes<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Aya","Christie","Ananse","Ekuwa",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"EFUAT. SUTHERLAND: The Marriage of Anansewa<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: Haven't you stayed at home for nearly<br>\r\ntwo weeks because your fees are owing?<br>\r\nAnd am I not still straining to find the money?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B: Yes<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Ekuwa","Anansewa","Ananse","Akosua",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the this passage carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: Delicious news cut a little whisky with me, <br>\r\nMr Honourable Hey, bring the <br>\r\ndrinks!......Sweet news Mr. Honourable (They drink)<br>\r\nDid he specify the day?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B: Oh yes. Two weeks today,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe 'delicious news' is delivered by","options":["the postman","Chief who is chief","the honourable","the messenger",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the this passage carefully and answer the question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A: Delicious news cut a little whisky with me, <br>\r\nMr Honourable Hey, bring the <br>\r\ndrinks!......Sweet news Mr. Honourable (They drink)<br>\r\nDid he specify the day?<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B: Oh yes. Two weeks today,<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Anansewa","Chief who is chief","the messenger","Ananse",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the this passage carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI have returned safely home after my visit to you<br>\r\nThey little affair about which we spoke seriously<br>\r\nOccupies my thoughts. How can I ever forget that<br>\r\nyou have done me great honour? To show my<br>\r\ngratitude. I will guard the object of your interest....<br>\r\nwith all the vigilance in my power......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Chief Sapa","Anansewa","Ananse","Chief who is chief",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the this passage carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI have returned safely home after my visit to you<br>\r\nThey little affair about which we spoke seriously<br>\r\nOccupies my thoughts. How can I ever forget that<br>\r\nyou have done me great honour? To show my<br>\r\ngratitude. I will guard the object of your interest....<br>\r\nwith all the vigilance in my power......<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe 'little affair' is about","options":["Ananse","Togbe Klu IV","Chief Sapa","Anansewa",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the this passage carefully and answer the question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\nI have returned safely home after my visit to you<br>\r\nThey little affair about which we spoke seriously<br>\r\nOccupies my thoughts. How can I ever forget that<br>\r\nyou have done me great honour? To show my<br>\r\ngratitude. I will guard the object of your interest....<br>\r\nwith all the vigilance in my power......<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'The object' of interest is","options":["Anansewa","Ananse","chieftaincy","marriage",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Did I say I would stop attending anywhere?<br>\r\nDid I? But bluntly speaking as for some old<br>\r\nchief with fifty wives, that won't do at all <br>\r\nNever.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (With cunning) Supposing it isn't some old<br>\r\nchief as you ignorantly describe, but the finely<br>\r\nbuilt, glowing black large - eyed, handsome as anything, courages and famous .....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is","options":["Christie","Aya","Ananse","Anansewa",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Did I say I would stop attending anywhere?<br>\r\nDid I? But bluntly speaking as for some old<br>\r\nchief with fifty wives, that won't do at all <br>\r\nNever.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (With cunning) Supposing it isn't some old<br>\r\nchief as you ignorantly describe, but the finely<br>\r\nbuilt, glowing black large - eyed, handsome as anything, courages and famous .....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker B is","options":["Ananse","messenger","christie","Anansewa",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer this question<br>\r\n<br>\r\nA : Did I say I would stop attending anywhere?<br>\r\nDid I? But bluntly speaking as for some old<br>\r\nchief with fifty wives, that won't do at all <br>\r\nNever.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nB : (With cunning) Supposing it isn't some old<br>\r\nchief as you ignorantly describe, but the finely<br>\r\nbuilt, glowing black large - eyed, handsome as anything, courages and famous .....<br>\r\n<br>\r\nSpeaker A is Speaker B's","options":["niece","sister","daughter","father",""],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Ah, here's a lovely thing. Oh, let me give service to my child.<br>\r\nMan, give me my child's brass bowl.....it's for you I'm spending my energy.<br>\r\nSir, give me the nyanya, please.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe speaker is","options":["Ekuwa","Christie","Aya","Ananse",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Ah, here's a lovely thing. Oh, let me give service to my child.<br>\r\nMan, give me my child's brass bowl.....it's for you I'm spending my energy.<br>\r\nSir, give me the nyanya, please.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe brass bowl is meant","options":["to collect gifts","for food","as a gift","for rituals",""],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Ah, here's a lovely thing. Oh, let me give service to my child.<br>\r\nMan, give me my child's brass bowl.....it's for you I'm spending my energy.<br>\r\nSir, give me the nyanya, please.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe above speech is made at the","options":["naming ceremony","christening ceremony","outdooring ceremony","chieeftaincy ceremony",""],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"1998"},{"question":"Read the passage carefully and answer question:<br>\r\n<br>\r\n'Ah, here's a lovely thing. Oh, let me give service to my child.<br>\r\nMan, give me my child's brass bowl.....it's for you I'm spending my energy.<br>\r\nSir, give me the nyanya, please.<br>\r\n<br>\r\nThe suitor who finally marries Anansewa is","options":["Chief Sapa","Chief who is chief","Chief of the mines","Togbe Klu IV",""],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"1998"}]